<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Voting on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Voting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Voting on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Voting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technologizing Democracy or Democratizing Technology? A Layered-Architecture Perspective on Potentials and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Draft &amp;ndash; June 4, 2020
Final version to appear in forthcoming book Digital Technology and Democratic Theory by Lucy Bernholz, Hélène Landemore, and Rob Reich (editors) published by the University of Chicago Press
 Abstract While technology is often claimed to be “democratizing”, the technologizing of society has more often yielded undemocratic or even anti-democratic outcomes. Is technology fundamentally at odds with democracy, or is it merely a rich and infinitely-adaptable toolbox that we’re using the wrong way?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Remote Voting Minefield: from North Carolina to Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/02/22/voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/02/22/voting/</guid>
      <description>The absentee ballot fraud in North Carolina shows how current vote-by-mail methods are fundamentally flawed and vulnerable to vote-buying and coercion. But banning remote voting of any kind would disenfranchise everyone not living in their country of citizenship; that is not a real option.
It is important to understand in this light the context of the Swiss e-voting project, one of whose two implementations was recently opened to public inspection by the Swiss Post for inspection and analysis by international experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Liquid Perspective on Democratic Choice</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/liquid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/liquid/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford  November 2018 (first draft)  arXiv preprint
 Abstract: The idea of liquid democracy responds to a widely-felt desire to make democracy more &#34;fluid&#34; and continuously participatory. Its central premise is to enable users to employ networked technologies to control and delegate voting power, to approximate the ideal of direct democracy in a scalable fashion that accounts for time and attention limits. There are many potential definitions, meanings, and ways to implement liquid democracy, however, and many distinct purposes to which it might be deployed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegative Democracy Revisited</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2014/11/16/deleg.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2014/11/16/deleg.html</guid>
      <description>Over a decade ago I wrote up some ideas I called &amp;ldquo;Delegative Democracy,&amp;rdquo; which has also become known as &amp;ldquo;Liquid Democracy.&amp;rdquo; My draft paper from 2002 took a first stab at laying out the general idea, though I never finished or tried to publish it. Since a lot has happened in this space since then, and I get regular inquiries about it, I thought it was high time to revisit the idea and review more recent developments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual Representation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2004/11/23/indrep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2004/11/23/indrep/</guid>
      <description>Real Choice for Voters, Democratic Currency for Activists Introduction The traditional purpose of popular elections is primarily to elect candidates to government offices or legislative seats, but this is not the only way we could use elections to facilitate democracy. Individual Representation, or indrep, provides a new and different reason to hold popular elections: as a tool for directly promoting the growth of grassroots social and political relationships throughout the basic fabric of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiki Democracy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2004/08/16/wiki-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2004/08/16/wiki-democracy/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegative Voting</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2002/10/21/deleg-voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2002/10/21/deleg-voting/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegative Democracy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2002/05/15/deleg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2002/05/15/deleg/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
