<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Voting on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Voting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Voting on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Voting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coercion-Resistant E-voting and Proof of Personhood</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2025-01-06-coercion-resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2025-01-06-coercion-resistance/</guid>
      <description> Keynote at IC3 Winter Retreat 2025 January 6, 2025 – Engelberg, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Real Democratic DAOs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2024-11-28-democratic-dao/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2024-11-28-democratic-dao/</guid>
      <description> Invited talk at DAO Symposium 2024 November 28, 2024 – Zürich, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-Vote Your Conscience: Perceptions of Coercion and Vote Buying, and the Usability of Fake Credentials in Online Voting</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/trip-usability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/trip-usability/</guid>
      <description>Louis-Henri Merino, Alaleh Azhir, Haoqian Zhang, Simone Colombo, Bernhard Tellenbach, Vero Estrada-Galiñanes, Bryan Ford To appear in 45th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy May 20-23, 2024 Abstract: Online voting is attractive for convenience and accessibility, but is more susceptible to voter coercion and vote buying than in-person voting. One mitigation is to give voters fake voting credentials that they can yield to a coercer. Fake credentials appear identical to real ones, but cast votes that are silently omitted from the final tally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can decentralized systems be truly “democratizing” – and how?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2024-04-05-democratizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2024-04-05-democratizing/</guid>
      <description> Keynote at ChainScience 2024 April 5, 2024 – Zürich, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Distributed Infrastructure Could Save the Planet?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2023-12-12-dicg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2023-12-12-dicg/</guid>
      <description> Keynote at 4th International Workshop on Distributed Infrastructure for Common Good (DICG) December 12, 2023 – Bologna, Italy Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who – Or What – Will Our Distributed Metaverse Serve?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2022-07-06-metaverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2022-07-06-metaverse/</guid>
      <description> Invited talk at INRIA prospective seminar on Distributed Systems and Middleware July 6, 2022 – Rungis, France Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Personhood: Towards Technology that Securely Serves People</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2022-02-17-personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2022-02-17-personhood/</guid>
      <description> Invited talk at SI Summit 2022 February 17, 2022 – Virtual Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIP: Trustless Coercion-Resistant In-Person Voter Registration</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/trip/</guid>
      <description>Louis-Henri Merino, Simone Colombo, Jeff Allen, Vero Estrada-Galiñanes, and Bryan Ford arXiv preprint Abstract: Most existing remote electronic voting systems are vulnerable to voter coercion and vote buying. While coercion-resistant voting systems address this challenge, current schemes assume that the voter has access to an untappable, incorruptible device during voter registration. We present TRIP, an in-person voter registration scheme enabling voters to create verifiable and indistinguishable real and fake credentials using an untrusted kiosk inside a privacy booth at a supervised location, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Personhood: Towards Technology that Securely Serves People</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2021-10-13-personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2021-10-13-personhood/</guid>
      <description> Distinguished Lecture at Vienna CyberSecurity and Privacy Research Cluster October 13, 2021 – Virtual Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Votegral: Coercion-Resistant E-voting Without Trusted Hardware</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2021-07-28-votegral/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2021-07-28-votegral/</guid>
      <description> Talk at IC3 Blockchain Summer Camp July 28, 2021 – Virtual Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof of Personhood: Introduction and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2021-07-27-personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2021-07-27-personhood/</guid>
      <description> Keynote at Internet of Humans Workshop #1 July 27, 2021 – Virtual Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technologizing Democracy or Democratizing Technology? A Layered-Architecture Perspective on Potentials and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Appears in Digital Technology and Democratic Theory by Lucy Bernholz, Hélène Landemore, and Rob Reich (editors) published by the University of Chicago Press
Abstract While technology is often claimed to be “democratizing”, the technologizing of society has more often yielded undemocratic or even anti-democratic outcomes. Is technology fundamentally at odds with democracy, or is it merely a rich and infinitely-adaptable toolbox that we’re using the wrong way? We explore how technology has failed to support robust democracy – but could do better – in the context of four basic social processes: collective deliberation and choice, information distribution and filtering, economic commerce, and identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personhood Online: Privacy, Transparency, and Inclusion for Digital Democracy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2020-11-05-personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2020-11-05-personhood/</guid>
      <description> Talk at Digital Democracy Workshop November 5, 2020 – Virtual Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identity and Personhood in Digital Democracy: Evaluating Inclusion, Equality, Security, and Privacy in Pseudonym Parties and Other Proofs of Personhood</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/personhood/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford November 2020 (first draft) arXiv preprint
Abstract: Digital identity seems at first like a prerequisite for digital democracy: how can we ensure &amp;ldquo;one person, one vote&amp;rdquo; online without identifying voters? But the full gamut of digital identity solutions &amp;ndash; e.g., online ID checking, biometrics, self-sovereign identity, and social/trust networks &amp;ndash; all present severe flaws in security, privacy, and transparency, leaving users vulnerable to exclusion, identity loss or theft, and coercion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain: Between Hype and Reality</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2020-01-29-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2020-01-29-blockchain/</guid>
      <description> Guest lecture at TransformTech January 29, 2020 – Lausanne, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain, Privacy, and Accountability</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2020-01-23-fintech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2020-01-23-fintech/</guid>
      <description> Talk at Caspian Week, World Economic Forum 2020 January 23, 2020 – Davos, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Architecture for Trust in the 21st Century</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2020-01-22-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2020-01-22-trust/</guid>
      <description> Talk at House of Switzerland, World Economic Forum 2020 January 22, 2020 – Davos, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voting and Blockchain: Promise and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2020-01-20-voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2020-01-20-voting/</guid>
      <description> Talk at Geneva Blockchain Congress 2020 January 20, 2020 – Geneva, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Remote Voting Minefield: from North Carolina to Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/02/22/voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/02/22/voting/</guid>
      <description>The absentee ballot fraud in North Carolina shows how current vote-by-mail methods are fundamentally flawed and vulnerable to vote-buying and coercion. But banning remote voting of any kind would disenfranchise everyone not living in their country of citizenship; that is not a real option.
It is important to understand in this light the context of the Swiss e-voting project, one of whose two implementations was recently opened to public inspection by the Swiss Post for inspection and analysis by international experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Liquid Perspective on Democratic Choice</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/liquid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/liquid/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford November 2018 (first draft) arXiv preprint
Abstract: The idea of liquid democracy responds to a widely-felt desire to make democracy more &#34;fluid&#34; and continuously participatory. Its central premise is to enable users to employ networked technologies to control and delegate voting power, to approximate the ideal of direct democracy in a scalable fashion that accounts for time and attention limits. There are many potential definitions, meanings, and ways to implement liquid democracy, however, and many distinct purposes to which it might be deployed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegative Democracy Revisited</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2014/11/16/deleg.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2014/11/16/deleg.html</guid>
      <description>Over a decade ago I wrote up some ideas I called &amp;ldquo;Delegative Democracy,&amp;rdquo; which has also become known as &amp;ldquo;Liquid Democracy.&amp;rdquo; My draft paper from 2002 took a first stab at laying out the general idea, though I never finished or tried to publish it. Since a lot has happened in this space since then, and I get regular inquiries about it, I thought it was high time to revisit the idea and review more recent developments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual Representation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2004/11/23/indrep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2004/11/23/indrep/</guid>
      <description>Real Choice for Voters, Democratic Currency for Activists Introduction The traditional purpose of popular elections is primarily to elect candidates to government offices or legislative seats, but this is not the only way we could use elections to facilitate democracy. Individual Representation, or indrep, provides a new and different reason to hold popular elections: as a tool for directly promoting the growth of grassroots social and political relationships throughout the basic fabric of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiki Democracy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2004/08/16/wiki-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2004/08/16/wiki-democracy/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegative Voting</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2002/10/21/deleg-voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2002/10/21/deleg-voting/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegative Democracy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2002/05/15/deleg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2002/05/15/deleg/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
