<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Side-Channels on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Side-Channels/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Side-Channels on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Side-Channels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrity and Metadata Protection in Data Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2021-nikitin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2021-nikitin/</guid>
      <description>Kirill Nikitin Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
November 26, 2021 Abstract: Secure retrieval of data requires integrity, confidentially, transparency, and metadata-privacy of the process. Existing protection mechanisms, however, provide only partially these properties: encryption schemes still expose cleartext metadata, protocols for private information retrieval neglect data integrity, and data-distribution architectures forego transparency. In this dissertation, by designing new cryptographic primitives and security architectures that provide a more comprehensive protection, we improve on the current security and privacy practices in data retrieval.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing and Protecting Communication Metadata</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2021-barman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2021-barman/</guid>
      <description>Ludovic Barman Ph.D. thesis advised by Jean-Pierre Hubaux and Bryan Ford
September 17, 2021 Abstract: Most communication systems (e.g., e-mails, instant messengers, VPNs) use encryption to prevent third parties from learning sensitive information. However, encrypted communications protect the contents but often leak metadata: the amount of data sent and the time it was sent, the way the data should be decrypted, the identity of the sender and the recipient. These metadata are a pervasive threat to privacy: They enable a variety of attacks that range from recovering plaintext contents from encrypted communications to inferring communicating parties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deterministically Deterring Timing Attacks in Deterland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-timing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-timing/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warding off Timing Channels in Deterland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-wu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-wu/</guid>
      <description> Weiyi Wu Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
August 10, 2015 Abstract: XXX Ph.D. Thesis: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugging Side-Channel Leaks with Timing Information Flow Control</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/tifc-hotcloud12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/tifc-hotcloud12/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determinating Timing Channels in Compute Clouds</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/timing-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/timing-abs/</guid>
      <description>Amittai Aviram, Sen Hu, Bryan Ford
Ramakrishna Gummadi
Yale University University of Massachusetts Amherst The ACM Cloud Computing Security Workshop (CCSW 2010) October 8, 2010, Chicago, IL, USA Abstract: Timing side-channels represent an insidious security challenge for cloud computing, because: (a) massive parallelism in the cloud makes timing channels pervasive and hard to control; (b) timing channels enable one customer to steal information from another without leaving a trail or raising alarms; (c) only the cloud provider can feasibly detect and report such attacks, but the provider&#39;s incentives are not to; and (d) resource partitioning schemes for timing channel control undermine statistical sharing efficiency, and, with it, the cloud computing business model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
