<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bford.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction: Promise, Failures, and Future of Self-Organizing Technologies</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/selforg/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/selforg/intro/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Layered Architecture Perspective on Self-Organizing Technologies</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/selforg/arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/selforg/arch/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identity, Personhood, and Citizenship in the Digital Age</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/selforg/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/selforg/people/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Empowerment and Inclusion: Money and Wealth in Digital Democracy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/selforg/money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/selforg/money/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speech and Association: Privacy, Accountability, and Freedoms in Digital Communications</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/selforg/comm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/selforg/comm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filtering, Curating, and Rewarding Value and Expertise in the Digital Information Deluge</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/selforg/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/selforg/info/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Liquid Perspective on Social Choice for Digital Democracy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/selforg/choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/selforg/choice/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design choices for Central Bank Digital Currency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cbdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cbdc/</guid>
      <description>Sarah Allen, Srdjan Capkun, Ittay Eyal, Giulia Fanti, Bryan Ford, James Grimmelmann, Ari Juels, Kari Kostiainen, Sarah Meiklejohn, Andrew Miller, Eswar Prasad, Karl Wüst, and Fan Zhang   Global Economy &amp; Development Working Paper 140,
Brookings Institution,
July 23, 2020. Abstract:  Central banks around the world are exploring and in some cases even piloting central bank digital currencies (CBDCs). CBDCs promise to realize a broad range of new capabilities, including direct government disbursements to citizens, frictionless consumer payment and money-transfer systems, and a range of new financial instruments and monetary policy levers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PriFi: Low-Latency Anonymity for Organizational Networks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/prifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/prifi/</guid>
      <description>Ludovic Barman, Italo Dacosta, Mahdi Zamani, Ennan Zhai, Apostolos Pyrgelis, Bryan Ford, Jean-Pierre Hubaux, and Joan Feigenbaum   Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium
July 13, 2020  Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
Volume 2020, Issue 4.  Abstract: Organizational networks are vulnerable to traffic-analysis attacks that enable adversaries to infer sensitive information from the network traffic &amp;ndash; even if encryption is used. Typical anonymous communication networks are tailored to the Internet and are poorly suited for organizational networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technologizing Democracy or Democratizing Technology? A Layered-Architecture Perspective on Potentials and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Draft &amp;ndash; June 4, 2020
Final version to appear in forthcoming book Digital Technology and Democratic Theory by Lucy Bernholz, Hélène Landemore, and Rob Reich (editors) published by the University of Chicago Press
 Abstract While technology is often claimed to be “democratizing”, the technologizing of society has more often yielded undemocratic or even anti-democratic outcomes. Is technology fundamentally at odds with democracy, or is it merely a rich and infinitely-adaptable toolbox that we’re using the wrong way?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure, Confidential Blockchains Providing High Throughput and Low Latency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2019-kokoris-kogias/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2019-kokoris-kogias/</guid>
      <description>Eleftherios Kokoris Kogias  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
September 27, 2019  Abstract:  One of the core promises of blockchain technology is that of enabling trustworthy data dissemination in a trustless environment. What current blockchain systems deliver, however, is slow dissemination of public data, rendering blockchain technology unusable in settings where latency, transaction capacity or data confidentiality is important. In this thesis, we focus on providing solutions on two of the most pressing problems blockchain technology currently faces: scalability and data confidentiality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rationality is Self-Defeating in Permissionless Systems</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/09/23/rational/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/09/23/rational/</guid>
      <description>by Bryan Ford and Rainer Böhme &amp;mdash; PDF preprint version available   Many blockchain and cryptocurrency fans seem to prefer building and analyzing decentralized systems in a rational or &amp;ldquo;greedy behavior&amp;rdquo; failure model, rather than a Byzantine or &amp;ldquo;arbitrary behavior&amp;rdquo; failure model. Many of the same blockchain and cryptocurrency fans also like open, permissionless systems like Bitcoin and Ethereum, which anyone can join and participate in using weak identities such as anonymous cryptography key pairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Only Type Parameters Generic Enough for Go 2 Generics?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/07/29/go-generics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/07/29/go-generics/</guid>
      <description>The Go language appears to be getting slightly closer to supporting generics, with the recent release of a new proposal for generics based on type parameters and contracts.
I generally like the direction this proposal is going, with one significant reservation. I feel that the current proposal both unnecessarily limits how &amp;ldquo;generic&amp;rdquo; Go&amp;rsquo;s generics will be, and risks painting the language into a corner in the long term. This is because the proposal single-mindedly assumes that the only compile-time generic parameters we will ever want are type parameters, which seems like an unnecessary and undesirable restriction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Metadata Leakage from Encrypted Files and Communication with PURBs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/purb-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/purb-abs/</guid>
      <description>Kirill Nikitin, Ludovic Barman, Wouter Lueks, Matthew Underwood, Jean-Pierre Hubaux and Bryan Ford EPFL - IC - DEDIS   Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium
July 2019.  Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
Volume 2019, Issue 4.  Abstract: Most encrypted data formats leak metadata via their plaintext headers, such as format version, encryption schemes used, number of recipients who can decrypt the data, and even the recipients’ identities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Security of Two-Round Multi-Signatures</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/two-round-multisig-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/two-round-multisig-abs/</guid>
      <description>Manu Drijvers, Kasra Edalatnejad, Bryan Ford, Eike Kiltz, Julian Loss, Gregory Neven, and Igors Stepanovs   40th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy
May 2019  Abstract: A multi-signature scheme allows a group of signers to collaboratively sign a message, creating a single signature that convinces a verifier that every individual signer approved the message. The increased interest in technologies to decentralize trust has triggered the proposal of highly efficient two-round Schnorr-based multi-signature schemes designed to scale up to thousands of signers, namely BCJ by Bagherzandi et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking General-Purpose Decentralized Computing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/protean-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/protean-abs/</guid>
      <description>Enis Ceyhun Alp, Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Georgia Fragkouli, and Bryan Ford EPFL - IC - DEDIS   17th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS XVII)
May 12-15, 2019.  Abstract: While showing great promise, smart contracts are difficult to program correctly, as they need a deep understanding of cryptography and distributed algorithms, and offer limited functionality, as they have to be deterministic and cannot operate on secret data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MorphIT: Morphing Packet Reports for Internet Transparency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/morphit-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/morphit-abs/</guid>
      <description>Georgia Fragkouli, Katerina Argyraki, and Bryan Ford EPFL   Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
May 4, 2019.  Abstract: Can we improve Internet transparency without worsening user anonymity? For a long time, researchers have been proposing transparency systems, where traffic reports produced at strategic network points help assess network behavior and verify service-level agreements or neutrality compliance. However, such reports necessarily reveal when certain traffic appeared at a certain network point, and this information could, in principle, be used to compromise low-latency anonymity networks like Tor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Remote Voting Minefield: from North Carolina to Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/02/22/voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/02/22/voting/</guid>
      <description>The absentee ballot fraud in North Carolina shows how current vote-by-mail methods are fundamentally flawed and vulnerable to vote-buying and coercion. But banning remote voting of any kind would disenfranchise everyone not living in their country of citizenship; that is not a real option.
It is important to understand in this light the context of the Swiss e-voting project, one of whose two implementations was recently opened to public inspection by the Swiss Post for inspection and analysis by international experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Priorities: Should Identity Systems Divide or Unite People?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/02/08/identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/02/08/identity/</guid>
      <description>Note: this is a brief, rough, first-draft sketch of a longer paper paper I intend to flesh out further in the near future.
The problem of identity has become a hot topic, with the idea of self-sovereign identity in particular attracting significant excitement. The essence of the idea, in short, is to put users in charge of how their identities and personal data are used. Self-sovereign identity posits that users should decide how much and what aspects of their identities to disclose in any situation, and should know and have control over what that information is used for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Biometrics a Good Test for Real Unique Personhood?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/biometric-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/biometric-id/</guid>
      <description>Are biometrics good for determining whether a digital identity uniquely represents a real person?
Break this down:
 Does it represent [the characteristics of] a person? Does it uniquely represent a person: i.e., the only identity of that person? Does it uniquely represent a real living person?  Authentication, Identification, and Real Personhood Biometric authentication is practical, and not necessarily a privacy disaster. Biometric template only needs to be stored on the device, &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So They&#39;re Selling You a Blockchain</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2018/09/11/blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2018/09/11/blockchain/</guid>
      <description>Blockchain is certainly one of the hot technology topics today. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s probably in part a hype bubble – but from my perspective as a long-time researcher in decentralized systems I believe there is also a lot of potential value in the concept, which is why my DEDIS lab at EPFL has been investing years of effort in building next generation blockchain architectures. I also believe the value of the blockchain concept is relatively independent of the unpredictable and scam-riddled &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://blockonomi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MedCo: Enabling Secure and Privacy-Conscious Exploration of Distributed Clinical and Genomic Data</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/medco-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/medco-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jean Louis Raisaro, Juan Ram&amp;oacute;n Troncoso-Pastoriza, Micka&amp;euml;l Misbach, Jo&amp;atilde;o S&amp;aacute; Sousa, Sylvain Pradervand, Edoardo Missiaglia, Olivier Michielin, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux   IEEE/ACM Transactions on Computational Biology and Bioinformatics,
July 13, 2018. Abstract: The increasing number of health-data breaches is creating a complicated environment for medical-data sharing and, consequently, for medical progress. Therefore, the development of new solutions that can reassure clinical sites by enabling privacy-preserving sharing of sensitive medical data in compliance with stringent regulations (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Scientific Conferences Must Leave the U.S.</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2018/06/27/muslim-ban/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2018/06/27/muslim-ban/</guid>
      <description>So the U.S. Supreme Court has upheld Trump&amp;rsquo;s so-called “travel ban” – more honestly labeled a Muslim ban. More precisely, it is a ban on people from Muslim-majority countries not hosting Trump business properties (see map and fact check).
Where to Hold Conferences? This development naturally and rightfully raises again to prominence the question of where responsible scientists should hold their international conferences. We may soon see renewed calls to boycott US-based conferences, in solidarity with the many scientists around the world who can no longer attend conferences held in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sightseeing Around Lausanne</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2018/06/16/lausanne/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2018/06/16/lausanne/</guid>
      <description>For the benefit those visiting but not yet familiar with EPFL, Lausanne, or other parts of the Lake Geneva Region, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a quick summary of some of my personal favorite places and sights in the area. This is completely my personal perspective; I make no pretense at being objective or unbiased here and am not trying to write a proper travel guide. But with that in mind, I hope you might find something interesting here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OmniLedger: A Secure, Scale-Out, Decentralized Ledger via Sharding</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/omniledger-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/omniledger-abs/</guid>
      <description>Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Philipp Jovanovic, Linus Gasser, Nicolas Gailly, Ewa Syta, and Bryan Ford
  IEEE Security &amp; Privacy (IEEE S&amp;P)
May 22, 2018 Abstract: Designing a secure permissionless distributed ledger (blockchain) that performs on par with centralized payment processors, such as Visa, is a challenging task. Most existing distributed ledgers are unable to scale-out, i.e., to grow their total processing capacity with the number of validators; and those that do, compromise security or decentralization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Enforcing the Digital Immunity of a Large Humanitarian Organization</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/immunity-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/immunity-abs/</guid>
      <description>Stevens Le Blond, Alejandro Cuevas, Juan Ram&amp;oacute;n Troncoso-Pastoriza, Philipp Jovanovic, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux
EPFL  Distinguished Paper Award   IEEE Security &amp; Privacy (IEEE S&amp;P)
May 22, 2018 Abstract: Humanitarian action, the process of aiding individuals in situations of crises, poses unique information-security challenges due to natural or manmade disasters, the adverse environments in which it takes place, and the scale and multidisciplinary nature of the problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure, Scalable Proof-of-Stake Blockchains</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/stake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/stake/</guid>
      <description>Proof-of-What? Currently-deployed permissionless blockchains such as Bitcoin and Ethereum rely on proof-of-work (PoW) to distribute both the computational networking costs, and the financial rewards, of maintaining and extending the blockchain. In proof-of-work systems, participating miners race (&amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo;) to compute solutions to cryptographic puzzles. These puzzles effectively act like self-printed lottery tickets, in that a miniscule fraction of these proof-of-work solutions may be easily verified by anyone as &amp;ldquo;winning&amp;rdquo; the lucky miner the right to add one block to the blockchain and collect associated rewards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom: Horizontally Scaling Strong Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/atom-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/atom-abs/</guid>
      <description>Albert Kwon
MIT  Henry Corrigan-Gibbs
Stanford  Srinivas Devadas
MIT  Bryan Ford
EPFL    26th ACM Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP)
October 30, 2017 Abstract: Atom is an anonymous messaging system that protects against traffic-analysis attacks. Unlike many prior systems, each Atom server touches only a small fraction of the total messages routed through the network. As a result, the system’s capacity scales near-linearly with the number of servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAINIAC: Proactive Software-Update Transparency via Collectively Signed Skipchains and Verified Builds</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/chainiac-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/chainiac-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do You Know It&#39;s On the Blockchain? With a SkipChain.</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2017/08/01/skipchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2017/08/01/skipchain/</guid>
      <description>A blockchain, or distributed ledger, is a log maintained collectively by a distributed group of participants who agree on and record transactions without relying for security on any single trusted party. While initially popularized by Bitcoin and its derivatives, the blockchain abstraction is not specific to currencies, and there is exploding industry interest in many non-currency uses.
  Many of these diverse use-cases, however, require users to be able to verify whether or not some transaction has been committed to a blockchain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UnLynx: A Decentralized System for Privacy-Conscious Data Sharing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/unlynx-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/unlynx-abs/</guid>
      <description>David Froelicher, Patricia Egger, Jo&amp;atilde;o S&amp;aacute; Sousa, Jean Louis Raisaro, Zhicong Huang, Christian Mouchet, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux   Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium (PETS)
July 19, 2017 Abstract: Current solutions for privacy-preserving data sharing among multiple parties either depend on a centralized authority that must be trusted and provides only weakest-link security (e.g., the entity that manages private/secret cryptographic keys), or leverage on decentralized but impractical approaches (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Governs Us. Will it Govern Us Well?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2017/06/23/turing50/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2017/06/23/turing50/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is a transcript of my opening remarks on the panel &#34;Restoring Personal Privacy without Compromising National Security&#34; at the 50 Years of the ACM Turing Award Celebration.   We now live in a world in which the rules coded into the technology we use plays as important a role in governing our lives as the formal laws written in the public law books. Code is law already, for better or worse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Bias-Resistant Distributed Randomness</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/random-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/random-abs/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta, Philipp Jovanovic, Eleftherios Kokoris Kogias, Nicolas Gailly, Linus Gasser, Ismail Khoffi, Michael J. Fischer, and Bryan Ford
  IEEE Security &amp; Privacy (IEEE S&amp;P)
May 23, 2017 Abstract: Bias-resistant public randomness is a critical component in many (distributed) protocols. Generating public randomness is hard, however, because active adversaries may behave dishonestly to bias public random choices toward their advantage. Existing solutions do not scale to hundreds or thousands of participants, as is needed in many decentralized systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof-of-Personhood: Redemocratizing Permissionless Cryptocurrencies</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</guid>
      <description>Maria Borge, Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Philipp Jovanovic, Linus Gasser, Nicolas Gailly, and Bryan Ford
EPFL   IEEE Security &amp; Privacy on the Blockchain (IEEE S&amp;B)
April 29, 2017 Abstract: Permissionless blockchain-based cryptocurrencies commonly use proof-of-work (PoW) or proof-of-stake (PoS) to ensure their security, e.g. to prevent double spending attacks. However, both approaches have disadvantages: PoW leads to massive amounts of wasted electricity and re-centralization, whereas major stakeholders in PoS might be able to create a monopoly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Objectives of Lawful-Surveillance Protocols</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/lawful-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/lawful-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selfish Mining in Bitcoin and ByzCoin</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/xx/xx/selfish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/xx/xx/selfish/</guid>
      <description>XXX intro
summary of selfish mining
selfish mining as a transparency problem: you get to build on a blockchain head you haven&amp;rsquo;t published.
same as transparency problem in Apple FBI case for example; that&amp;rsquo;s what CoSi is for.
solution: any keyblock you build on is collectively signed, and the next block&amp;rsquo;s hash covers the last block&amp;rsquo;s signature.
if you withhold a block, you can&amp;rsquo;t get a collective signature on it; without that collective signature, you can&amp;rsquo;t secretly mine a next block on top of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untangling Mining Incentives in Bitcoin and ByzCoin</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/10/25/mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/10/25/mining/</guid>
      <description>--   As the first widely-deployed cryptocurrency, Bitcoin has proven hugely successful and inspired a blockchain fever (or is it a bubble?). Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s security and economic assumptions are showing significant fractures, however. Following previously-identified selfish mining and stubborn mining attacks, new research from Princeton being presented at CCS identifies further incentive weaknesses that appear as transaction fees supplant block rewards as the primary incentive for mining.
In short, miners motivated by transaction fees have even greater incentive to deviate strategically from the standard Bitcoin protocol in selfish and potentially destructive ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-Preserving Lawful Contact Chaining</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/contact-chaining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/contact-chaining/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Bitcoin Security and Performance with Strong Consistency via Collective Signing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/byzcoin-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/byzcoin-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Efficient Communication System With Strong Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/riffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/riffle/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open, privacy-preserving protocols for lawful surveillance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/open-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/open-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Authorities “Honest or Bust” with Decentralized Witness Cosigning</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cosi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cosi/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AnonRep: Towards Tracking-Resistant Anonymous Reputation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Privacy-Preserving Cryptographic Credentials from Federated Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book-codaspy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book-codaspy/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple, FBI, and Software Transparency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/03/10/apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/03/10/apple/</guid>
      <description>*This post [originally appeared](https://freedom-to-tinker.com/blog/bford/apple-fbi-and-software-transparency/) on the [Freedom to Tinker](https://freedom-to-tinker.com/) blog by the [Center for Information Technology Policy](https://citp.princeton.edu) at [Princeton University](http://www.princeton.edu/).*  The Apple versus FBI showdown has quickly become a crucial flashpoint of the “new Crypto War.” On February 16 the FBI invoked the All Writs Act of 1789, a catch-all authority for assistance of law enforcement, demanding that Apple create a custom version of its iOS to help the FBI decrypt an iPhone used by one of the San Bernardino shooters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An advanced crypto library for Go</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/03/08/crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/03/08/crypto/</guid>
      <description>{{ page.title }} Interesting features:
  An abstract group arithmetic framework for public-key cryptography based on the discrete logarithm problem.
  Several alternative concrete instantiations of this abstract group arithmetic framework, based on the NIST elliptic curve implementations in the Go standard library and in the OpenSSL crypto library, and implementations of both generic Edwards curves and an adaptation of Adam Langley&amp;rsquo;s Ed25519-curve-specific optimized group arithmetic code to the abstract group API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backdoors, Trusted Servers, and Deanonymization</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/03/08/backdoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/03/08/backdoors/</guid>
      <description>{{ page.title }} To my knowledge there are currently only two fundamentally distinct approaches to achieving strong anonymity online, and the same legendary computing figure, David Chaum, pioneered both. His first approach, mixes, relay messages over multi-hop paths around the network to obscure their source and destinations. State-of-the-art deployed anonymity systems such as Tor are highly evolved and performance-optimized variants of this basic relaying idea.
Chaum&amp;rsquo;s second approach, dining cryptographers, instead uses information-coding principles to hide the sender of a message among a group of nodes all of whom seem to be spewing gibberish at once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to prove DNSSEC isn&#39;t a key escrow scheme</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/03/08/dnssec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/03/08/dnssec/</guid>
      <description>{{ page.title }} &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metadata Protection Considerations for TLS Present and Future</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/tlsmeta-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/tlsmeta-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
EPFL   TLS 1.3 Ready or Not (TRON) Workshop
February 21, 2016 Abstract: TLS 1.3 takes important steps to improve both performance and security, so far offers little protection against traffic analysis or fingerprinting using unencrypted metadata or other side-channels such as transmission lengths and timings. This paper explores metadata protection mechanisms for TLS, including already-included provisions (e.g., record padding), provisions not yet included but potentially feasible in TLS 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collectively Witnessing Log Servers in CT</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2015-10-20-cosi-ct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2015-10-20-cosi-ct/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford   draft-ford-trans-witness-00  Abstract: This document proposes a backward-compatible extension to CT enabling log servers to obtain compact collective signatures from any number of well-known &#34;witness&#34; servers, which clients can check without gossip to verify that log server records have been widely witnessed. Collective signatures proactively protect clients from man-in-the- middle attackers who may have stolen the private keys of one or more log servers, even if the attacker controls the client&#39;s network access, the client is unwilling to gossip for privacy reasons, or the client does not wish to incur the network bandwidth and/or latency costs of gossip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s verify real people, not real names.</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2015/10/07/names.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2015/10/07/names.html</guid>
      <description>On Monday the EFF, together with a &amp;ldquo;Nameless Coalition&amp;rdquo; of like-minded groups, escalated the backlash against Facebook&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;real names&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;authentic identities&amp;rdquo; policy with an open letter urging Facebook to end this policy like Google Plus did last year. Facebook&amp;rsquo;s response cites concerns about pseudonyms helping to hide &amp;ldquo;terrorist organizations&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;school bullies&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;criminal behavior.&amp;rdquo;
While I support anonymity and have spent years working to strengthen it, terrorist fearmongering aside, Facebook is right that anonymity is often abused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deterministically Deterring Timing Attacks in Deterland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-timing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-timing/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Anonymity in an Internet Panopticon</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/panopticon-cacm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/panopticon-cacm/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Flexible Architecture for Structural Reliability Auditing to the Clouds</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-zhai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-zhai/</guid>
      <description>Ennan Zhai  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
August 11, 2015  Abstract:  Today’s cloud computing systems pervasively rely on redundancy techniques to enhance reliability and availability. In complex multi-layered hardware/software stacks, however, seemingly independent components used redundantly might share deep, hidden dependencies. These common dependencies may potentially result in unexpected correlated failures, thus undermining redundancy efforts.  Heading off correlated failures is extremely challenging in cloud-scale systems for the following three reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identity Management through Privacy-Preserving Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-syta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-syta/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
August 11, 2015  Abstract:  Maintaining privacy on the Internet is increasingly difficult in this ever-connected world. In most cases, our online interactions are a highly personalized experience and require some form of identity verification, most commonly, logging into an account. Unfortunately, people frequently give away a lot of information while obtaining accounts, reuse usernames and passwords across different services, or link their accounts to take advantage of single sign-on to avoid retyping passwords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warding off Timing Channels in Deterland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-wu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-wu/</guid>
      <description>   Weiyi Wu  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
August 10, 2015  Abstract: XXX Ph.D. Thesis: PDF  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Eyes: Secure Remote Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta, Michael J. Fischer, David Wolinsky, Abraham Silberschatz, Gina Gallegos-García, and Bryan Ford   12th International Conference on Security and Cryptography (SECRYPT)
July 2015.  Abstract: We propose an efficient remote biometric authentication protocol that gives strong protection to the user’s biometric data in case of two common kinds of security breaches: (1) loss or theft of the user’s token (smart card, handheld device, etc.), giving the attacker full access to any secrets embedded within it; (2) total penetration of the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certificate Cothority: Towards Trustworthy Collective CAs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/certco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/certco/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Privacy-Preserving Cryptographic Credentials from Federated Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-maheswaran/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-maheswaran/</guid>
      <description>John Maheswaran  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
June 24, 2015  Abstract:  Third-party applications such as Quora or StackOverflow allow users to log in through a federated identity provider such as Facebook (Log in with Facebook), Google+ or Twitter. This process is called federated authentication. Examples of federated identity providers include social networks as well as other non-social network identity providers such as PayPal.  Federated identity providers have gained widespread popularity among users as a way to manage their online identity across the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/page/about/</guid>
      <description>About Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Aenean nec dolor in magna lobortis egestas. Suspendisse eu erat tempor, tristique neque eu, convallis nulla. Curabitur vel bibendum lacus, at semper mauris. Suspendisse aliquet commodo ex, sed sagittis metus aliquam id. Maecenas feugiat rutrum lorem vel imperdiet. Nullam ornare lectus ut enim finibus, et porttitor mi tincidunt. Aenean lacinia, leo quis vehicula eleifend, quam libero sagittis erat, at euismod augue mauris et sapien.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPUfs: The Case for Operating System Services on GPUs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/gpufs-cacm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/gpufs-cacm/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegative Democracy Revisited</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2014/11/16/deleg.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2014/11/16/deleg.html</guid>
      <description>Over a decade ago I wrote up some ideas I called &amp;ldquo;Delegative Democracy,&amp;rdquo; which has also become known as &amp;ldquo;Liquid Democracy.&amp;rdquo; My draft paper from 2002 took a first stab at laying out the general idea, though I never finished or tried to publish it. Since a lot has happened in this space since then, and I get regular inquiries about it, I thought it was high time to revisit the idea and review more recent developments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faculty size and growth in the top 20 Computer Science departments</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2014/10/22/cs-growth.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2014/10/22/cs-growth.html</guid>
      <description>Yesterday the Yale Daily News ran an article on our CS department&amp;rsquo;s faculty shortage, which generated some discussion among CS colleagues. Yale&amp;rsquo;s CS faculty shortage is not really news: for example, another YDN article over a year ago made basically the same point, and that probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t the first.
Setting aside Yale in particular, however, it is interesting to notice some broader trends in CS department growth. So here are a couple charts I recently put together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/post/2014-10-22-open-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/post/2014-10-22-open-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heading Off Correlated Failures through Independence-as-a-Service</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-indaas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-indaas/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching Bandits and Only Bandits: Privacy-Preserving Intersection Warrants for Lawful Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/bandits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/bandits/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing NymBoxes for Identity and Tracking Protection</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/nymboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/nymboxes/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Analysis of Accountable Anonymity in Dissent</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-analysis/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A TorPath to TorCoin: Proof-of-Bandwidth Altcoins for Compensating Relays</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/torcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/torcoin/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Onions to Shallots: Rewarding Tor Relays with TEARS</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/onions-to-shallots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/onions-to-shallots/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TAQ: Enhancing Fairness and Performance Predictability in Small Packet Regimes</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/taq-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/taq-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wire-Compatible TCP Implementation for Low-Latency Applications</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2014-nowlan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2014-nowlan/</guid>
      <description>Michael F. Nowlan  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
March 7, 2014  Abstract:  Despite alternative transport protocols more suitable to latency-sensitive applications, TCP remains the de facto standard for Internet traffic, including many low-latency, interactive applications. As such, applications often tweak the TCP protocol to better suit their needs but run the risk that any change to TCP’s wire format can cause reachability issues or complete failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crypto-Book: An Architecture for Privacy Preserving Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Cloud Audits that Protect Private Information</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-psra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-psra/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conscript Your Friends into Larger Anonymity Sets with JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/conscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/conscript/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring High-Quality Randomness in Cryptographic Key Generation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/randomness-keygen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/randomness-keygen/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hang With Your Buddies to Resist Intersection Attacks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/buddies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/buddies/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Untold Story of Redundant Clouds: Making Your Service Deployment Truly Reliable</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/irec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/irec/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proactively Accountable Anonymous Messaging in Verdict</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/verdict/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/verdict/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maple: Simplifying SDN Programming Using Algorithmic Policies</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/maple-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/maple-abs/</guid>
      <description>Andreas Voellmy, Junchang Wang, Y. Richard Yang, Bryan Ford, and Paul Hudak   ACM SIGCOMM 2013
August 12-16, 2013  Abstract: Software-Defined Networking offers the appeal of a simple, centralized programming model for managing complex networks. However, challenges in managing low-level details, such as setting up and maintaining correct and efficient forwarding tables on distributed switches, often compromise this conceptual simplicity. In this paper, we present Maple, a system that simplifies SDN programming by (1) allowing a programmer to use a standard programming language to design an arbitrary, centralized algorithm, which we call an algorithmic policy, to decide the behaviors of an entire network, and (2) providing an abstraction that the programmer-defined, centralized policy runs, conceptually, &amp;ldquo;afresh&amp;rdquo; on every packet entering a network, and hence is oblivious to the challenge of translating a high-level policy into sets of rules on distributed individual switches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Latency in Tor Circuits with Unordered Delivery</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/tor-unordered/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/tor-unordered/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy Tree Mapping: Generalizing and Scaling Deterministic Parallelism</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/lazy-tree-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/lazy-tree-mapping/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the World of Human Rights: Please Make Yourself Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/human-rights-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/human-rights-abs/</guid>
      <description>   Henry Corrigan-Gibbs and Bryan Ford Yale University   Cyber-security Research Ethics Dialog &amp; Strategy Workshop (CREDS 2013)
May 23, 2013  Abstract: We draw an ethical analogy between Internet freedom efforts and humanitarian aid work. This parallel motivates a number of ethical questions relating to anonymity and censorship-circumvention research. Paper: PDF  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPUfs: Integrating a File System with GPUs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/gpufs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/gpufs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the OS against Security Threats in System Administration</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/middleware12-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/middleware12-abs/</guid>
      <description>Nuno Santos, Rodrigo Rodrigues, and Bryan Ford   ACM/IFIP/USENIX 13th International Conference on Middleware
December 2012  Abstract: The consequences of security breaches due to system administrator errors can be catastrophic. Software systems in general, and OSes in particular, ultimately depend on a fully trusted administrator whom is granted superuser privileges that allow him to fully control the system. Consequently, an administrator acting negligently or unethically can easily compromise user data in irreversible ways by leaking, modifying, or deleting data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissent in Numbers: Making Strong Anonymity Scale</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-in-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-in-numbers/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deterministic OpenMP</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2012-aviram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2012-aviram/</guid>
      <description>Amittai F. Aviram  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
September 20, 2012  Abstract: Researchers widely agree that determinism in parallel programs is desirable. Although experimental parallel programming languages have long featured deterministic semantics, in mainstream parallel environments, developers still build on non-deterministic constructs such as mutexes, leading to time- or schedule-dependent heisenbugs. To make deterministic programming more accessible, we introduce DOMP, a deterministic extension to OpenMP, preserving the familiarity of traditional languages such as C and Fortran, and maintaining source-compatibility with much of the existing OpenMP standard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scavenging for Anonymity with BlogDrop</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/blogdrop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/blogdrop/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Software-Defined Network Controllers on Multicore Servers</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/scaling-sdn-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/scaling-sdn-abs/</guid>
      <description>Andreas Voellmy, Bryan Ford, Paul Hudak, and Y. Richard Yang Yale University Department of Computer Science
  Technical Report YALEU/DCS/TR-1468
July 2012  Abstract: Software defined networks (SDN) introduce centralized controllers to drastically increase network programmability. The simplicity of a logical centralized controller, however, can come at the cost of controller programming complexity and scalability. In this paper, we present McNettle, an extensible SDN controller system whose control event processing throughput scales with the number of system CPU cores and which supports control algorithms requiring globally visible state changes occurring at flow arrival rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-Linear Compression: Gzip Me Not!</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/non-linear/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/non-linear/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugging Side-Channel Leaks with Timing Information Flow Control</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/tifc-hotcloud12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/tifc-hotcloud12/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icebergs in the Clouds: the Other Risks of Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/icebergs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/icebergs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Theft-Proof Privacy-Preserving Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitting Square Pegs Through Round Pipes: Unordered Delivery Wire-Compatible with TCP and TLS</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/nsdi12-minion-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/nsdi12-minion-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faceless: Decentralized Anonymous Group Messaging for Online Social Networks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/faceless-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/faceless-abs/</guid>
      <description>Xiaoxiao Song, David Isaac Wolinsky, and Bryan Ford Yale University   5th Workshop on Social Network Systems
April 10, 2012  Abstract: Social networks (SNs) enable physically distributed groups to communicate seamlessly. Unfortunately such communi- cation can be easily mined by adversaries in attempts to breach users’ privacy or suppress open discussion on sensi- tive topics. While anonymous posting can help protect users by hiding the link between individuals and the messages they post, existing anonymization schemes are centralized or vul- nerable to well-known attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Anonymous Group Communication in the Anytrust Model</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/anytrust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/anytrust/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Virtual Memory Foundation for Scalable Deterministic Parallelism</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-vm/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CertiKOS: A Certified Kernel for Secure Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/certikos-apsys11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/certikos-apsys11/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eyo: Device-Transparent Personal Storage</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/eyo-usenix-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/eyo-usenix-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jacob Strauss, Justin Mazzola Paluska, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Bryan Ford, Robert Morris, and Frans Kaashoek
 2011 USENIX Annual Technical Conference June 15-17, 2011, Portland, OR, USA Abstract: Users increasingly store data collections such as digital photographs on multiple personal devices, each of which typically offers a storage management interface oblivious to the contents of the user’s other devices. As a result, collections become disorganized and drift out of sync.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deterministic OpenMP for Race-Free Parallelism</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-openmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-openmp/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspace Consistency: A Programming Model for Shared Memory Parallelism</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/workspace-consistency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/workspace-consistency/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dynamic Recursive Unified Internet Design (DRUID)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/druid-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/druid-abs/</guid>
      <description>Joe Touch, Ilia Baldine, Rudra Dutta, Gregory G. Finn, Bryan Ford, Scott Jordan, Dan Massey, Abraham Matta, Christos Papadopoulos, Peter Reiher, George Rouskas   Computer Networks December 24, 2010 Abstract: The Dynamic Recursive Unified Internet Design (DRUID) is a future Internet design that unifies overlay networks with conventional layered network architectures. DRUID is based on the fundamental concept of recursion, enabling a simple and direct network architecture that unifies the data, control, management, and security aspects of the current Internet, leading to a more trustworthy network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minion: an all-terrain packet packhorse to jump-start stalled internet transports</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/pfldnet10-minion-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/pfldnet10-minion-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determinating Timing Channels in Compute Clouds</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/timing-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/timing-abs/</guid>
      <description>Amittai Aviram, Sen Hu, Bryan Ford
	Ramakrishna Gummadi
	Yale University 	University of Massachusetts Amherst  The ACM Cloud Computing Security Workshop (CCSW 2010) October 8, 2010, Chicago, IL, USA Abstract: Timing side-channels represent an insidious security challenge for cloud computing, because: (a) massive parallelism in the cloud makes timing channels pervasive and hard to control; (b) timing channels enable one customer to steal information from another without leaving a trail or raising alarms; (c) only the cloud provider can feasibly detect and report such attacks, but the provider&#39;s incentives are not to; and (d) resource partitioning schemes for timing channel control undermine statistical sharing efficiency, and, with it, the cloud computing business model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient System-Enforced Deterministic Parallelism</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-osdi10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-osdi10/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissent: Accountable Anonymous Group Messaging</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/dissent-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/dissent-abs/</guid>
      <description>Henry Corrigan-Gibbs and Bryan Ford
	Yale University  To appear in 17th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS 2010) October 4-8, 2010, Chicago, IL, USA Abstract:  Users often wish to participate in online groups anonymously, but misbehaving users may abuse this anonymity to disrupt the group&#39;s communication. Existing messaging protocols such as DC-nets leave groups vulnerable to denial-of-service and Sybil attacks, Mix-nets are difficult to protect against traffic analysis, and accountable voting protocols are unsuited to general anonymous messaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Development of Certified OS Kernels</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/certified-kernels-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/certified-kernels-abs/</guid>
      <description>Zhong Shao and Bryan Ford Department of Computer Science, Yale University   Yale University Technical Report TR1436
July 15, 2010  Abstract: Operating System (OS) kernels form the bedrock of all system software&amp;mdash;they can have the greatest impact on the resilience, extensibility, and security of today’s computing hosts. A single kernel bug can easily wreck the entire system’s integrity and protection. We propose to apply new advances in certified software to the development of a novel OS kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unintended Consequences of NAT Deployments with Overlapping Address Space</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5684-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5684-abs/</guid>
      <description>Pyda Srisuresh and Bryan Ford   IETF RFC 5684
February 2010  Abstract: This document identifies two deployment scenarios that have arisen from the unconventional network topologies formed using Network Address Translator (NAT) devices. First, the simplicity of administering networks through the combination of NAT and DHCP has increasingly lead to the deployment of multi-level inter-connected private networks involving overlapping private IP address spaces. Second, the proliferation of private networks in enterprises, hotels and conferences, and the wide-spread use of Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) to access an enterprise intranet from remote locations has increasingly lead to overlapping private IP address space between remote and corporate networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Cross-Layer Negotiation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/nego-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/nego-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
	Janardhan Iyengar
	Yale University 	Franklin &amp;amp; Marshall College  Published in Eighth ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets-VIII) October 22-23, 2009, New York City, NY, USA Abstract: Internet evolution often depends on either inserting new protocol layers or upgrading existing layers to new protocols, but both of these evolutionary paths are obstructed by the difficulty and inefficiency of determining which protocols a pair of hosts mutually support and prefer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Device Transparency: a New Model for Mobile Storage</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/devtransp-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/devtransp-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jacob Strauss
	Chris Lesniewski-Laas
	Justin Mazzola Paluska
	Bryan Ford
	Robert Morris
	Frans Kaashoek
 Published in SOSP Workshop on Hot Topics in Storage and File Systems (HotStorage &#39;09) October 11, 2009, Big Sky, MT, USA Abstract: This paper proposes a new storage model, device transparency, in which users view and manage their entire data collection from any of their devices, even from disconnected storage-limited devices holding only a subset of the entire collection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAT Behavioral Requirements for ICMP</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5508-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5508-abs/</guid>
      <description>Pyda Srisuresh, Bryan Ford, Senthil Sivakumar, and Saikat Guha   IETF RFC 5508
April 2009  Abstract: This document specifies the behavioral properties required of the Network Address Translator (NAT) devices in conjunction with the Internet Control Message Protocol (ICMP). The objective of this memo is to make NAT devices more predictable and compatible with diverse application protocols that traverse the devices. Companion documents provide behavioral recommendations specific to TCP, UDP, and other protocols.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Up the Transport Logjam</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/logjam-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/logjam-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
	Janardhan Iyengar
	Massachusetts Institute of Technology 	Franklin &amp;amp; Marshall College  Published in Seventh ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets-VII) October 6-7, 2008, Calgary, Alberta, Canada Abstract: Current Internet transports conflate transport semantics with endpoint addressing and flow regulation, creating roadblocks to Internet evolution that we propose to address with a new layering model. Factoring endpoint addressing (port numbers) into a separate Endpoint Layer permits incremental rollout of new or improved transports at OS or application level, enables transport-oblivious firewall/NAT traversal, improves transport negotiation efficiency, and simplifies endpoint address space administration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAT Behavioral Requirements for TCP</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5382-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5382-abs/</guid>
      <description>   Saikat Guha, Kaushik Biswas, Bryan Ford, Senthil Sivakumar, and Pyda Srisuresh   IETF RFC 5382
October 2008  Abstract: This document defines a set of requirements for NATs that handle TCP that would allow many applications, such as peer-to-peer applications and online games to work consistently. Developing NATs that meet this set of requirements will greatly increase the likelihood that these applications will function properly. Final RFC: Plain text  Early drafts:   IETF working group draft versions: 06 05 04 03 02 01 00  Individual draft versions: 02 01 00  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIA: A Global Connectivity Architecture for Mobile Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Ph.D. thesis, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, September 2008. Abstract:  The Internet&#39;s architecture, designed in the days of large, stationary computers tended by technically savvy and accountable administrators, fails to meet the demands of the emerging ubiquitous computing era. Nontechnical users now routinely own multiple personal devices, many of them mobile, and need to share information securely among them using interactive, delay-sensitive applications.  Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) is a novel, incrementally deployable network architecture for modern personal devices, which reconsiders three architectural cornerstones: naming, routing, and transport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIA: A Global Connectivity Architecture for Mobile Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2008-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2008-phd/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vx32: Lightweight User-level Sandboxing on the x86</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/vx32-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/vx32-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Russ Cox
Massachusetts Institute of Technology USENIX Annual Technical Conference
Awarded Best Student Paper
June 22-27, 2008, Boston, Massachusetts. Abstract:  Code sandboxing is useful for many purposes, but most sandboxing techniques require kernel modifications, do not completely isolate guest code, or incur substantial performance costs. Vx32 is a multipurpose user-level sandbox that enables any application to load and safely execute one or more guest plug-ins, confining each guest to a system call API controlled by the host application and to a restricted memory region within the host&amp;rsquo;s address space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Offline Foundation for Online Accountable Pseudonyms</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Jacob Strauss 
Massachusetts Institute of Technology First Workshop on Social Network Systems
April 1, 2008 Abstract:  Online anonymity often appears to undermine accountability, offering little incentive for civil behavior, but accountability failures usually result not from anonymity itself but from the disposability of virtual identities. A user banned for misbehavior&amp;mdash;e.g., spamming from a free E-mail account or stuffing an online ballot box&amp;mdash;can simply open other accounts or connect from other IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Peer-to-Peer (P2P) Communication across Network Address Translators (NATs)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5128-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5128-abs/</guid>
      <description>Pyda Srisuresh, Bryan Ford, and Dan Kegel   IETF RFC 5128
March 2008  Abstract: This memo documents the various methods known to be in use by applications to establish direct communication in the presence of Network Address Translators (NATs) at the current time. Although this memo is intended to be mainly descriptive, the Security Considerations section makes some purely advisory recommendations about how to deal with security vulnerabilities the applications could inadvertently create when using the methods described.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Directions in Internet Transport Evolution</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/transport-ietf-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/transport-ietf-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpaca: Extensible Authorization for Distributed Services</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/alpaca-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/alpaca-abs/</guid>
      <description>Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Robert Morris, and M. Frans Kaashoek
Massachusetts Institute of Technology Published in 14th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security, Oct 29-Nov 2, 2007, Alexandria, VA. Abstract:  Traditional Public Key Infrastructures (PKI) have not lived up to their promise because there are too many ways to define PKIs, too many cryptographic primitives to build them with, and too many administrative domains with incompatible roots of trust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured Streams: a New Transport Abstraction</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/sst-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/sst-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Massachusetts Institute of Technology Published in ACM SIGCOMM 2007, August 27-31, 2007, Kyoto, Japan. Abstract:  Internet applications currently have a choice between stream and datagram transport abstractions. Datagrams efficiently support small transactions and streams are suited for long-running conversations, but neither abstraction adequately supports applications like HTTP that exhibit a mixture of transaction sizes, or applications like FTP and SIP that use multiple transport instances. Structured Stream Transport (SST) enhances the traditional stream abstraction with a hierarchical hereditary structure, allowing applications to create lightweight child streams from any existing stream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi/</guid>
      <description>Persistent Personal Names for Globally Connected Mobile Devices Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, Robert Morris
	Massachusetts Institute of Technology Published in 7th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation, November 6-8, 2006.   Abstract:   The  Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) provides zero-configuration connectivity among mobile devices through personal names. Users assign personal names through an ad hoc device introduction process requiring no central allocation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent Personal Names for Globally Connected Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, Robert Morris
 Massachusetts Institute of Technology 7th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation
November 6-8, 2006 Abstract:  The  Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) provides zero-configuration connectivity among mobile devices through personal names. Users assign personal names through an ad hoc device introduction process requiring no central allocation. Once assigned, names bind securely to the global identities of their target devices independent of network location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sybil Parties: An Offline Foundation for Online Accountability</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/log/2006/0924-SybilParties.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/log/2006/0924-SybilParties.html</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford - September 24, 2006 Preliminary draft: see here for the final published paper  The Human Recognition Problem  Today&#39;s online ecosphere continually suffers from its inability to tell who is a genuine, unique human and who isn&#39;t. Because open-access messaging systems cannot isolate or authenticate the human source of messages for the purpose of suppressing abuses, spam has already relegated USENET to historical obscurity [Templeton01], threatens the usability of E-mail [Wouters05], and is even advancing on Skype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User-Relative Names for Globally Connected Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-iptps-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-iptps-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, and Robert Morris Massachusetts Institute of Technology   5th International Workshop on Peer-to-Peer Systems
February 27-28, 2006  Abstract The User Information Architecture, or UIA, is a peer-to-peer connectivity architecture that provides users a simple, intuitive, and secure way to share information and services between personal devices by assigning ad hoc names that act like &amp;ldquo;virtual cables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VXA: A Virtual Architecture for Durable Compressed Archives</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/vxa-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/vxa-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Massachusetts Institute of Technology 4th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies (FAST &#39;05)
December 16, 2005, San Francisco, California, USA. Abstract:  Data compression algorithms change frequently, and obsolete decoders do not always run on new hardware and operating systems, threatening the long-term usability of content archived using those algorithms. Re-encoding content into new formats is cumbersome, and highly undesirable when lossy compression is involved. Processor architectures, in contrast, have remained comparatively stable over recent decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer-to-Peer Communication Across Network Address Translators</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/p2pnat-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/p2pnat-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Massachusetts Institute of Technology baford (at) mit.edu Pyda Srisuresh Caymas Systems, Inc. srisuresh (at) yahoo.com Dan Kegel dank (at) kegel.com   Presented at the USENIX Annual Technical Conference, April 10-15, 2005. Abstract:  Network Address Translation (NAT) causes well-known difficulties for peer-to-peer (P2P) communication, since the peers involved may not be reachable at any globally valid IP address. Several NAT traversal techniques are known, but their documentation is slim, and data about their robustness or relative merits is slimmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/p2pnat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/p2pnat/</guid>
      <description>Peer-to-Peer Communication Across Network Address Translators Bryan Ford Massachusetts Institute of Technology baford (at) mit.edu Pyda Srisuresh Caymas Systems, Inc. srisuresh (at) yahoo.com Dan Kegel dank (at) kegel.com    J&#39;fais des trous, des petits troustoujours des petits trous &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; - S. Gainsbourg  Abstract:  Network Address Translation (NAT) causes well-known difficulties for peer-to-peer (P2P) communication, since the peers involved may not be reachable at any globally valid IP address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Design Guidelines for Traversal through Network Address Translators</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2005/02/01/behave-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2005/02/01/behave-app/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Pyda Srisuresh, and Dan Kegel   draft-ford-behave-app  Abstract: This document defines guidelines by which application designers can create applications that communicate reliably and efficiently in the presence of Network Address Translators (NATs), particularly when the application has a need for &#34;peer-to-peer&#34; (P2P) type of communication. The guidelines allow a P2P application to work reliably across a majority of existing NATs, as well as all future NATs that conform to the behave requirements specified in companion documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operating Principles and General Behavioral Requirements for Network Address Translators (BEH-GEN)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2005/02/01/behave-gen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2005/02/01/behave-gen/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Pyda Srisuresh   draft-ford-behave-gen
 Abstract: This document discusses the operating principles of Network Address Translator (NAT) devices and the behavioral properties required to make NAT more predictable and compatible with diverse application protocols. First, this document presents an architectural model for NAT devices and defines important terms used in conjunction with NAT operation. The architectural model sets the stage for a set of concrete recommendations for NAT implementers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual Representation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2004/11/23/indrep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2004/11/23/indrep/</guid>
      <description>Real Choice for Voters, Democratic Currency for Activists Introduction The traditional purpose of popular elections is primarily to elect candidates to government offices or legislative seats, but this is not the only way we could use elections to facilitate democracy. Individual Representation, or indrep, provides a new and different reason to hold popular elections: as a tool for directly promoting the growth of grassroots social and political relationships throughout the basic fabric of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiki Democracy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2004/08/16/wiki-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2004/08/16/wiki-democracy/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cache Directory Tagging Specification</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/cachedir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/cachedir/</guid>
      <description>Version 0.6 (Changes)  Proposed by Bryan Ford  Abstract Many applications create and manage directories containing cached information about content stored elsewhere, such as cached Web content or thumbnail-size versions of images or movies. For speed and storage efficiency we would often like to avoid backing up, archiving, or otherwise unnecessarily copying such directories around, but it is a pain to identify and individually exclude each such directory during data transfer operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parsing Expression Grammars: A Recognition-Based Syntactic Foundation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/peg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/peg/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Massachusetts Institute of Technology  Symposium on Principles of Programming Languages, January 14-16, 2004, Venice, Italy   Abstract For decades we have been using Chomsky&#39;s generative system of grammars, particularly context-free grammars (CFGs) and regular expressions (REs), to express the syntax of programming languages and protocols. The power of generative grammars to express ambiguity is crucial to their original purpose of modelling natural languages, but this very power makes it unnecessarily difficult both to express and to parse machine-oriented languages using CFGs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unmanaged Internet Protocol: Taming the Edge Network Management Crisis</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-case-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-case-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Massachusetts Institute of Technology   Second Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks
November 20-21, 2003  Abstract: Though appropriate for core Internet infrastructure, the Internet Protocol is unsuited to routing within and between emerging ad-hoc edge networks due to its dependence on hierarchical, administratively assigned addresses. Existing ad-hoc routing protocols address the management problem but do not scale to Internet-wide networks. The promise of ubiquitous network computing cannot be fulfilled until we develop an Unmanaged Internet Protocol (UIP), a scalable routing protocol that manages itself automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Internet Routing on Topology-Independent Node Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Massachusetts Institute of Technology   Technical Report MIT-LCS-TR-926
October 31, 2003  Abstract: Unmanaged Internet Protocol (UIP) is a fully self-organizing network-layer protocol that implements scalable identity-based routing. In contrast with address-based routing protocols, which depend for scalability on centralized hierarchical address management, UIP nodes use a flat namespace of cryptographic node identifiers. Node identities can be created locally on demand and remain stable across network changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fx86: Functional Management of Imperative Virtual Machines</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2003/08/28/fx86/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2003/08/28/fx86/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Duality - Vitalizing the Commons</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2003/07/24/service-duality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2003/07/24/service-duality/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegative Voting</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2002/10/21/deleg-voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2002/10/21/deleg-voting/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packrat Parsing: Simple, Powerful, Lazy, Linear Time</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/packrat-icfp02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/packrat-icfp02/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Massachusetts Institute of Technology  International Conference on Functional Programming, October 4-6, 2002, Pittsburgh   Abstract Packrat parsing is a novel technique for implementing parsers in a lazy functional programming language. A packrat parser provides the power and flexibility of top-down parsing with backtracking and unlimited lookahead, but nevertheless guarantees linear parse time. Any language defined by an LL(k) or LR(k) grammar can be recognized by a packrat parser, in addition to many languages that conventional linear-time algorithms do not support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packrat Parsing: a Practical Linear-Time Algorithm with Backtracking</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/thesis/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Master&#39;s Thesis
Massachusetts Institute of Technology   Abstract  Packrat parsing is a novel and practical method for implementing linear-time parsers for grammars defined in Top-Down Parsing Language (TDPL). While TDPL was originally created as a formal model for top-down parsers with backtracking capability, this thesis extends TDPL into a powerful general-purpose notation for describing language syntax, providing a compelling alternative to traditional context-free grammars (CFGs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packrat Parsing: a Practical Linear-Time Algorithm with Backtracking</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2002-masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2002-masters/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegative Democracy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2002/05/15/deleg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2002/05/15/deleg/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interface and Execution Models in the Fluke Kernel</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/atomic-osdi99-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/atomic-osdi99-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Mike Hibler, Jay Lepreau, Roland McGrath, and Patrick Tullmann 
Department of Computer Science, University of Utah  3rd Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation
February 22-25, 1999 Abstract:  We have defined and implemented a kernel API that makes every exported operation fully interruptible and restartable, thereby appearing atomic to the user. To achieve interruptibility, all possible kernel states in which a thread may become blocked for a &amp;ldquo;long&amp;rdquo; time are represented as kernel system calls, without requiring the kernel to retain any unexposable internal state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flux OSKit: A Substrate for Kernel and Language Research</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/oskit-sosp16-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/oskit-sosp16-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Godmar Back, Greg Benson, Jay Lepreau, Albert Lin, and Olin Shivers 
 Proceedings of the 16th ACM Symposium on Operating System Principles
October 5-8, 1997 Abstract:  Implementing new operating systems is tedious, costly, and often impractical except for large projects. The Flux OSKit addresses this problem in a novel way by providing clean, well-documented OS components designed to be reused in a wide variety of other environments, rather than defining a new OS structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flick: A Flexible, Optimizing IDL Compiler</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/flick-pldi97-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/flick-pldi97-abs/</guid>
      <description>Eric Eide, Kevin Frei, Bryan Ford, Jay Lepreau, and Gary Lindstrom University of Utah, Department of Computer Science   ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation
June 15-18, 1997.  Abstract: Modern operating systems must support a wide variety of services for a diverse set of users. Designers of these systems face a tradeoff between functionality and performance. Systems like Mach provide a set of general abstractions and attempt to handle every situation, which can lead to poor performance for common cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flux OS Toolkit: Reusable Components for OS Implementation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/oskit-hotos6-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/oskit-hotos6-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Kevin Van Maren, Jay Lepreau, Stephen Clawson, Bart Robinson, and Jeff Turner
University of Utah 6th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS-VI)
May 5-6, 1997 Abstract:  To an unappreciated degree, research both in operating systems and their programming languages has been severely hampered by the lack of cleanly reusable code providing mundane low-level OS infrastructure such as bootstrap code and device drivers. The Flux OS Toolkit solves this problem by providing a set of clean, well-documented components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CPU Inheritance Scheduling</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/inherit-sched-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 1996 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/inherit-sched-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Sai R. Susarla  Department of Computer Science, University of Utah  Proceedings of the Second Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation
October 28-31, 1996  Abstract: Traditional processor scheduling mechanisms in operating systems are fairly rigid, often supporting only one fixed scheduling policy, or, at most, a few &amp;ldquo;scheduling classes&amp;rdquo; whose implementations are closely tied together in the OS kernel. This paper presents CPU inheritance scheduling, a novel processor scheduling framework in which arbitrary threads can act as schedulers for other threads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microkernels Meet Recursive Virtual Machines</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/fluke-rvm-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 1996 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/fluke-rvm-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Mike Hibler, Jay Lepreau, Patrick Tullmann, Godmar Back, and Stephen Clawson
University of Utah USENIX 2nd Symposium on OS Design and Implementation (OSDI &#39;96)
October 28-31, 1996, Seattle, Washington, USA. Abstract:  This paper describes a novel approach to providing modular and extensible operating system functionality and encapsulated environments based on a synthesis of microkernel and virtual machine concepts. We have developed a software-based virtualizable architecture called Fluke that allows recursive virtual machines (virtual machines running on other virtual machines) to be implemented efficiently by a microkernel running on generic hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User-level Checkpointing Through Exportable Kernel State</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/iwooos96-flobs-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 1996 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/iwooos96-flobs-abs/</guid>
      <description>Patrick Tullmann, Jay Lepreau, Bryan Ford, and Mike Hibler  Department of Computer Science, University of Utah  Proceedings of the Fifth IEEE International Workshop on Object Orientation in Operating Systems (IWOOOS)
October 27-28, 1996  Abstract: Checkpointing, process migration, and similar services need to have access not only to the memory of the constituent processes, but also to the complete state of all kernel provided objects (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Persistent Relevance of the Local Operating System to Global Applications</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/dist-vs-local-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 1996 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/dist-vs-local-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jay Lepreau, Bryan Ford, and Mike Hibler  Department of Computer Science, University of Utah  Proceedings of the Seventh ACM SIGOPS European Workshop
September 9-11, 1996  Abstract: The growth and popularity of loosely-coupled distributed systems such as the World Wide Web and the touting of Java-based systems as the solution to the issues of software maintenance, flexibility, and security are changing the research emphasis away from traditional single node operating system issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Annotated Interface Definitions to Optimize RPC</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/presint3-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 1995 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/presint3-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Mike Hibler, and Jay Lepreau University of Utah, Department of Computer Science   Technical Report UUCS-95-014
March 1995.  Abstract: In RPC-based communication, it is useful to distinguish the RPC interface, which is the “network contract” be- tween the client and the server, from the presentation, which is the “programmer’s contract” between the RPC stubs and the code that calls or is called by them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Separating Presentation from Interface in RPC and IDLs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/presint2-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 1994 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/presint2-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Mike Hibler, and Jay Lepreau University of Utah, Department of Computer Science   Technical Report UUCS-95-018
December 1994.  Abstract: In RPC-based communication, we term the interface the set of remote procedures and the types of their arguments; the presentation is the way these procedures and types are mapped to the target language environment in a particular client or server, including semantic requirements. For example, presentation includes the local names assigned to RPC stubs, the physical representation of a logical block of data (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolving Mach 3.0 to A Migrating Thread Model</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/thread-migrate-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 1994 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/thread-migrate-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Jay Lepreau  Department of Computer Science, University of Utah  Proceedings of the Winter 1994 USENIX Technical Conference
January 17-21, 1994  Abstract: We have modified Mach 3.0 to treat cross-domain remote procedure call (RPC) as a single entity, instead of a sequence of message passing operations. With RPC thus elevated, we improved the transfer of control during RPC by changing the thread model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microkernels Should Support Passive Objects</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/passive-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 1993 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/passive-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Jay Lepreau  Department of Computer Science, University of Utah  International Workshop on Object Orientation in Operating Systems (IWOOOS)
December 9-10, 1993  Abstract: We believe that a passive object model, in which the active entities or threads migrate between passive objects, is more appropriate than an active object model, as the basic structure of a microkernel-based operating system. A passive object model provides enhanced performance and simplicity because it is more closely matched to the basic nature of microprocessors and the requirements of applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FLEX: A Tool for Building Efficient and Flexible Systems</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/flex-wwos4-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 1993 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/flex-wwos4-abs/</guid>
      <description>John B. Carter, Bryan Ford, Mike Hibler, Ravindra Kuramkote, Jeffrey Law, Jay Lepreau, Douglas B. Orr, Leigh Stoller, and Mark Swanson University of Utah, Department of Computer Science   4th IEEE Workshop on Workstation Operating Systems (WWOS)
October 14-15, 1993.  Abstract: Modern operating systems must support a wide variety of services for a diverse set of users. Designers of these systems face a tradeoff between functionality and performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-Kernel Servers on Mach 3.0: Implementation and Performance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/inks-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 1993 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/inks-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jay Lepreau, Mike Hibler, Bryan Ford, and Jeffrey Law  Department of Computer Science, University of Utah  Proceedings of the Third USENIX Mach Symposium
April 1993  Abstract: The advantages in modularity and power of microkernel-based operating systems such as Mach 3.0 are well known. The existing performance problems of these systems, however, are significant. Much of the performance degradation is due to the cost of maintaining separate protection domains, traversing software layers, and using a semantically rich inter-process communication mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Thread Models in Mach 3.0</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/threadmodel-93-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 1993 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/threadmodel-93-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Mike Hibler, and Jay Lepreau Department of Computer Science, University of Utah   Technical Report UUCS-93-012
April 1993  Abstract: During the Mach In-Kernel Servers work, we explored two alternate thread models that could be used to support traps to in-kernel servers. In the &amp;ldquo;migrating threads&amp;rdquo; model we used, the client&#39;s thread temporarily moves into the server&#39;s task for the duration of the call. In the &amp;ldquo;thread switching&amp;rdquo; model, an actual server thread is dispatched to handle client traps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object-Oriented Display Refreshing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/call-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 1992 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/call-lists/</guid>
      <description> &amp;ldquo;CallLists is a refreshing way to keep your interactive programs up to date.&amp;rdquo;  Bryan Ford
 AmigaWorld Tech Journal
Volume 2 Number 2, April 1992   Article: PDF  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/async/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/async/</guid>
      <description>For another thing, I’m personally not a big believer in the practical value of the asynchronous model anyway. I know I’m at odds here with most people with a theory/algorithms background; reasonable people may differ. :) Almost every practical distributed system that ever actually gets deployed has timeouts and such buried in it here, there, everywhere. User-experience expectations are synchronous, not asynchronous: even if the underlying protocol is in principle perfectly capable of tolerating arbitrarily-long adversary-controlled propagation delays among honest nodes, the real users relying on the system are going to start complaining rather soon after the expected/normal amount of transaction time elapses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/vx32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/vx32/</guid>
      <description>Vx32: Lightweight, User-level Sandboxing on the x86    Vx32: Lightweight, User-level Sandboxing on the x86  Bryan Ford and Russ Cox Massachusetts Institute of Technology {baford,rsc}@pdos.csail.mit.edu  Abstract Code sandboxing is useful for many purposes, but most sandboxing techniques require kernel modifications, do not completely isolate guest code, or incur substantial performance costs. Vx32 is a multipurpose user-level sandbox that enables any application to load and safely execute one or more guest plug-ins, confining each guest to a system call API controlled by the host application and to a restricted memory region within the host&amp;rsquo;s address space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/vxa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/vxa/</guid>
      <description>VXA: A Virtual Architecture for Durable Compressed Archives Bryan Ford 	Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory 	Massachusetts Institute of Technology   Abstract:  Data compression algorithms change frequently, and obsolete decoders do not always run on new hardware and operating systems, threatening the long-term usability of content archived using those algorithms. Re-encoding content into new formats is cumbersome, and highly undesirable when lossy compression is involved. Processor architectures, in contrast, have remained comparatively stable over recent decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aachen</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2005/0717-Aachen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2005/0717-Aachen/</guid>
      <description>Aachen (Aix-la-Chapelle) July 17, 2005  &amp;nbsp; 
From the quiet and privincial side streets of Aachen...  &amp;nbsp;  &amp;nbsp; 
...you wouldn&#39;t know that it was the capital of the Holy Roman Empire.  &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 
 &amp;nbsp; 
Inside Charlemagne&#39;s cathedral  &amp;nbsp; 
The remains of Charlemagne&#39;s palace 
with the Rathaus glued onto it 
and the local pub nestled in the middle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antelope Island</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/AntelopeIsland.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/AntelopeIsland.html</guid>
      <description>   Antelope Island  No, I have no idea what it was...  The Attack (yeah - she started it!!!)  The Duel...  The Reconciliation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avignon</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2005/0305-Avignon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2005/0305-Avignon/</guid>
      <description>  Avignon March 5, 2005 
&amp;nbsp; 
Place de l&#39;Horloge   &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 
 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 
Place du Palais  &amp;nbsp; 
 &amp;nbsp; 
Rocher de Doms  &amp;nbsp; 
Pont Saint B&amp;eacute;nezet  



 &amp;nbsp; 
Rue des Teinturiers   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bar Harbor, Maine</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2002/0527-BarHarbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2002/0527-BarHarbor/</guid>
      <description>Bar Harbor, Maine (Memorial Day Weekend, May 24-27, 2002)   A hazy view of Bar Harbor from the top of Mount Desert. (Yep, that&#39;s really its name.)        A lovely day at the beach.   And lo, the prophet Zebadia went down to the sea, and he spake unto the multitudes, saying...   Seek, and ye shall find; but beware the curious onlooker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barcelona</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2003/0527-Barcelona/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2003/0527-Barcelona/</guid>
      <description>Barcelona May 2003 My colleague Athicha and I spent a week early in the summer exploring Barcelona and other nearby attractions in Catalonia, Spain.  
Walking the narrow streets 	
Barcelona&#39;s version of the Arc de Triomphe
(every European city&#39;s gotta have one) 
Getting trampled by a thundering herd of green-capped kids 
A perfectly ordinary building...
with flaming torches at night</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2005/0820-Berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2005/0820-Berlin/</guid>
      <description>Berlin August 19-22, 2005  Potsdamer Platz  
 



 
   
 The Sony Center
(Helmut Jahn, 1996-2000)  
The Berlin Philharmonic in Kulturforum   Friedrichstrasse  
The job of a checkpoint guard
just ain&#39;t what it used to be. 
Just garbage.
&amp;nbsp;   

 

 Brides&#39; Day Out on Gendarmenmarkt</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary Encoded Schematic Objects (BESO)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/beso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/beso/</guid>
      <description>BESO provides a generic representation for any JSON, using JSON Schema information to provide a compact binary encoding. Unlike schema-free binary encodings like BSON and CBOR, BESO encoding leverages the schema to optimize the encoded representation, for example by replacing object tags specified in the schema with small integers, by representing numbers in binary integer or floating-point forms, etc.
BESO Generic does not modify the JSON Schema language at all. It takes only the information already specified in a JSON schema and provides a more compact schema-optimized binary representation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonn</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2005/0709-Bonn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2005/0709-Bonn/</guid>
      <description>  Bonn July 9, 2005 The Botanical Garden  &amp;nbsp;   &amp;nbsp;   &amp;nbsp;   &amp;nbsp;    Rheinaue Freizeitpark  
This metal ball is actually a giant merry-go-round that can be rotated manually and even ridden. The kid was fascinated.    &amp;nbsp;    Blindengarten    &amp;nbsp;   &amp;nbsp;  Nightlife  &amp;nbsp;     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bryan&#39;s Family</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Family.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Family.html</guid>
      <description>   Bryan&#39;s Family    My father, Robert E. Ford&amp;nbsp;   My mother Karen      My little brother Colby&amp;nbsp;  The family cat, Carmen San Diego,&amp;nbsp; in her natural furball state.&amp;nbsp;    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bryan&#39;s Home in Cambridge</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Home.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Home.html</guid>
      <description>Bryan&#39;s Home  I&#39;m now a proud first-time homeowner of a wee little place in Cambridge, Massachusetts! It&#39;s the second-floor condo in this cute old-style building near Inman Square: Of course, indoor shots in a small place are really difficult without a good wide-angle lens, which I don&#39;t have unfortunately, but here are a couple pitiful attempts anyway... The Living Room.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s my dad on the futon. The Kitchen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cologne</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2005/0723-Cologne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2005/0723-Cologne/</guid>
      <description>K&amp;ouml;ln (Cologne, Germany - July 23, 2005)   

Soap bubbles in front of the cathedral!    
There was absolutely no one to be found in St. Maria-im-Kapitol.  
The locals seem to have a Lace Curtain Competition running...   
but this is where we actually found them.  
 
 
In the Rheingarten.    &amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Composable Markup (CMark)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/cmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/cmark/</guid>
      <description>Hyphen  X	[-]	Optional line-breaking hyphen??? &amp;ndash;	–	[&amp;ndash;]	En-dash or numeric range &amp;mdash;	—	[&amp;mdash;]	Em-dash &amp;hellip;	…	[&amp;hellip;]	Ellipsis  &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;	Quoted string: quotes become left/right
⏎	[br]	Line break ␍	[r]	Carriage return character mark ␤	[n]	Newline character mark ¶	[p]	Paragraph mark X	[o&#39;]	Open single quote X	[c&#39;]	Close single quote X	[o&amp;quot;]	Open double quote X	[c&amp;quot;]	Close double quote X	[o&amp;lt;&amp;gt;]	Open angle bracket X	[c&amp;lt;&amp;gt;]	Close angle bracket X	[o&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;]	Open double angle bracket X	[c&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;]	Close double angle bracket  Spacing: &amp;quot; &amp;quot;	[mq_]	Em quad space &amp;quot; &amp;quot;	[nq_]	En quad space &amp;quot; &amp;quot;	[m_]	Em space &amp;quot; &amp;quot;	[n_]	En space &amp;quot; &amp;quot;	[3m_]	Three-per-Em space &amp;quot; &amp;quot;	[4m_]	Four-per-Em space &amp;quot; &amp;quot;	[6m_]	Six-per-Em space &amp;quot; &amp;quot;	[d_]	Figure (digit) space &amp;quot; &amp;quot;	[.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Composable Math Markup (CMath)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/cmath/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/cmath/</guid>
      <description>Symbols Arithmetic Basic:
   Plus sign     −	[-]	Minus sign   ×	Multiplication ÷	[d]	Division /	⁄	[/]	Fraction slash  Technical: ±	[+-]	Plus-minus sign ∕	[d/]	Division slash ⋅	[.]	Multiplication or dot product √	[root]	Square root ∛	[3root]	Cube root ∜	[4root]	Fourth root ∞	[inf]	Infinity ∶	[:]	Ratio ∷	[::]	Proportion sum	∑	[sum]	Sum prod	∏	[prod]	Product 𝔼	[expect] Expected value pi	π	[pi]	Mathematical value pi (3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Composable Text Markup Language (CTML)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/ctml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/ctml/</guid>
      <description>CTML is simply an alternate character-level syntax for HTML. It otherwise closes closely to HTML (currently HTML5 in particular), and is designed to be easily convertible both to and from HTML.
The main goal of CTML is to satisfy the CTS metasyntactic discipline, so that CTML can be readily composed with other CTL-compliant languages without escaping. Secondary goals are to be more concise, readable, and easily typeable than HTML, while keeping the syntax simple and readily cross-convertible with HTML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Composable Text Syntax</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/cts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/cts/</guid>
      <description>XXX to be written.
goal: composability. A valid CTs text inserted into another should remain a valid CTS text.
Matched open/close punctuation pairs, which we call matchers.
Basic principle: matchers must match. This dominates all other more specialized syntaxes.
We could define a variant of CTS for any particular set of matchers we want; all the principles would be the same.
But to avoid further confusion, would be best to have one &amp;ldquo;standardized&amp;rdquo; set of matchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decentralized Update Governance (DUG)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/follow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/follow/</guid>
      <description>Orthogonal concepts to be defined independently but worked together:
 identification (e.g., by content hash) of current version linkage of versions into a linear series, SkipChain, or TimeTree update authorization by one or quorum of identities authentication of identities (people or devices) eg by signing registration of updates on authoritative registry or registries  checking of witnesses by threshold   definition of unambiguous authoritative chain by timescale?  &amp;ndash; Version Identifier (VID) scheme:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delimited Text and Binary Syntax</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/delimited-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/delimited-syntax/</guid>
      <description>or Composable Text/Binary Syntax (CTS/CBS)?
Goals:
 Text format self-describing and human-readable Binary format for compactness and efficiency  Either self-describing or schema-dependent   Easy cross-conversion between text and binary formats  Easy for schemas to define both text and binary equivalents at once   Streamable: encoder can start sending long composites before knowing length Embeddable:  for embeddability, see for example JSON Schema&amp;rsquo;s desire to be able to embed arbitrary non-JSON data with a MIME Media Type: https://json-schema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed randomness, drand, and the League of Entropy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/drand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/drand/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The coin to us is sacred.&amp;rdquo; - Thomas Shelby (Peaky Blinders)
 Public randomness – or &amp;ldquo;flipping coins&amp;rdquo; in some way so that anyone can see (and trust) the outcome – is fundamental to numerous social and technical processes. Besides gambling and lotteries (obviously), we need public randomness to choose a sample of some population fairly. The ancient Greeks used sortition, or selection by random lottery, to appoint political officials to office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dresden</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2007/0622-Dresden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2007/0622-Dresden/</guid>
      <description>Dresden June 21-28, 2007  The City   &amp;nbsp; Dresden&#39;s &#34;Little Louvre&#34; Museum   &amp;nbsp;  &amp;nbsp;  The old city (Altstadt)   &amp;nbsp; Odd little artworks lurk in unexpected places   &amp;nbsp;   &amp;nbsp;  After a bit of rain   &amp;nbsp;  Sunset over the Elbe  Hiking near Schmilka (On the Elbe, within sight of the Czech border.)      A climber&#39;s paradise, looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Stream Embedding with Composable Binary Encoding (CBE)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/cbe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/cbe/</guid>
      <description>An old problem in data format design is embedding an arbitrary variable-length byte sequence in a longer one, so that a decoder can tell unambiguously where the embedded string ends. This problem is ubiquitous in the design of machine-readable data formats, which often hierarchically compose large and complex data streams from sequences of nested substrings and strings using simpler encodings. Embedding challenges include encoding and decoding simplicity, keeping space overheads low and predictable for both small and large embedded strings, and allowing for stream processing in which an encoder must start writing an embedded sequence before knowing how long it will be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escaping Escaping Hell with Composable Resource Identifiers</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/cri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/cri/</guid>
      <description>Uniform resource identifiers or URIs were a genuinely great idea and have rightfully become the ubiquitous way to &amp;ldquo;name things&amp;rdquo; on the Internet. As the basis of web addresses or URLs, they are human readable (to varying degrees), manually transcribable, cut-and-pasteable, and have proven incrementally extensible to a vast multitude of schemes. Their later extension to internationalized resource identifiers or IRIs allow people whose native language is not English to type, and view, non-ASCII Unicode characters in web addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eXtensible Syntax Object Notation (XSON)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/xson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/xson/</guid>
      <description>Goals:
 Consistent with and easily convertible to and from JSON Support syntactic and semantic extensions for expressiveness Incremental complexity growth: simple formats and schemas stay simple Baseline even more minimalistic than JSON (&amp;ldquo;minXSON&amp;rdquo;) All elements have both human-readable and compact binary representations  The XSON header An XSON stream starts with xson[imports], where imports is a comma-separated list of syntax imports. These can be simple identifiers for extensions defined in this document, or may (how?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flowers in Lausanne</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2006/0430-Flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2006/0430-Flowers/</guid>
      <description>  Flowers in Lausanne Spring 2006                       </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geneva</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2004/0617-Geneva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2004/0617-Geneva/</guid>
      <description>Geneva June-August 2004  
 

 Walking along Lake Geneva  


 Farther along, at the Botanical Garden  

  


 Landscapes and contemporary art along the Arve  

 A geek trying to get work done in Geneva  



 Paragliders jumping off Mont Sal&amp;egrave;ve  
Someone else getting ready to fly</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JSON Binary Schema</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/jbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/jbs/</guid>
      <description>JBS allows the specification of customized binary representations via extensions to the JSON Schema language.
XXX allow specifying BESO (or CBOR or &amp;hellip;) as a default binary encoding
XXX related: Katai Struct, The Next 700 Data Description Languages, binpac, IDRIS, etc.
Variable-width unsigned integers When the scheme type is integer, an encoding property of unsigned indicates that values greater than or equal to zero are to be encoded in a variable-length binary representation:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lagoon</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Lagoon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Lagoon.html</guid>
      <description>    Lagoon Our latest trip to the world-famous amusement park that attracts millions of people from around the world to Utah each year...&amp;nbsp; (NOT!) Actually, it&#39;s a pretty decent place, and happens to be nearby and not too crowded. &amp;nbsp;        &amp;nbsp;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Louise</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2001/1021-LakeLouise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2001/1021-LakeLouise/</guid>
      <description>Lake Louise October 21, 2001  These pictures are from a day hike I took with others in the PDOS group during the ACM Symposium on Operating System Principles, which was held this year at Chateau Lake Louise in Banff, Canada.   The lake and the Fairmont Chateau   Gettin&#39; a little stormy out there...  Lake Louise from higher up.      Chuck and Benji take time out for a little baseball practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnitudes: When an Integer is Too Precise</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/mag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/mag/</guid>
      <description>Interesting uses:
  Side-channel leak control: PURBs
  Indexing and counting for divide-and-conquer algorithms. Example: binary search (works) vs linear search (breaks quickly); quick/merge sorts (works) vs naive sorts (breaks); &amp;hellip;
  Related: summary data for large-scale data for parallel processing
  Efficient memory allocation with fragmentation control Use next mag to bucket allocation units; allocation can scavenge and split a larger bucket and (proof?) remainder will also fall into a valid bucket (subtraction closure: mag minus a mag is a mag if no underflow)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marseille</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2005/0304-Marseille/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2005/0304-Marseille/</guid>
      <description>  Marseille March 3-5, 2005  
 &amp;nbsp; 
Le Vieux Port  &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 
 
&amp;nbsp; 
Jeu de Boules  
&amp;nbsp


 Eglise St. Victor  &amp;nbsp; 
 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 
The much older crypt below St. Victor La Corniche  
 &amp;nbsp; 
 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 
 
 &amp;nbsp;   
Le Panier  &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;   &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midsummer&#39;s Eve at Zebediah&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2002/0713-MidsummersEve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2002/0713-MidsummersEve/</guid>
      <description>Midsummer&#39;s Eve at Zebediah&#39;s (July 13, 2002)  Our gracious host industriously overseeing the preparations...  Think we&#39;ll have enough firewood?         Zeb is a master at constructing fun toys involving swinging or flying. Here&#39;s his latest: a zip line across his back yard!   The neighborhood folk trio Full Cold Moon treated us to some great music during the afternoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Cats</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Cats.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Cats.html</guid>
      <description>My Cat, Willow          I&amp;nbsp;found Willow at a nearby shelter in February 2001, while I was out helping a friend look for a second cat.&amp;nbsp; My friend loved Willow too, but she&#39;s allergic to long-haired cats - so I&amp;nbsp;decided then and there that I was ready for a companion of my own. :-)&amp;nbsp; Willow is as sweet as she is pretty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opus &#39;99</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Opus99.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Opus99.html</guid>
      <description>My trip to Opus &#39;99  
Five of us drove from Salt Lake City to Longview, Washington, stopping along the way at Multnomah Falls near Portland: from left, myself, Melissa, Jana, Kabe, and Steve. 
&amp;nbsp;  Yeah, we made it!!!   My very special friend Zarrin    &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;  My touch group going on a hike that turned out to be a lot more adventurous than we expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paris</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2005/0801-Paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2005/0801-Paris/</guid>
      <description>  Paris August 1-3, 2005  
Le petit parisien
(Jardin du Palais Royal)  &amp;nbsp; 

&amp;nbsp; 
Rue St. Jacques   
Parc Monceau 
Square Jean XXIII   
Quai d&#39;Anjou 
&amp;nbsp;    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peterhof</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2003/0624-Peterhof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2003/0624-Peterhof/</guid>
      <description>  Peterhof June 24, 2003     &amp;nbsp;    &amp;nbsp;    Marly Pond and Golden Hill Cascade   Hermitage Palace 
Lion Fountain 
Pyramid Fountain   
Sheaf Fountain 
Sun Fountain 
Little Oak Fountain    &amp;nbsp; 
Chessboard Hill Cascade   &amp;nbsp;    &amp;nbsp;  &amp;nbsp;  The Grand Cascade and Samson Fountain   &amp;nbsp;    The Grand Palace and Upper Gardens   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piano</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Piano.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Piano.html</guid>
      <description>   My favorite hobby... &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; (at home) &amp;nbsp; (at church - yeah, that&#39;s a real piano!)   &amp;nbsp;       Alright, does anyone know what the Academy of St. Martin in the Fields is?  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Social Media to Escape the Echo Chamber</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/11/13/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/11/13/info/</guid>
      <description>Hillary Clinton&amp;rsquo;s electoral college defeat has provoked many questions about how so many Americans could have choosen a misogynistic, xenophobic, pathologically lying, authoritarian ideologue as their next President &amp;ndash; and one of many targets of their blame is social media. Compounding its polarizing &amp;ldquo;echo chamber&amp;rdquo; effect, online discussions were tarnished with deliberate misinformation, including incorrect instructions on how to vote. But is the solution for social media companies like Facebook to ``do a better job&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; at curating the world&amp;rsquo;s content to suppress out false or hateful speech?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rome</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2006/1225-Rome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2006/1225-Rome/</guid>
      <description>Rome December 21-26, 2006 &amp;nbsp; In winter, still bathed in the sun...                      Wood-burning in the sun for an artistic ceremony celebrating the centenary of Samuel Beckett &amp;nbsp; A glimpse of ancient times           --  &amp;nbsp; The grandeur of Catholicism              &amp;nbsp; .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rwanda</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Rwanda.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Rwanda.html</guid>
      <description>   Rwanda, 1984-1987 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; At home with my family at the&amp;nbsp; Adventist University of Central Africa (AUCA) &amp;nbsp; Hiking with my best friend Paulo   &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Hiking up to see the gorillas &amp;nbsp; Me (top left) and all the other foreign faculty kids&amp;nbsp; out for a day at the beach at Lake Kivu, Gisenyi    The same gang (mostly) as a Pathfinder group   Our cat, Mimosa &amp;nbsp;     &amp;nbsp;     &amp;nbsp;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saint Petersburg</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2003/0621-StPetersbourg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2003/0621-StPetersbourg/</guid>
      <description>St. Petersburg June 20-27, 2003     &amp;nbsp;  &amp;nbsp;    &amp;nbsp;   Palace Square   &amp;nbsp;   Kazan Cathedral     &amp;nbsp;  &amp;nbsp;   St. Isaac&#39;s Cathedral   &amp;nbsp;  &amp;nbsp;    &amp;nbsp;  &amp;nbsp;  White nights in the channels  
Peter and Paul Fortress 
Atlas holding up the New Hermitage</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South Korea</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2002/1122-Korea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2002/1122-Korea/</guid>
      <description>South Korea (November 22-December 9, 2002) First Weekend: Daegu  Despite my jet lag, we managed to get out and see Donghwasa Temple in Mt. Palgongsan, just north of Daegu.  Home to a huge standing Buddha in a courtyard built into the side of the mountain.  A view from some of the hiking trails on Mt. Palgongsan near the temple. No, Buddhist monks aren&#39;t Nazis. It&#39;s a reverse swastika, so maybe they&#39;re the exact opposite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2002</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2002/0601-Spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2002/0601-Spring/</guid>
      <description>Spring (June 1-8, 2002)  Spring is not just a season, but also a wonderful yearly week-long campout in New Hampshire organized by some friends of mine! I was having too much fun there to remember to take many pictures, but here are a few. There should be more soon at the camp&#39;s official site.   An amusing sight we just had to stop at on the trip up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stata Center</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2004/0601-StataCenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2004/0601-StataCenter/</guid>
      <description>The Stata Center Cambridge, MA - June 2004  This is the year MIT&#39;s new Stata Center, designed by Frank Gehry, was finally finished and ready for our lab (among others) to move into. Old Office  
First, a historical shot of me in our old digs in Tech Square, just before the move (courtesy of my colleague JinYang Li).
Can you tell we&#39;ve been in here a while?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tornado</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Tornado.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Tornado.html</guid>
      <description>&#34;The Great Salt Lake City Tornado of &#39;99&#34; OK, so it was pretty wimpy as far as tornados go compared with those in other areas, but it was sort of a novelty here.&amp;nbsp; Unfortunately, I wasn&#39;t in the area when it hit, so I missed most of the fun; however, I did get in on some of the aftermath on the way home.&amp;nbsp; The tornado passed just to the east of my house, so we didn&#39;t get any damage at all (although our yard did catch a few pieces of some less fortunate houses).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travels</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Travels.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Travels.html</guid>
      <description>Snapshots from some of my other travels...  Snorkeling with Colby in my trusty PocoMan T-shirt during my latest trip to the Bay Islands, April 1998  Taking a rest after climbing the Schilthorn, Switzerland, October 1986  Feeding the swans with Aunt Arlene in Hallstatt, Austria, October 1986 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Nairobi, Kenya, April 1986 &amp;nbsp; Mombasa, Kenya, April 1986   &amp;nbsp;  Our dog Penny patiently tolerates my ceremoniously conferring Dad&#39;s Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip to Hawaii, October 1999</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Hawaii.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Hawaii.html</guid>
      <description>Hawaii How many people are lucky enough to be offered a free trip for two to Hawaii for a couple days of easy work? :-) (Actually, I learned later that those couple days of easy work saved someone $40,000, so I guess maybe it was worth it... :) This was the first trip I&#39;ve been on with my new 48MB flash card for my Kodak DC240 digital camera, and I went berserk!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utah Travels</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Utah.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Utah.html</guid>
      <description>    Travels in and around Utah &amp;nbsp;  &amp;nbsp; The whole family in Southern Utah&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; OK, Mom, just take the picture!!!&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Colby&#39;s way of playing &#39;possum...&amp;nbsp;   &amp;nbsp;  &amp;nbsp; Sunny in a cave with Michael and Monty&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Me, Sunny, Colby, and his pal... (can you find him?)&amp;nbsp;    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venice</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2004/0116-Venice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2004/0116-Venice/</guid>
      <description>Venice  (January 13-23, 2004) The Official Excuse ... er, Reason I was presenting a paper at Principles of Programming Languages 2004, a programming language theory conference.    It&#39;s not too often that I get to go to a conference in such a place! Here&#39;s the conference croud, geeking away under centuries-old Italian frescoes in the Auditorium Santa Margherita, Dorsoduro.     I stayed at Palazzo Zenobio, an old Armenian palace near the auditorium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vermont</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2001/0506-Vermont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2001/0506-Vermont/</guid>
      <description>Vermont May 6, 2001  A quick Sunday road trip with my friend Zarrin to see a few historic sites in New England. Old Bennington, Vermont  The Old First Church in Old Bennington...    ...where William Ellery Channing died and where Robert Frost is buried. Covered Bridges  We hunted down three of the classic covered bridges in Vermont.  Silk Road Bridge  Henry Bridge  Paper Mill Bridge</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vienna</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2004/0626-Vienna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2004/0626-Vienna/</guid>
      <description>Vienna June 2004  


  

 Wien, Wein, und Gesang  
Bespectacled Renaissance Backgammon Cow 
Franz-Hochedlingergasse   
Tramwaychik! 
Garden at the Hundertwasser House   Belvedere  
&#34;Last year at Belvedere&#34;  

 Smiling ladies  

  Wienerwald  

 On a wine-tasting trip to a Heurigen outside the city  Vienna Nights</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Villars, Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2006/0119-Villars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2006/0119-Villars/</guid>
      <description>  Villars, Switzerland January 2006                 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIPcode: Encoding and Decoding Structured Data with Verifiable Interface Presentations (VIPs)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/vipcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/vipcode/</guid>
      <description>In this post I would like to introduce VIPcode, a library that encodes and decodes structured data specified by verifiable interface presentations or VIPs in the Go language. In brief, VIPs are presentations or mappings of an abstract wire-format interface into the concrete data types of a specific target language (in this case Go). While embodying all information needed to marshal and unmarshall complex data, VIPs may also be verified automatically for compliance with a language-neutral interface specification, such as a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XTAX: an Extensible Sytntax Metalanguage</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/xtax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/xtax/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>