<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Smart Contracts on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Smart-Contracts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Smart Contracts on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Smart-Contracts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ZeroAuction: Zero-Deposit Sealed-bid Auction via Delayed Execution</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/zeroauction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/zeroauction/</guid>
      <description>Haoqian Zhang, Michelle Yeo, Vero Estrada-Galinanes, and Bryan Ford 8th Workshop on Trusted Smart Contracts (WTSC) March 8, 2024 Abstract: Auctions, a long-standing method of trading goods and services, are a promising use case for decentralized finance. However, due to the inherent transparency property of blockchains, current sealed-bid auction implementations on smart contracts requires a bidder to send at least two transactions to the underlying blockchain: a bidder must first commit their bid in the first transaction during the bidding period and reveal their bid in the second transaction once the revealing period starts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards General-Purpose Decentralized Computing with Permissionless Extensibility</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2024-alp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2024-alp/</guid>
      <description>Enis Ceyhun Alp Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford January 19, 2024 Abstract: Smart contracts have emerged as the most promising foundations for applications of the blockchain technology. Even though smart contracts are expected to serve as the backbone of the next-generation web, they have several limitations that hinder their widespread adoption, namely limited computational functionality, restricted programmability, and lack of data confidentiality. Moreover, addressing these challenges manually in application-specific ways requires a lot of developer effort and time due to the monolithic architecture of smart contracts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flash Freezing Flash Boys: Countering Blockchain Front-Running</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/f3b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/f3b/</guid>
      <description>Haoqian Zhang, Louis-Henri Merino, Vero Estrada-Galiñanes, and Bryan Ford Decentralized Internet, Networks, Protocols, and Systems (DINPS)
Bologna, Italy &amp;ndash; July 10, 2022 Abstract: Front-running, the practice of benefiting from advanced knowledge of pending transactions, has proliferated in the cryptocurrency space with the emergence of decentralized finance. Front-running causes devastating losses to honest participants—estimated at $280M each month—and endangers the fairness of the ecosystem. We present Flash Freezing Flash Boys (F3B), an architecture to address front-running attacks by relying on a commit-and-reveal scheme where the contents of a transaction are encrypted and later revealed by a decentralized secret-management committee (SMC) when the transaction has been committed by the underlying consensus layer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking General-Purpose Decentralized Computing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/protean-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/protean-abs/</guid>
      <description>Enis Ceyhun Alp, Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Georgia Fragkouli, and Bryan Ford EPFL - IC - DEDIS 17th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS XVII)
May 12-15, 2019. Abstract: While showing great promise, smart contracts are difficult to program correctly, as they need a deep understanding of cryptography and distributed algorithms, and offer limited functionality, as they have to be deterministic and cannot operate on secret data. In this paper we present Protean, a general-purpose decentralized computing platform that addresses these limitations by moving from a monolithic execution model, where all participating nodes store all the state and execute every computation, to a modular execution model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
