<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Privacy on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Privacy on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Identity and Personhood in Digital Democracy: Evaluating Inclusion, Equality, Security, and Privacy in Pseudonym Parties and Other Proofs of Personhood</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/personhood/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford  November 2020 (first draft)  preprint
 Abstract: Digital identity seems at first like a prerequisite for digital democracy: how can we ensure &amp;ldquo;one person, one vote&amp;rdquo; online without identifying voters? But the full gamut of digital identity solutions &amp;ndash; e.g., online ID checking, biometrics, self-sovereign identity, and social/trust networks &amp;ndash; all present severe flaws in security, privacy, and transparency, leaving users vulnerable to exclusion, identity loss or theft, and coercion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design choices for Central Bank Digital Currency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cbdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cbdc/</guid>
      <description>Sarah Allen, Srdjan Capkun, Ittay Eyal, Giulia Fanti, Bryan Ford, James Grimmelmann, Ari Juels, Kari Kostiainen, Sarah Meiklejohn, Andrew Miller, Eswar Prasad, Karl Wüst, and Fan Zhang   Global Economy &amp; Development Working Paper 140,
Brookings Institution,
July 23, 2020. Abstract:  Central banks around the world are exploring and in some cases even piloting central bank digital currencies (CBDCs). CBDCs promise to realize a broad range of new capabilities, including direct government disbursements to citizens, frictionless consumer payment and money-transfer systems, and a range of new financial instruments and monetary policy levers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PriFi: Low-Latency Anonymity for Organizational Networks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/prifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/prifi/</guid>
      <description>Ludovic Barman, Italo Dacosta, Mahdi Zamani, Ennan Zhai, Apostolos Pyrgelis, Bryan Ford, Jean-Pierre Hubaux, and Joan Feigenbaum   Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium
July 13, 2020  Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
Volume 2020, Issue 4.  Abstract: Organizational networks are vulnerable to traffic-analysis attacks that enable adversaries to infer sensitive information from the network traffic &amp;ndash; even if encryption is used. Typical anonymous communication networks are tailored to the Internet and are poorly suited for organizational networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technologizing Democracy or Democratizing Technology? A Layered-Architecture Perspective on Potentials and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Draft &amp;ndash; June 4, 2020
Final version to appear in forthcoming book Digital Technology and Democratic Theory by Lucy Bernholz, Hélène Landemore, and Rob Reich (editors) published by the University of Chicago Press
 Abstract While technology is often claimed to be “democratizing”, the technologizing of society has more often yielded undemocratic or even anti-democratic outcomes. Is technology fundamentally at odds with democracy, or is it merely a rich and infinitely-adaptable toolbox that we’re using the wrong way?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure, Confidential Blockchains Providing High Throughput and Low Latency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2019-kokoris-kogias/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2019-kokoris-kogias/</guid>
      <description>Eleftherios Kokoris Kogias  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
September 27, 2019  Abstract:  One of the core promises of blockchain technology is that of enabling trustworthy data dissemination in a trustless environment. What current blockchain systems deliver, however, is slow dissemination of public data, rendering blockchain technology unusable in settings where latency, transaction capacity or data confidentiality is important. In this thesis, we focus on providing solutions on two of the most pressing problems blockchain technology currently faces: scalability and data confidentiality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Metadata Leakage from Encrypted Files and Communication with PURBs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/purb-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/purb-abs/</guid>
      <description>Kirill Nikitin, Ludovic Barman, Wouter Lueks, Matthew Underwood, Jean-Pierre Hubaux and Bryan Ford EPFL - IC - DEDIS   Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium
July 2019.  Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
Volume 2019, Issue 4.  Abstract: Most encrypted data formats leak metadata via their plaintext headers, such as format version, encryption schemes used, number of recipients who can decrypt the data, and even the recipients’ identities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MorphIT: Morphing Packet Reports for Internet Transparency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/morphit-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/morphit-abs/</guid>
      <description>Georgia Fragkouli, Katerina Argyraki, and Bryan Ford EPFL   Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
May 4, 2019.  Abstract: Can we improve Internet transparency without worsening user anonymity? For a long time, researchers have been proposing transparency systems, where traffic reports produced at strategic network points help assess network behavior and verify service-level agreements or neutrality compliance. However, such reports necessarily reveal when certain traffic appeared at a certain network point, and this information could, in principle, be used to compromise low-latency anonymity networks like Tor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Priorities: Should Identity Systems Divide or Unite People?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/02/08/identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/02/08/identity/</guid>
      <description>Note: this is a brief, rough, first-draft sketch of a longer paper paper I intend to flesh out further in the near future.
The problem of identity has become a hot topic, with the idea of self-sovereign identity in particular attracting significant excitement. The essence of the idea, in short, is to put users in charge of how their identities and personal data are used. Self-sovereign identity posits that users should decide how much and what aspects of their identities to disclose in any situation, and should know and have control over what that information is used for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So They&#39;re Selling You a Blockchain</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2018/09/11/blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2018/09/11/blockchain/</guid>
      <description>Blockchain is certainly one of the hot technology topics today. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s probably in part a hype bubble – but from my perspective as a long-time researcher in decentralized systems I believe there is also a lot of potential value in the concept, which is why my DEDIS lab at EPFL has been investing years of effort in building next generation blockchain architectures. I also believe the value of the blockchain concept is relatively independent of the unpredictable and scam-riddled &amp;lt;a href=&amp;ldquo;https://blockonomi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MedCo: Enabling Secure and Privacy-Conscious Exploration of Distributed Clinical and Genomic Data</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/medco-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/medco-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jean Louis Raisaro, Juan Ram&amp;oacute;n Troncoso-Pastoriza, Micka&amp;euml;l Misbach, Jo&amp;atilde;o S&amp;aacute; Sousa, Sylvain Pradervand, Edoardo Missiaglia, Olivier Michielin, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux   IEEE/ACM Transactions on Computational Biology and Bioinformatics,
July 13, 2018. Abstract: The increasing number of health-data breaches is creating a complicated environment for medical-data sharing and, consequently, for medical progress. Therefore, the development of new solutions that can reassure clinical sites by enabling privacy-preserving sharing of sensitive medical data in compliance with stringent regulations (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Enforcing the Digital Immunity of a Large Humanitarian Organization</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/immunity-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/immunity-abs/</guid>
      <description>Stevens Le Blond, Alejandro Cuevas, Juan Ram&amp;oacute;n Troncoso-Pastoriza, Philipp Jovanovic, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux
EPFL  Distinguished Paper Award   IEEE Security &amp; Privacy (IEEE S&amp;P)
May 22, 2018 Abstract: Humanitarian action, the process of aiding individuals in situations of crises, poses unique information-security challenges due to natural or manmade disasters, the adverse environments in which it takes place, and the scale and multidisciplinary nature of the problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verifiable Management of Private Data under Byzantine Failures</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/calypso/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/calypso/</guid>
      <description>Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Enis Ceyhun Alp, Linus Gasser, Philipp Jovanovic, Ewa Syta, and Bryan Ford   Cryptology ePrint Archive
February 21, 2018  Abstract: Distributed ledger technologies provide high availability and integrity, making them a key enabler for practical and secure computation of distributed workloads among mutually distrustful parties. However, many practical applications also require confidentiality, the third pillar of the CIA triad. In this work, we enhance permissioned and permissionless blockchains with the ability to manage confidential data without forfeiting availability or decentralization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom: Horizontally Scaling Strong Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/atom-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/atom-abs/</guid>
      <description>Albert Kwon
MIT  Henry Corrigan-Gibbs
Stanford  Srinivas Devadas
MIT  Bryan Ford
EPFL    26th ACM Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP)
October 30, 2017 Abstract: Atom is an anonymous messaging system that protects against traffic-analysis attacks. Unlike many prior systems, each Atom server touches only a small fraction of the total messages routed through the network. As a result, the system’s capacity scales near-linearly with the number of servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UnLynx: A Decentralized System for Privacy-Conscious Data Sharing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/unlynx-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/unlynx-abs/</guid>
      <description>David Froelicher, Patricia Egger, Jo&amp;atilde;o S&amp;aacute; Sousa, Jean Louis Raisaro, Zhicong Huang, Christian Mouchet, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux   Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium (PETS)
July 19, 2017 Abstract: Current solutions for privacy-preserving data sharing among multiple parties either depend on a centralized authority that must be trusted and provides only weakest-link security (e.g., the entity that manages private/secret cryptographic keys), or leverage on decentralized but impractical approaches (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Governs Us. Will it Govern Us Well?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2017/06/23/turing50/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2017/06/23/turing50/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is a transcript of my opening remarks on the panel &#34;Restoring Personal Privacy without Compromising National Security&#34; at the 50 Years of the ACM Turing Award Celebration.   We now live in a world in which the rules coded into the technology we use plays as important a role in governing our lives as the formal laws written in the public law books. Code is law already, for better or worse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof-of-Personhood: Redemocratizing Permissionless Cryptocurrencies</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</guid>
      <description>Maria Borge, Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Philipp Jovanovic, Linus Gasser, Nicolas Gailly, and Bryan Ford
EPFL   IEEE Security &amp; Privacy on the Blockchain (IEEE S&amp;B)
April 29, 2017 Abstract: Permissionless blockchain-based cryptocurrencies commonly use proof-of-work (PoW) or proof-of-stake (PoS) to ensure their security, e.g. to prevent double spending attacks. However, both approaches have disadvantages: PoW leads to massive amounts of wasted electricity and re-centralization, whereas major stakeholders in PoS might be able to create a monopoly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Objectives of Lawful-Surveillance Protocols</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/lawful-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/lawful-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-Preserving Lawful Contact Chaining</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/contact-chaining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/contact-chaining/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riffle: An Efficient Communication System With Strong Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/riffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/riffle/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open, privacy-preserving protocols for lawful surveillance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/open-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/open-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AnonRep: Towards Tracking-Resistant Anonymous Reputation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Privacy-Preserving Cryptographic Credentials from Federated Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book-codaspy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book-codaspy/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metadata Protection Considerations for TLS Present and Future</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/tlsmeta-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/tlsmeta-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
EPFL   TLS 1.3 Ready or Not (TRON) Workshop
February 21, 2016 Abstract: TLS 1.3 takes important steps to improve both performance and security, so far offers little protection against traffic analysis or fingerprinting using unencrypted metadata or other side-channels such as transmission lengths and timings. This paper explores metadata protection mechanisms for TLS, including already-included provisions (e.g., record padding), provisions not yet included but potentially feasible in TLS 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s verify real people, not real names.</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2015/10/07/names.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2015/10/07/names.html</guid>
      <description>On Monday the EFF, together with a &amp;ldquo;Nameless Coalition&amp;rdquo; of like-minded groups, escalated the backlash against Facebook&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;real names&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;authentic identities&amp;rdquo; policy with an open letter urging Facebook to end this policy like Google Plus did last year. Facebook&amp;rsquo;s response cites concerns about pseudonyms helping to hide &amp;ldquo;terrorist organizations&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;school bullies&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;criminal behavior.&amp;rdquo;
While I support anonymity and have spent years working to strengthen it, terrorist fearmongering aside, Facebook is right that anonymity is often abused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Anonymity in an Internet Panopticon</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/panopticon-cacm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/panopticon-cacm/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Flexible Architecture for Structural Reliability Auditing to the Clouds</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-zhai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-zhai/</guid>
      <description>Ennan Zhai  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
August 11, 2015  Abstract:  Today’s cloud computing systems pervasively rely on redundancy techniques to enhance reliability and availability. In complex multi-layered hardware/software stacks, however, seemingly independent components used redundantly might share deep, hidden dependencies. These common dependencies may potentially result in unexpected correlated failures, thus undermining redundancy efforts.  Heading off correlated failures is extremely challenging in cloud-scale systems for the following three reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identity Management through Privacy-Preserving Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-syta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-syta/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
August 11, 2015  Abstract:  Maintaining privacy on the Internet is increasingly difficult in this ever-connected world. In most cases, our online interactions are a highly personalized experience and require some form of identity verification, most commonly, logging into an account. Unfortunately, people frequently give away a lot of information while obtaining accounts, reuse usernames and passwords across different services, or link their accounts to take advantage of single sign-on to avoid retyping passwords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Eyes: Secure Remote Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta, Michael J. Fischer, David Wolinsky, Abraham Silberschatz, Gina Gallegos-García, and Bryan Ford   12th International Conference on Security and Cryptography (SECRYPT)
July 2015.  Abstract: We propose an efficient remote biometric authentication protocol that gives strong protection to the user’s biometric data in case of two common kinds of security breaches: (1) loss or theft of the user’s token (smart card, handheld device, etc.), giving the attacker full access to any secrets embedded within it; (2) total penetration of the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Privacy-Preserving Cryptographic Credentials from Federated Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-maheswaran/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-maheswaran/</guid>
      <description>John Maheswaran  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
June 24, 2015  Abstract:  Third-party applications such as Quora or StackOverflow allow users to log in through a federated identity provider such as Facebook (Log in with Facebook), Google+ or Twitter. This process is called federated authentication. Examples of federated identity providers include social networks as well as other non-social network identity providers such as PayPal.  Federated identity providers have gained widespread popularity among users as a way to manage their online identity across the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/post/2014-10-22-open-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/post/2014-10-22-open-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heading Off Correlated Failures through Independence-as-a-Service</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-indaas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-indaas/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching Bandits and Only Bandits: Privacy-Preserving Intersection Warrants for Lawful Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/bandits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/bandits/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing NymBoxes for Identity and Tracking Protection</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/nymboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/nymboxes/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Analysis of Accountable Anonymity in Dissent</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-analysis/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A TorPath to TorCoin: Proof-of-Bandwidth Altcoins for Compensating Relays</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/torcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/torcoin/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Onions to Shallots: Rewarding Tor Relays with TEARS</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/onions-to-shallots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/onions-to-shallots/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crypto-Book: An Architecture for Privacy Preserving Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Cloud Audits that Protect Private Information</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-psra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-psra/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conscript Your Friends into Larger Anonymity Sets with JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/conscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/conscript/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring High-Quality Randomness in Cryptographic Key Generation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/randomness-keygen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/randomness-keygen/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hang With Your Buddies to Resist Intersection Attacks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/buddies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/buddies/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Untold Story of Redundant Clouds: Making Your Service Deployment Truly Reliable</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/irec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/irec/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proactively Accountable Anonymous Messaging in Verdict</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/verdict/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/verdict/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Latency in Tor Circuits with Unordered Delivery</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/tor-unordered/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/tor-unordered/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the World of Human Rights: Please Make Yourself Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/human-rights-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/human-rights-abs/</guid>
      <description>   Henry Corrigan-Gibbs and Bryan Ford Yale University   Cyber-security Research Ethics Dialog &amp; Strategy Workshop (CREDS 2013)
May 23, 2013  Abstract: We draw an ethical analogy between Internet freedom efforts and humanitarian aid work. This parallel motivates a number of ethical questions relating to anonymity and censorship-circumvention research. Paper: PDF  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissent in Numbers: Making Strong Anonymity Scale</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-in-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-in-numbers/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scavenging for Anonymity with BlogDrop</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/blogdrop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/blogdrop/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Theft-Proof Privacy-Preserving Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faceless: Decentralized Anonymous Group Messaging for Online Social Networks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/faceless-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/faceless-abs/</guid>
      <description>Xiaoxiao Song, David Isaac Wolinsky, and Bryan Ford Yale University   5th Workshop on Social Network Systems
April 10, 2012  Abstract: Social networks (SNs) enable physically distributed groups to communicate seamlessly. Unfortunately such communi- cation can be easily mined by adversaries in attempts to breach users’ privacy or suppress open discussion on sensi- tive topics. While anonymous posting can help protect users by hiding the link between individuals and the messages they post, existing anonymization schemes are centralized or vul- nerable to well-known attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Anonymous Group Communication in the Anytrust Model</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/anytrust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/anytrust/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissent: Accountable Anonymous Group Messaging</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/dissent-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/dissent-abs/</guid>
      <description>Henry Corrigan-Gibbs and Bryan Ford
	Yale University  To appear in 17th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS 2010) October 4-8, 2010, Chicago, IL, USA Abstract:  Users often wish to participate in online groups anonymously, but misbehaving users may abuse this anonymity to disrupt the group&#39;s communication. Existing messaging protocols such as DC-nets leave groups vulnerable to denial-of-service and Sybil attacks, Mix-nets are difficult to protect against traffic analysis, and accountable voting protocols are unsuited to general anonymous messaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Offline Foundation for Online Accountable Pseudonyms</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Jacob Strauss 
Massachusetts Institute of Technology First Workshop on Social Network Systems
April 1, 2008 Abstract:  Online anonymity often appears to undermine accountability, offering little incentive for civil behavior, but accountability failures usually result not from anonymity itself but from the disposability of virtual identities. A user banned for misbehavior&amp;mdash;e.g., spamming from a free E-mail account or stuffing an online ballot box&amp;mdash;can simply open other accounts or connect from other IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sybil Parties: An Offline Foundation for Online Accountability</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/log/2006/0924-SybilParties.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/log/2006/0924-SybilParties.html</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford - September 24, 2006 Preliminary draft: see here for the final published paper  The Human Recognition Problem  Today&#39;s online ecosphere continually suffers from its inability to tell who is a genuine, unique human and who isn&#39;t. Because open-access messaging systems cannot isolate or authenticate the human source of messages for the purpose of suppressing abuses, spam has already relegated USENET to historical obscurity [Templeton01], threatens the usability of E-mail [Wouters05], and is even advancing on Skype.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
