<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Storage on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Storage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Storage on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Strongly-Consistent Systems Resilient to Failures, Partitions, and Slowdowns</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2022-basescu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2022-basescu/</guid>
      <description>Cristina Băsescu Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
November 30, 2022 Abstract: Distributed systems designers typically strive to improve performance and preserve availability despite failures or attacks; but, when strong consistency is also needed, they encounter fundamental limitations. The bottleneck is in replica coordination, which is impacted by partitions and slowdowns that can occur anywhere. We believe the present ecosystem fails to recognize that not all failures and partitions are supposed to be equal — at least from a user-centric performance and availability standpoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPUfs: The Case for Operating System Services on GPUs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/gpufs-cacm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/gpufs-cacm/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPUfs: Integrating a File System with GPUs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/gpufs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/gpufs/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Device Transparency: a New Model for Mobile Storage</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/devtransp-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/devtransp-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jacob Strauss
Chris Lesniewski-Laas
Justin Mazzola Paluska
Bryan Ford
Robert Morris
Frans Kaashoek
Published in SOSP Workshop on Hot Topics in Storage and File Systems (HotStorage &#39;09) October 11, 2009, Big Sky, MT, USA Abstract: This paper proposes a new storage model, device transparency, in which users view and manage their entire data collection from any of their devices, even from disconnected storage-limited devices holding only a subset of the entire collection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VXA: A Virtual Architecture for Durable Compressed Archives</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/vxa-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/vxa-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Massachusetts Institute of Technology 4th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies (FAST &#39;05)
December 16, 2005, San Francisco, California, USA. Abstract: Data compression algorithms change frequently, and obsolete decoders do not always run on new hardware and operating systems, threatening the long-term usability of content archived using those algorithms. Re-encoding content into new formats is cumbersome, and highly undesirable when lossy compression is involved. Processor architectures, in contrast, have remained comparatively stable over recent decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cache Directory Tagging Specification</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/cachedir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/cachedir/</guid>
      <description>Version 0.6 (Changes) Proposed by Bryan Ford Abstract Many applications create and manage directories containing cached information about content stored elsewhere, such as cached Web content or thumbnail-size versions of images or movies. For speed and storage efficiency we would often like to avoid backing up, archiving, or otherwise unnecessarily copying such directories around, but it is a pain to identify and individually exclude each such directory during data transfer operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Duality - Vitalizing the Commons</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2003/07/24/service-duality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2003/07/24/service-duality/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
