<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bryan&#39;s Photo Album on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/album/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bryan&#39;s Photo Album on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bford.info/album/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aachen</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2005/0717-Aachen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2005/0717-Aachen/</guid>
      <description> Aachen (Aix-la-Chapelle) July 17, 2005 &amp;nbsp; From the quiet and privincial side streets of Aachen... &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; ...you wouldn&#39;t know that it was the capital of the Holy Roman Empire. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Inside Charlemagne&#39;s cathedral &amp;nbsp; The remains of Charlemagne&#39;s palace with the Rathaus glued onto it and the local pub nestled in the middle. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Angels and devils live side by side on the walls. &amp;nbsp; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antelope Island</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/AntelopeIsland.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/AntelopeIsland.html</guid>
      <description> Antelope Island No, I have no idea what it was... The Attack (yeah - she started it!!!) The Duel... The Reconciliation </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avignon</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2005/0305-Avignon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2005/0305-Avignon/</guid>
      <description> Avignon March 5, 2005 &amp;nbsp; Place de l&#39;Horloge &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Place du Palais &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Rocher de Doms &amp;nbsp; Pont Saint B&amp;eacute;nezet &amp;nbsp; Rue des Teinturiers </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bar Harbor, Maine</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2002/0527-BarHarbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2002/0527-BarHarbor/</guid>
      <description>Bar Harbor, Maine (Memorial Day Weekend, May 24-27, 2002) A hazy view of Bar Harbor from the top of Mount Desert. (Yep, that&#39;s really its name.) A lovely day at the beach. And lo, the prophet Zebadia went down to the sea, and he spake unto the multitudes, saying... Seek, and ye shall find; but beware the curious onlooker... ...for she may attack without warning; yea, even flirt! Well, it&#39;s not quite Hawaii, but hey, they&#39;ve got lobsters!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barcelona</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2003/0527-Barcelona/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2003/0527-Barcelona/</guid>
      <description>Barcelona May 2003 My colleague Athicha and I spent a week early in the summer exploring Barcelona and other nearby attractions in Catalonia, Spain. Walking the narrow streets Barcelona&#39;s version of the Arc de Triomphe
(every European city&#39;s gotta have one) Getting trampled by a thundering herd of green-capped kids A perfectly ordinary building...
with flaming torches at night One of the famous Gaud&amp;iacute; buildings A presumably not-so-famous famous &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2005/0820-Berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2005/0820-Berlin/</guid>
      <description>Berlin August 19-22, 2005 Potsdamer Platz The Sony Center
(Helmut Jahn, 1996-2000) The Berlin Philharmonic in Kulturforum Friedrichstrasse The job of a checkpoint guard
just ain&#39;t what it used to be. Just garbage.
&amp;nbsp; Brides&#39; Day Out on Gendarmenmarkt Inside Galeries Lafayette
(Jean Nouvel, 1993-96) Berlin Mitte The Reichstag overlooking the Tiergarten.
(Original by Paul Wallot, 1884-94; renovations by Norman Foster, 1994-99) Marie-Elisabeth-L&amp;uuml;ders-Haus on the River Spree (Stephan Braunfels, 1998-2004)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonn</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2005/0709-Bonn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2005/0709-Bonn/</guid>
      <description> Bonn July 9, 2005 The Botanical Garden &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Rheinaue Freizeitpark This metal ball is actually a giant merry-go-round that can be rotated manually and even ridden. The kid was fascinated. &amp;nbsp; Blindengarten &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Nightlife &amp;nbsp; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bryan&#39;s Family</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Family.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Family.html</guid>
      <description> Bryan&#39;s Family My father, Robert E. Ford&amp;nbsp; My mother Karen My little brother Colby&amp;nbsp; The family cat, Carmen San Diego,&amp;nbsp; in her natural furball state.&amp;nbsp; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bryan&#39;s Home in Cambridge</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Home.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Home.html</guid>
      <description>Bryan&#39;s Home I&#39;m now a proud first-time homeowner of a wee little place in Cambridge, Massachusetts! It&#39;s the second-floor condo in this cute old-style building near Inman Square: Of course, indoor shots in a small place are really difficult without a good wide-angle lens, which I don&#39;t have unfortunately, but here are a couple pitiful attempts anyway... The Living Room.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s my dad on the futon. The Kitchen.&amp;nbsp; Yep, that&#39;s a piano on the right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cologne</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2005/0723-Cologne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2005/0723-Cologne/</guid>
      <description>K&amp;ouml;ln (Cologne, Germany - July 23, 2005) Soap bubbles in front of the cathedral! There was absolutely no one to be found in St. Maria-im-Kapitol. The locals seem to have a Lace Curtain Competition running... but this is where we actually found them. In the Rheingarten. &amp;nbsp; Watching the trains from K&amp;ouml;ln&#39;s Gothic cathedral. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Looking up and down. The Rathaus and its guardians. It was getting late... but the bubbles were still there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dresden</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2007/0622-Dresden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2007/0622-Dresden/</guid>
      <description>Dresden June 21-28, 2007 The City &amp;nbsp; Dresden&#39;s &#34;Little Louvre&#34; Museum &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The old city (Altstadt) &amp;nbsp; Odd little artworks lurk in unexpected places &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; After a bit of rain &amp;nbsp; Sunset over the Elbe Hiking near Schmilka (On the Elbe, within sight of the Czech border.) A climber&#39;s paradise, looks like. Everything alive. TU-Dresden The fantastic, audaciously colored new computer science building at Technische Universit&amp;auml;t Dresden,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flowers in Lausanne</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2006/0430-Flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2006/0430-Flowers/</guid>
      <description> Flowers in Lausanne Spring 2006 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geneva</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2004/0617-Geneva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2004/0617-Geneva/</guid>
      <description> Geneva June-August 2004 Walking along Lake Geneva Farther along, at the Botanical Garden Landscapes and contemporary art along the Arve A geek trying to get work done in Geneva Paragliders jumping off Mont Sal&amp;egrave;ve Someone else getting ready to fly &amp;nbsp; Waiting for Mme de Quevedo Our last supper together </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lagoon</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Lagoon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Lagoon.html</guid>
      <description> Lagoon Our latest trip to the world-famous amusement park that attracts millions of people from around the world to Utah each year...&amp;nbsp; (NOT!) Actually, it&#39;s a pretty decent place, and happens to be nearby and not too crowded. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake Louise</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2001/1021-LakeLouise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2001/1021-LakeLouise/</guid>
      <description>Lake Louise October 21, 2001 These pictures are from a day hike I took with others in the PDOS group during the ACM Symposium on Operating System Principles, which was held this year at Chateau Lake Louise in Banff, Canada. The lake and the Fairmont Chateau Gettin&#39; a little stormy out there... Lake Louise from higher up. Chuck and Benji take time out for a little baseball practice. The view from midway up the trail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marseille</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2005/0304-Marseille/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2005/0304-Marseille/</guid>
      <description> Marseille March 3-5, 2005 &amp;nbsp; Le Vieux Port &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Jeu de Boules &amp;nbsp
Eglise St. Victor &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The much older crypt below St. Victor La Corniche &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Le Panier &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midsummer&#39;s Eve at Zebediah&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2002/0713-MidsummersEve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2002/0713-MidsummersEve/</guid>
      <description>Midsummer&#39;s Eve at Zebediah&#39;s (July 13, 2002) Our gracious host industriously overseeing the preparations... Think we&#39;ll have enough firewood? Zeb is a master at constructing fun toys involving swinging or flying. Here&#39;s his latest: a zip line across his back yard! The neighborhood folk trio Full Cold Moon treated us to some great music during the afternoon. One of those rare occasions when I feel almost conservative in comparison with others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Cats</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Cats.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Cats.html</guid>
      <description>My Cat, Willow I&amp;nbsp;found Willow at a nearby shelter in February 2001, while I was out helping a friend look for a second cat.&amp;nbsp; My friend loved Willow too, but she&#39;s allergic to long-haired cats - so I&amp;nbsp;decided then and there that I was ready for a companion of my own. :-)&amp;nbsp; Willow is as sweet as she is pretty. My Family&#39;s Cat, Carmen San Diego So named by Colby because when we first got her as a kitten she would constantly hide out in the most unimaginable places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opus &#39;99</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Opus99.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Opus99.html</guid>
      <description>My trip to Opus &#39;99 Five of us drove from Salt Lake City to Longview, Washington, stopping along the way at Multnomah Falls near Portland: from left, myself, Melissa, Jana, Kabe, and Steve. &amp;nbsp; Yeah, we made it!!! My very special friend Zarrin &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; My touch group going on a hike that turned out to be a lot more adventurous than we expected... Emmie, Elisha, Al, Zarrin, Jeff, Candace, and David.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paris</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2005/0801-Paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2005/0801-Paris/</guid>
      <description> Paris August 1-3, 2005 Le petit parisien
(Jardin du Palais Royal) &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Rue St. Jacques Parc Monceau Square Jean XXIII Quai d&#39;Anjou &amp;nbsp; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peterhof</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2003/0624-Peterhof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2003/0624-Peterhof/</guid>
      <description> Peterhof June 24, 2003 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Marly Pond and Golden Hill Cascade Hermitage Palace Lion Fountain Pyramid Fountain Sheaf Fountain Sun Fountain Little Oak Fountain &amp;nbsp; Chessboard Hill Cascade &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The Grand Cascade and Samson Fountain &amp;nbsp; The Grand Palace and Upper Gardens </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piano</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Piano.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Piano.html</guid>
      <description> My favorite hobby... &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; (at home) &amp;nbsp; (at church - yeah, that&#39;s a real piano!) &amp;nbsp; Alright, does anyone know what the Academy of St. Martin in the Fields is? </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rome</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2006/1225-Rome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2006/1225-Rome/</guid>
      <description>Rome December 21-26, 2006 &amp;nbsp; In winter, still bathed in the sun... Wood-burning in the sun for an artistic ceremony celebrating the centenary of Samuel Beckett &amp;nbsp; A glimpse of ancient times &amp;nbsp; The grandeur of Catholicism &amp;nbsp; ...and its mystery &amp;nbsp; Over 2000 years of art expressed in marble &amp;nbsp; Italian pine trees, rivaling the architecture in elegance &amp;nbsp; Walking the streets in daylight... &amp;nbsp; ...at sunset... &amp;nbsp; .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rwanda</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Rwanda.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Rwanda.html</guid>
      <description> Rwanda, 1984-1987 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; At home with my family at the&amp;nbsp; Adventist University of Central Africa (AUCA) &amp;nbsp; Hiking with my best friend Paulo &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Hiking up to see the gorillas &amp;nbsp; Me (top left) and all the other foreign faculty kids&amp;nbsp; out for a day at the beach at Lake Kivu, Gisenyi The same gang (mostly) as a Pathfinder group Our cat, Mimosa &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saint Petersburg</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2003/0621-StPetersbourg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2003/0621-StPetersbourg/</guid>
      <description>St. Petersburg June 20-27, 2003 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Palace Square &amp;nbsp; Kazan Cathedral &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; St. Isaac&#39;s Cathedral &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; White nights in the channels Peter and Paul Fortress Atlas holding up the New Hermitage The Strelka of Vasilievsky Island The Bronze Horseman Along the banks of the Neva &amp;nbsp; Lilacs in the Field of Mars
&amp;nbsp; Church of Our Savior on Spilled Blood
(!!!) On and off Nevsky Prospekt Little Holland St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South Korea</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2002/1122-Korea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2002/1122-Korea/</guid>
      <description>South Korea (November 22-December 9, 2002) First Weekend: Daegu Despite my jet lag, we managed to get out and see Donghwasa Temple in Mt. Palgongsan, just north of Daegu. Home to a huge standing Buddha in a courtyard built into the side of the mountain. A view from some of the hiking trails on Mt. Palgongsan near the temple. No, Buddhist monks aren&#39;t Nazis. It&#39;s a reverse swastika, so maybe they&#39;re the exact opposite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2002</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2002/0601-Spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2002/0601-Spring/</guid>
      <description>Spring (June 1-8, 2002) Spring is not just a season, but also a wonderful yearly week-long campout in New Hampshire organized by some friends of mine! I was having too much fun there to remember to take many pictures, but here are a few. There should be more soon at the camp&#39;s official site. An amusing sight we just had to stop at on the trip up... The swimming hole at the camp: beautiful, skin-numbingly cold, and C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stata Center</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2004/0601-StataCenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2004/0601-StataCenter/</guid>
      <description>The Stata Center Cambridge, MA - June 2004 This is the year MIT&#39;s new Stata Center, designed by Frank Gehry, was finally finished and ready for our lab (among others) to move into. Old Office First, a historical shot of me in our old digs in Tech Square, just before the move (courtesy of my colleague JinYang Li).
Can you tell we&#39;ve been in here a while? Stata Center Construction July 2001 - Just a huge hole in the ground.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tornado</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Tornado.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Tornado.html</guid>
      <description>&#34;The Great Salt Lake City Tornado of &#39;99&#34; OK, so it was pretty wimpy as far as tornados go compared with those in other areas, but it was sort of a novelty here.&amp;nbsp; Unfortunately, I wasn&#39;t in the area when it hit, so I missed most of the fun; however, I did get in on some of the aftermath on the way home.&amp;nbsp; The tornado passed just to the east of my house, so we didn&#39;t get any damage at all (although our yard did catch a few pieces of some less fortunate houses).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travels</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Travels.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Travels.html</guid>
      <description>Snapshots from some of my other travels... Snorkeling with Colby in my trusty PocoMan T-shirt during my latest trip to the Bay Islands, April 1998 Taking a rest after climbing the Schilthorn, Switzerland, October 1986 Feeding the swans with Aunt Arlene in Hallstatt, Austria, October 1986 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Nairobi, Kenya, April 1986 &amp;nbsp; Mombasa, Kenya, April 1986 &amp;nbsp; Our dog Penny patiently tolerates my ceremoniously conferring Dad&#39;s Ph.D. tassle on her ear Loma Linda, CA, June 1982 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; When&#39;s the last time you took a bath this way?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip to Hawaii, October 1999</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Hawaii.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Hawaii.html</guid>
      <description>Hawaii How many people are lucky enough to be offered a free trip for two to Hawaii for a couple days of easy work? :-) (Actually, I learned later that those couple days of easy work saved someone $40,000, so I guess maybe it was worth it... :) This was the first trip I&#39;ve been on with my new 48MB flash card for my Kodak DC240 digital camera, and I went berserk!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utah Travels</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/Utah.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/Utah.html</guid>
      <description> Travels in and around Utah &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The whole family in Southern Utah&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; OK, Mom, just take the picture!!!&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Colby&#39;s way of playing &#39;possum...&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Sunny in a cave with Michael and Monty&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Me, Sunny, Colby, and his pal... (can you find him?)&amp;nbsp; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venice</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2004/0116-Venice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2004/0116-Venice/</guid>
      <description>Venice (January 13-23, 2004) The Official Excuse ... er, Reason I was presenting a paper at Principles of Programming Languages 2004, a programming language theory conference. It&#39;s not too often that I get to go to a conference in such a place! Here&#39;s the conference croud, geeking away under centuries-old Italian frescoes in the Auditorium Santa Margherita, Dorsoduro. I stayed at Palazzo Zenobio, an old Armenian palace near the auditorium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vermont</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2001/0506-Vermont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2001/0506-Vermont/</guid>
      <description>Vermont May 6, 2001 A quick Sunday road trip with my friend Zarrin to see a few historic sites in New England. Old Bennington, Vermont The Old First Church in Old Bennington... ...where William Ellery Channing died and where Robert Frost is buried. Covered Bridges We hunted down three of the classic covered bridges in Vermont. Silk Road Bridge Henry Bridge Paper Mill Bridge Turned out we weren&#39;t the only ones touring the countryside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vienna</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2004/0626-Vienna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2004/0626-Vienna/</guid>
      <description> Vienna June 2004 Wien, Wein, und Gesang Bespectacled Renaissance Backgammon Cow Franz-Hochedlingergasse Tramwaychik! Garden at the Hundertwasser House Belvedere &#34;Last year at Belvedere&#34; Smiling ladies Wienerwald On a wine-tasting trip to a Heurigen outside the city Vienna Nights St. Stephan Peterskirche St.Ruprecht Donner Brunnen Fountain Student nightlife on the Danube Canal A furniture store on Rotenturmstrasse </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Villars, Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/album/2006/0119-Villars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/album/2006/0119-Villars/</guid>
      <description> Villars, Switzerland January 2006 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
