<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personhood on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Personhood/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personhood on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Personhood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coercion-Resistant E-voting and Proof of Personhood</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2025-01-06-coercion-resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2025-01-06-coercion-resistance/</guid>
      <description> Keynote at IC3 Winter Retreat 2025 January 6, 2025 – Engelberg, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Real Democratic DAOs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2024-11-28-democratic-dao/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2024-11-28-democratic-dao/</guid>
      <description> Invited talk at DAO Symposium 2024 November 28, 2024 – Zürich, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can decentralized systems be truly “democratizing” – and how?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2024-04-05-democratizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2024-04-05-democratizing/</guid>
      <description> Keynote at ChainScience 2024 April 5, 2024 – Zürich, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Distributed Infrastructure Could Save the Planet?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2023-12-12-dicg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2023-12-12-dicg/</guid>
      <description> Keynote at 4th International Workshop on Distributed Infrastructure for Common Good (DICG) December 12, 2023 – Bologna, Italy Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-Preserving Personhood-Based Credentials</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2023-01-16-personhood-credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2023-01-16-personhood-credentials/</guid>
      <description> Talk at IC3 Winter Retreat 2023 January 16, 2023 – Les Diablerets, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who – Or What – Will Our Distributed Metaverse Serve?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2022-07-06-metaverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2022-07-06-metaverse/</guid>
      <description> Invited talk at INRIA prospective seminar on Distributed Systems and Middleware July 6, 2022 – Rungis, France Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3PBCS: A Privacy-Preserving, Personhood-Based Credential System</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2022-apostoli/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2022-apostoli/</guid>
      <description>Ksandros Apostoli M.S. thesis advised by Simone Colombo and Bryan Ford March 22, 2022 Abstract Recent anonymous credential schemes present major advances in the way digital identities are treated, empowering users with fine-grained control over their personal data. While limiting the amount of user-data that is accessible to third parties paves the way to stronger privacy guarantees, it also leads to new challenges in preserving accountability and Sybil-Resistance. In this work, we present 3PBCS, a novel credential system, which integrates existing anonymous credential schemes with the notion of Proof-of-Personhood to achieve privacy, accountability and Sybil-Protection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Personhood: Towards Technology that Securely Serves People</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2022-02-17-personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2022-02-17-personhood/</guid>
      <description> Invited talk at SI Summit 2022 February 17, 2022 – Virtual Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIP: Trustless Coercion-Resistant In-Person Voter Registration</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/trip/</guid>
      <description>Louis-Henri Merino, Simone Colombo, Jeff Allen, Vero Estrada-Galiñanes, and Bryan Ford arXiv preprint Abstract: Most existing remote electronic voting systems are vulnerable to voter coercion and vote buying. While coercion-resistant voting systems address this challenge, current schemes assume that the voter has access to an untappable, incorruptible device during voter registration. We present TRIP, an in-person voter registration scheme enabling voters to create verifiable and indistinguishable real and fake credentials using an untrusted kiosk inside a privacy booth at a supervised location, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decentralized Finance: for the few, the many, or everyone?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2021-11-05-defi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2021-11-05-defi/</guid>
      <description> Talk at Finance &amp;amp; Technology Conference 2021 on Crypto-assets and Asset Tokenization EPFL Center for Digital Trust (C4DT) November 5, 2021 – Lausanne, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consensus for Decentralized Ledgers</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2021-10-25-consensus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2021-10-25-consensus/</guid>
      <description> Talk at Seminar 21431 – Rigorous Methods for Smart Contracts October 25, 2021 – Schloss Dagstuhl, Germany Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Personhood: Towards Technology that Securely Serves People</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2021-10-13-personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2021-10-13-personhood/</guid>
      <description> Distinguished Lecture at Vienna CyberSecurity and Privacy Research Cluster October 13, 2021 – Virtual Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof of Personhood: Introduction and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2021-07-27-personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2021-07-27-personhood/</guid>
      <description> Keynote at Internet of Humans Workshop #1 July 27, 2021 – Virtual Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technologizing Democracy or Democratizing Technology? A Layered-Architecture Perspective on Potentials and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Appears in Digital Technology and Democratic Theory by Lucy Bernholz, Hélène Landemore, and Rob Reich (editors) published by the University of Chicago Press
Abstract While technology is often claimed to be “democratizing”, the technologizing of society has more often yielded undemocratic or even anti-democratic outcomes. Is technology fundamentally at odds with democracy, or is it merely a rich and infinitely-adaptable toolbox that we’re using the wrong way? We explore how technology has failed to support robust democracy – but could do better – in the context of four basic social processes: collective deliberation and choice, information distribution and filtering, economic commerce, and identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personhood Online: Privacy, Transparency, and Inclusion for Digital Democracy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2020-11-05-personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2020-11-05-personhood/</guid>
      <description> Talk at Digital Democracy Workshop November 5, 2020 – Virtual Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identity and Personhood in Digital Democracy: Evaluating Inclusion, Equality, Security, and Privacy in Pseudonym Parties and Other Proofs of Personhood</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/personhood/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford November 2020 (first draft) arXiv preprint
Abstract: Digital identity seems at first like a prerequisite for digital democracy: how can we ensure &amp;ldquo;one person, one vote&amp;rdquo; online without identifying voters? But the full gamut of digital identity solutions &amp;ndash; e.g., online ID checking, biometrics, self-sovereign identity, and social/trust networks &amp;ndash; all present severe flaws in security, privacy, and transparency, leaving users vulnerable to exclusion, identity loss or theft, and coercion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain: Between Hype and Reality</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2020-01-29-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2020-01-29-blockchain/</guid>
      <description> Guest lecture at TransformTech January 29, 2020 – Lausanne, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain, Privacy, and Accountability</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2020-01-23-fintech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2020-01-23-fintech/</guid>
      <description> Talk at Caspian Week, World Economic Forum 2020 January 23, 2020 – Davos, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Architecture for Trust in the 21st Century</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2020-01-22-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2020-01-22-trust/</guid>
      <description> Talk at House of Switzerland, World Economic Forum 2020 January 22, 2020 – Davos, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Priorities: Should Identity Systems Divide or Unite People?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/02/08/identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/02/08/identity/</guid>
      <description>Note: this blog post was a brief sketch of ideas elaborated in a longer paper written later.
The problem of identity has become a hot topic, with the idea of self-sovereign identity in particular attracting significant excitement. The essence of the idea, in short, is to put users in charge of how their identities and personal data are used. Self-sovereign identity posits that users should decide how much and what aspects of their identities to disclose in any situation, and should know and have control over what that information is used for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof-of-Personhood: Redemocratizing Permissionless Cryptocurrencies</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</guid>
      <description>Maria Borge, Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Philipp Jovanovic, Linus Gasser, Nicolas Gailly, and Bryan Ford
EPFL IEEE Security &amp; Privacy on the Blockchain (IEEE S&amp;B)
April 29, 2017 Abstract: Permissionless blockchain-based cryptocurrencies commonly use proof-of-work (PoW) or proof-of-stake (PoS) to ensure their security, e.g. to prevent double spending attacks. However, both approaches have disadvantages: PoW leads to massive amounts of wasted electricity and re-centralization, whereas major stakeholders in PoS might be able to create a monopoly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s verify real people, not real names.</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2015/10/07/names.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2015/10/07/names.html</guid>
      <description>On Monday the EFF, together with a &amp;ldquo;Nameless Coalition&amp;rdquo; of like-minded groups, escalated the backlash against Facebook&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;real names&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;authentic identities&amp;rdquo; policy with an open letter urging Facebook to end this policy like Google Plus did last year. Facebook&amp;rsquo;s response cites concerns about pseudonyms helping to hide &amp;ldquo;terrorist organizations&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;school bullies&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;criminal behavior.&amp;rdquo;
While I support anonymity and have spent years working to strengthen it, terrorist fearmongering aside, Facebook is right that anonymity is often abused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Offline Foundation for Online Accountable Pseudonyms</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Jacob Strauss Massachusetts Institute of Technology First Workshop on Social Network Systems
April 1, 2008 Abstract: Online anonymity often appears to undermine accountability, offering little incentive for civil behavior, but accountability failures usually result not from anonymity itself but from the disposability of virtual identities. A user banned for misbehavior&amp;mdash;e.g., spamming from a free E-mail account or stuffing an online ballot box&amp;mdash;can simply open other accounts or connect from other IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sybil Parties: An Offline Foundation for Online Accountability</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/log/2006/0924-SybilParties.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/log/2006/0924-SybilParties.html</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford - September 24, 2006 Preliminary draft: see here for the final published paper The Human Recognition Problem Today&#39;s online ecosphere continually suffers from its inability to tell who is a genuine, unique human and who isn&#39;t. Because open-access messaging systems cannot isolate or authenticate the human source of messages for the purpose of suppressing abuses, spam has already relegated USENET to historical obscurity [Templeton01], threatens the usability of E-mail [Wouters05], and is even advancing on Skype.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
