<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Posts and Other Drafts on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Posts and Other Drafts on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MinML: concise but general markup syntax</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2022/12/28/minml/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2022/12/28/minml/</guid>
      <description>Could you use a markup syntax that supports the full expressive power and richness of HTML or XML, but is more terse, easier to type, and less frankly ugly? To emphasize text, for example, would it be nice just to write em[emphasize] instead of &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;emphasize&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;? If so, pleae read on. The tussle between generality and writer-friendliness Markup languages derived from SGML, like HTML and XML, are powerful and have many uses but are verbose and often a pain to write or edit manually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI for Governance Belongs in Mechanism, Not Policy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/post/2020-11-18-ai-governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/post/2020-11-18-ai-governance/</guid>
      <description>AI in Policy? This post contains an address delivered at the IRGC conference on Governance Of and By Digital Technology.
The separation of mechanism and policy Computer science has a well-established design principle known as separation of mechanism and policy. I think this principle may be equally applicable to human governance &amp;ndash; especially in considering the question of where AI does and does not belong.
I believe the cautious use of today&amp;rsquo;s powerful AI technologies based on machine learning can justifiably play many useful roles in implementing low-level mechanisms used in governance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rationality is Self-Defeating in Permissionless Systems</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/09/23/rational/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/09/23/rational/</guid>
      <description>by Bryan Ford and Rainer Böhme &amp;mdash; PDF preprint version available Many blockchain and cryptocurrency fans seem to prefer building and analyzing decentralized systems in a rational or &amp;ldquo;greedy behavior&amp;rdquo; failure model, rather than a Byzantine or &amp;ldquo;arbitrary behavior&amp;rdquo; failure model. Many of the same blockchain and cryptocurrency fans also like open, permissionless systems like Bitcoin and Ethereum, which anyone can join and participate in using weak identities such as anonymous cryptography key pairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Only Type Parameters Generic Enough for Go 2 Generics?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/07/29/go-generics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/07/29/go-generics/</guid>
      <description>The Go language appears to be getting slightly closer to supporting generics, with the recent release of a new proposal for generics based on type parameters and contracts.
I generally like the direction this proposal is going, with one significant reservation. I feel that the current proposal both unnecessarily limits how &amp;ldquo;generic&amp;rdquo; Go&amp;rsquo;s generics will be, and risks painting the language into a corner in the long term. This is because the proposal single-mindedly assumes that the only compile-time generic parameters we will ever want are type parameters, which seems like an unnecessary and undesirable restriction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Remote Voting Minefield: from North Carolina to Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/02/22/voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/02/22/voting/</guid>
      <description>The absentee ballot fraud in North Carolina shows how current vote-by-mail methods are fundamentally flawed and vulnerable to vote-buying and coercion. But banning remote voting of any kind would disenfranchise everyone not living in their country of citizenship; that is not a real option.
It is important to understand in this light the context of the Swiss e-voting project, one of whose two implementations was recently opened to public inspection by the Swiss Post for inspection and analysis by international experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Priorities: Should Identity Systems Divide or Unite People?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/02/08/identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/02/08/identity/</guid>
      <description>Note: this blog post was a brief sketch of ideas elaborated in a longer paper written later.
The problem of identity has become a hot topic, with the idea of self-sovereign identity in particular attracting significant excitement. The essence of the idea, in short, is to put users in charge of how their identities and personal data are used. Self-sovereign identity posits that users should decide how much and what aspects of their identities to disclose in any situation, and should know and have control over what that information is used for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So They&#39;re Selling You a Blockchain</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2018/09/11/blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2018/09/11/blockchain/</guid>
      <description>Blockchain is certainly one of the hot technology topics today. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s probably in part a hype bubble – but from my perspective as a long-time researcher in decentralized systems I believe there is also a lot of potential value in the concept, which is why my DEDIS lab at EPFL has been investing years of effort in building next generation blockchain architectures. I also believe the value of the blockchain concept is relatively independent of the unpredictable and scam-riddled financial market for cryptocurrencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Scientific Conferences Must Leave the U.S.</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2018/06/27/muslim-ban/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2018/06/27/muslim-ban/</guid>
      <description>So the U.S. Supreme Court has upheld Trump&amp;rsquo;s so-called “travel ban” – more honestly labeled a Muslim ban. More precisely, it is a ban on people from Muslim-majority countries not hosting Trump business properties (see map and fact check).
Where to Hold Conferences? This development naturally and rightfully raises again to prominence the question of where responsible scientists should hold their international conferences. We may soon see renewed calls to boycott US-based conferences, in solidarity with the many scientists around the world who can no longer attend conferences held in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sightseeing Around Lausanne</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2018/06/16/lausanne/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2018/06/16/lausanne/</guid>
      <description>For the benefit those visiting but not yet familiar with EPFL, Lausanne or other parts of the Lake Geneva Region, I thought I&#39;d write a quick summary of some of my personal favorite places and sights in the area. This is completely my personal perspective; I make no pretense at being objective or unbiased here and am not trying to write a proper travel guide. But with that in mind, I hope you might find something interesting here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do You Know It&#39;s On the Blockchain? With a SkipChain.</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2017/08/01/skipchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2017/08/01/skipchain/</guid>
      <description>A blockchain, or distributed ledger, is a log maintained collectively by a distributed group of participants who agree on and record transactions without relying for security on any single trusted party. While initially popularized by Bitcoin and its derivatives, the blockchain abstraction is not specific to currencies, and there is exploding industry interest in many non-currency uses. Many of these diverse use-cases, however, require users to be able to verify whether or not some transaction has been committed to a blockchain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Governs Us. Will it Govern Us Well?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2017/06/23/turing50/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2017/06/23/turing50/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is a transcript of my opening remarks on the panel &#34;Restoring Personal Privacy without Compromising National Security&#34; at the 50 Years of the ACM Turing Award Celebration. We now live in a world in which the rules coded into the technology we use plays as important a role in governing our lives as the formal laws written in the public law books. Code is law already, for better or worse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untangling Mining Incentives in Bitcoin and ByzCoin</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/10/25/mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/10/25/mining/</guid>
      <description>As the first widely-deployed cryptocurrency, Bitcoin has proven hugely successful and inspired a blockchain fever (or is it a bubble?). Bitcoin&#39;s security and economic assumptions are showing significant fractures, however. Following previously-identified selfish mining and stubborn mining attacks, new research from Princeton being presented at CCS identifies further incentive weaknesses that appear as transaction fees supplant block rewards as the primary incentive for mining. In short, miners motivated by transaction fees have even greater incentive to deviate strategically from the standard Bitcoin protocol in selfish and potentially destructive ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple, FBI, and Software Transparency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/03/10/apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/03/10/apple/</guid>
      <description>*This post [originally appeared](https://freedom-to-tinker.com/blog/bford/apple-fbi-and-software-transparency/) on the [Freedom to Tinker](https://freedom-to-tinker.com/) blog by the [Center for Information Technology Policy](https://citp.princeton.edu) at [Princeton University](http://www.princeton.edu/).* The Apple versus FBI showdown has quickly become a crucial flashpoint of the “new Crypto War.” On February 16 the FBI invoked the All Writs Act of 1789, a catch-all authority for assistance of law enforcement, demanding that Apple create a custom version of its iOS to help the FBI decrypt an iPhone used by one of the San Bernardino shooters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collectively Witnessing Log Servers in CT</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2015-10-20-cosi-ct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2015-10-20-cosi-ct/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford draft-ford-trans-witness-00 Abstract: This document proposes a backward-compatible extension to CT enabling log servers to obtain compact collective signatures from any number of well-known &#34;witness&#34; servers, which clients can check without gossip to verify that log server records have been widely witnessed. Collective signatures proactively protect clients from man-in-the- middle attackers who may have stolen the private keys of one or more log servers, even if the attacker controls the client&#39;s network access, the client is unwilling to gossip for privacy reasons, or the client does not wish to incur the network bandwidth and/or latency costs of gossip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s verify real people, not real names.</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2015/10/07/names.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2015/10/07/names.html</guid>
      <description>On Monday the EFF, together with a &amp;ldquo;Nameless Coalition&amp;rdquo; of like-minded groups, escalated the backlash against Facebook&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;real names&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;authentic identities&amp;rdquo; policy with an open letter urging Facebook to end this policy like Google Plus did last year. Facebook&amp;rsquo;s response cites concerns about pseudonyms helping to hide &amp;ldquo;terrorist organizations&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;school bullies&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;criminal behavior.&amp;rdquo;
While I support anonymity and have spent years working to strengthen it, terrorist fearmongering aside, Facebook is right that anonymity is often abused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegative Democracy Revisited</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2014/11/16/deleg.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2014/11/16/deleg.html</guid>
      <description>Over a decade ago I wrote up some ideas I called &amp;ldquo;Delegative Democracy,&amp;rdquo; which has also become known as &amp;ldquo;Liquid Democracy.&amp;rdquo; My draft paper from 2002 took a first stab at laying out the general idea, though I never finished or tried to publish it. Since a lot has happened in this space since then, and I get regular inquiries about it, I thought it was high time to revisit the idea and review more recent developments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faculty size and growth in the top 20 Computer Science departments</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2014/10/22/cs-growth.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2014/10/22/cs-growth.html</guid>
      <description>Yesterday the Yale Daily News ran an article on our CS department&amp;rsquo;s faculty shortage, which generated some discussion among CS colleagues. Yale&amp;rsquo;s CS faculty shortage is not really news: for example, another YDN article over a year ago made basically the same point, and that probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t the first.
Setting aside Yale in particular, however, it is interesting to notice some broader trends in CS department growth. So here are a couple charts I recently put together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/post/2014-10-22-open-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/post/2014-10-22-open-surveillance/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Design Guidelines for Traversal through Network Address Translators</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2005/02/01/behave-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2005/02/01/behave-app/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Pyda Srisuresh, and Dan Kegel draft-ford-behave-app Abstract: This document defines guidelines by which application designers can create applications that communicate reliably and efficiently in the presence of Network Address Translators (NATs), particularly when the application has a need for &#34;peer-to-peer&#34; (P2P) type of communication. The guidelines allow a P2P application to work reliably across a majority of existing NATs, as well as all future NATs that conform to the behave requirements specified in companion documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operating Principles and General Behavioral Requirements for Network Address Translators (BEH-GEN)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2005/02/01/behave-gen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2005/02/01/behave-gen/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Pyda Srisuresh draft-ford-behave-gen
Abstract: This document discusses the operating principles of Network Address Translator (NAT) devices and the behavioral properties required to make NAT more predictable and compatible with diverse application protocols. First, this document presents an architectural model for NAT devices and defines important terms used in conjunction with NAT operation. The architectural model sets the stage for a set of concrete recommendations for NAT implementers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual Representation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2004/11/23/indrep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2004/11/23/indrep/</guid>
      <description>Real Choice for Voters, Democratic Currency for Activists Introduction The traditional purpose of popular elections is primarily to elect candidates to government offices or legislative seats, but this is not the only way we could use elections to facilitate democracy. Individual Representation, or indrep, provides a new and different reason to hold popular elections: as a tool for directly promoting the growth of grassroots social and political relationships throughout the basic fabric of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiki Democracy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2004/08/16/wiki-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2004/08/16/wiki-democracy/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cache Directory Tagging Specification</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/cachedir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/cachedir/</guid>
      <description>Version 0.6 (Changes) Proposed by Bryan Ford Abstract Many applications create and manage directories containing cached information about content stored elsewhere, such as cached Web content or thumbnail-size versions of images or movies. For speed and storage efficiency we would often like to avoid backing up, archiving, or otherwise unnecessarily copying such directories around, but it is a pain to identify and individually exclude each such directory during data transfer operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fx86: Functional Management of Imperative Virtual Machines</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2003/08/28/fx86/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2003/08/28/fx86/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Duality - Vitalizing the Commons</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2003/07/24/service-duality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2003/07/24/service-duality/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegative Voting</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2002/10/21/deleg-voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2002/10/21/deleg-voting/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegative Democracy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2002/05/15/deleg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2002/05/15/deleg/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
