<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Humanitarian on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Humanitarian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Humanitarian on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Humanitarian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Decentralized Finance: for the few, the many, or everyone?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2021-11-05-defi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2021-11-05-defi/</guid>
      <description> Talk at Finance &amp;amp; Technology Conference 2021 on Crypto-assets and Asset Tokenization EPFL Center for Digital Trust (C4DT) November 5, 2021 – Lausanne, Switzerland Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Enforcing the Digital Immunity of a Large Humanitarian Organization</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/immunity-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/immunity-abs/</guid>
      <description>Stevens Le Blond, Alejandro Cuevas, Juan Ram&amp;oacute;n Troncoso-Pastoriza, Philipp Jovanovic, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux
EPFL Winner of Distinguished Paper Award IEEE Security &amp; Privacy (IEEE S&amp;P)
May 22, 2018 Abstract: Humanitarian action, the process of aiding individuals in situations of crises, poses unique information-security challenges due to natural or manmade disasters, the adverse environments in which it takes place, and the scale and multidisciplinary nature of the problems. Despite these challenges, humanitarian organizations are transitioning towards a strong reliance on the digitization of collected data and digital tools, which improves their effectiveness but also exposes them to computer-security threats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the World of Human Rights: Please Make Yourself Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/human-rights-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/human-rights-abs/</guid>
      <description> Henry Corrigan-Gibbs and Bryan Ford Yale University Cyber-security Research Ethics Dialog &amp; Strategy Workshop (CREDS 2013)
May 23, 2013 Abstract: We draw an ethical analogy between Internet freedom efforts and humanitarian aid work. This parallel motivates a number of ethical questions relating to anonymity and censorship-circumvention research. Paper: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
