<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Consensus on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Consensus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Consensus on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Consensus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rationality is Self-Defeating in Permissionless Systems</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/09/23/rational/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/09/23/rational/</guid>
      <description>by Bryan Ford and Rainer Böhme &amp;mdash; PDF preprint version available   Many blockchain and cryptocurrency fans seem to prefer building and analyzing decentralized systems in a rational or &amp;ldquo;greedy behavior&amp;rdquo; failure model, rather than a Byzantine or &amp;ldquo;arbitrary behavior&amp;rdquo; failure model. Many of the same blockchain and cryptocurrency fans also like open, permissionless systems like Bitcoin and Ethereum, which anyone can join and participate in using weak identities such as anonymous cryptography key pairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untangling Mining Incentives in Bitcoin and ByzCoin</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/10/25/mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/10/25/mining/</guid>
      <description>--   As the first widely-deployed cryptocurrency, Bitcoin has proven hugely successful and inspired a blockchain fever (or is it a bubble?). Bitcoin&#39;s security and economic assumptions are showing significant fractures, however. Following previously-identified selfish mining and stubborn mining attacks, new research from Princeton being presented at CCS identifies further incentive weaknesses that appear as transaction fees supplant block rewards as the primary incentive for mining.
In short, miners motivated by transaction fees have even greater incentive to deviate strategically from the standard Bitcoin protocol in selfish and potentially destructive ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Bitcoin Security and Performance with Strong Consistency via Collective Signing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/byzcoin-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/byzcoin-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>