<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peer-to-Peer on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Peer-to-Peer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peer-to-Peer on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Peer-to-Peer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Immunizing Systems from Distant Failures by Limiting Lamport Exposure</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/limix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/limix/</guid>
      <description>Cristina Băsescu and Bryan Ford Twentieth ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets)
November 10-12, 2021 Abstract: Failures far away from a user should intuitively be less likely to affect that user. Today&#39;s ecosystem miserably fails this test, however, despite high-availability best practices. Correlated and cascading failures &amp;ndash; triggered by misconfigurations, bugs, and network partitions &amp;ndash; often invalidate assumptions of failure independence. We propose that distributed services need not and should not expose local activities to distant failures or partitions, no matter how severe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eyo: Device-Transparent Personal Storage</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/eyo-usenix-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/eyo-usenix-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jacob Strauss, Justin Mazzola Paluska, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Bryan Ford, Robert Morris, and Frans Kaashoek
2011 USENIX Annual Technical Conference June 15-17, 2011, Portland, OR, USA Abstract: Users increasingly store data collections such as digital photographs on multiple personal devices, each of which typically offers a storage management interface oblivious to the contents of the user’s other devices. As a result, collections become disorganized and drift out of sync. This paper presents Eyo, a novel personal storage system that provides device transparency: a user can think in terms of &amp;ldquo;file X&amp;rdquo;, rather than &amp;ldquo;file X on device Y&amp;rdquo;, and will see the same set of files on all personal devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unintended Consequences of NAT Deployments with Overlapping Address Space</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5684-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5684-abs/</guid>
      <description>Pyda Srisuresh and Bryan Ford IETF RFC 5684
February 2010 Abstract: This document identifies two deployment scenarios that have arisen from the unconventional network topologies formed using Network Address Translator (NAT) devices. First, the simplicity of administering networks through the combination of NAT and DHCP has increasingly lead to the deployment of multi-level inter-connected private networks involving overlapping private IP address spaces. Second, the proliferation of private networks in enterprises, hotels and conferences, and the wide-spread use of Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) to access an enterprise intranet from remote locations has increasingly lead to overlapping private IP address space between remote and corporate networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Device Transparency: a New Model for Mobile Storage</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/devtransp-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/devtransp-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jacob Strauss
Chris Lesniewski-Laas
Justin Mazzola Paluska
Bryan Ford
Robert Morris
Frans Kaashoek
Published in SOSP Workshop on Hot Topics in Storage and File Systems (HotStorage &#39;09) October 11, 2009, Big Sky, MT, USA Abstract: This paper proposes a new storage model, device transparency, in which users view and manage their entire data collection from any of their devices, even from disconnected storage-limited devices holding only a subset of the entire collection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAT Behavioral Requirements for ICMP</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5508-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5508-abs/</guid>
      <description>Pyda Srisuresh, Bryan Ford, Senthil Sivakumar, and Saikat Guha IETF RFC 5508
April 2009 Abstract: This document specifies the behavioral properties required of the Network Address Translator (NAT) devices in conjunction with the Internet Control Message Protocol (ICMP). The objective of this memo is to make NAT devices more predictable and compatible with diverse application protocols that traverse the devices. Companion documents provide behavioral recommendations specific to TCP, UDP, and other protocols.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAT Behavioral Requirements for TCP</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5382-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5382-abs/</guid>
      <description> Saikat Guha, Kaushik Biswas, Bryan Ford, Senthil Sivakumar, and Pyda Srisuresh IETF RFC 5382
October 2008 Abstract: This document defines a set of requirements for NATs that handle TCP that would allow many applications, such as peer-to-peer applications and online games to work consistently. Developing NATs that meet this set of requirements will greatly increase the likelihood that these applications will function properly. Final RFC: Plain text Early drafts: IETF working group draft versions: 06 05 04 03 02 01 00 Individual draft versions: 02 01 00 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIA: A Global Connectivity Architecture for Mobile Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Ph.D. thesis, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, September 2008. Abstract: The Internet&#39;s architecture, designed in the days of large, stationary computers tended by technically savvy and accountable administrators, fails to meet the demands of the emerging ubiquitous computing era. Nontechnical users now routinely own multiple personal devices, many of them mobile, and need to share information securely among them using interactive, delay-sensitive applications. Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) is a novel, incrementally deployable network architecture for modern personal devices, which reconsiders three architectural cornerstones: naming, routing, and transport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Peer-to-Peer (P2P) Communication across Network Address Translators (NATs)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5128-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5128-abs/</guid>
      <description>Pyda Srisuresh, Bryan Ford, and Dan Kegel IETF RFC 5128
March 2008 Abstract: This memo documents the various methods known to be in use by applications to establish direct communication in the presence of Network Address Translators (NATs) at the current time. Although this memo is intended to be mainly descriptive, the Security Considerations section makes some purely advisory recommendations about how to deal with security vulnerabilities the applications could inadvertently create when using the methods described.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent Personal Names for Globally Connected Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, Robert Morris
Massachusetts Institute of Technology 7th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation
November 6-8, 2006 Abstract: The Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) provides zero-configuration connectivity among mobile devices through personal names. Users assign personal names through an ad hoc device introduction process requiring no central allocation. Once assigned, names bind securely to the global identities of their target devices independent of network location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User-Relative Names for Globally Connected Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-iptps-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-iptps-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, and Robert Morris Massachusetts Institute of Technology 5th International Workshop on Peer-to-Peer Systems
February 27-28, 2006 Abstract The User Information Architecture, or UIA, is a peer-to-peer connectivity architecture that provides users a simple, intuitive, and secure way to share information and services between personal devices by assigning ad hoc names that act like &amp;ldquo;virtual cables.&amp;rdquo; Users assign names by &amp;ldquo;introducing&amp;rdquo; devices to each other on a common network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer-to-Peer Communication Across Network Address Translators</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/p2pnat-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/p2pnat-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Massachusetts Institute of Technology baford (at) mit.edu Pyda Srisuresh Caymas Systems, Inc. srisuresh (at) yahoo.com Dan Kegel dank (at) kegel.com Presented at the USENIX Annual Technical Conference, April 10-15, 2005. Abstract: Network Address Translation (NAT) causes well-known difficulties for peer-to-peer (P2P) communication, since the peers involved may not be reachable at any globally valid IP address. Several NAT traversal techniques are known, but their documentation is slim, and data about their robustness or relative merits is slimmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Design Guidelines for Traversal through Network Address Translators</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2005/02/01/behave-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2005/02/01/behave-app/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Pyda Srisuresh, and Dan Kegel draft-ford-behave-app Abstract: This document defines guidelines by which application designers can create applications that communicate reliably and efficiently in the presence of Network Address Translators (NATs), particularly when the application has a need for &#34;peer-to-peer&#34; (P2P) type of communication. The guidelines allow a P2P application to work reliably across a majority of existing NATs, as well as all future NATs that conform to the behave requirements specified in companion documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operating Principles and General Behavioral Requirements for Network Address Translators (BEH-GEN)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2005/02/01/behave-gen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2005/02/01/behave-gen/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Pyda Srisuresh draft-ford-behave-gen
Abstract: This document discusses the operating principles of Network Address Translator (NAT) devices and the behavioral properties required to make NAT more predictable and compatible with diverse application protocols. First, this document presents an architectural model for NAT devices and defines important terms used in conjunction with NAT operation. The architectural model sets the stage for a set of concrete recommendations for NAT implementers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Duality - Vitalizing the Commons</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2003/07/24/service-duality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2003/07/24/service-duality/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
