<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peer-to-peer on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Peer-to-peer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peer-to-peer on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Peer-to-peer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Unintended Consequences of NAT Deployments with Overlapping Address Space</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5684-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5684-abs/</guid>
      <description>Pyda Srisuresh and Bryan Ford   IETF RFC 5684
February 2010  Abstract: This document identifies two deployment scenarios that have arisen from the unconventional network topologies formed using Network Address Translator (NAT) devices. First, the simplicity of administering networks through the combination of NAT and DHCP has increasingly lead to the deployment of multi-level inter-connected private networks involving overlapping private IP address spaces. Second, the proliferation of private networks in enterprises, hotels and conferences, and the wide-spread use of Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) to access an enterprise intranet from remote locations has increasingly lead to overlapping private IP address space between remote and corporate networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAT Behavioral Requirements for ICMP</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5508-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5508-abs/</guid>
      <description>Pyda Srisuresh, Bryan Ford, Senthil Sivakumar, and Saikat Guha   IETF RFC 5508
April 2009  Abstract: This document specifies the behavioral properties required of the Network Address Translator (NAT) devices in conjunction with the Internet Control Message Protocol (ICMP). The objective of this memo is to make NAT devices more predictable and compatible with diverse application protocols that traverse the devices. Companion documents provide behavioral recommendations specific to TCP, UDP, and other protocols.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAT Behavioral Requirements for TCP</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5382-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5382-abs/</guid>
      <description>   Saikat Guha, Kaushik Biswas, Bryan Ford, Senthil Sivakumar, and Pyda Srisuresh   IETF RFC 5382
October 2008  Abstract: This document defines a set of requirements for NATs that handle TCP that would allow many applications, such as peer-to-peer applications and online games to work consistently. Developing NATs that meet this set of requirements will greatly increase the likelihood that these applications will function properly. Paper: Plain text  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIA: A Global Connectivity Architecture for Mobile Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Ph.D. thesis, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, September 2008. Abstract:  The Internet&#39;s architecture, designed in the days of large, stationary computers tended by technically savvy and accountable administrators, fails to meet the demands of the emerging ubiquitous computing era. Nontechnical users now routinely own multiple personal devices, many of them mobile, and need to share information securely among them using interactive, delay-sensitive applications.  Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) is a novel, incrementally deployable network architecture for modern personal devices, which reconsiders three architectural cornerstones: naming, routing, and transport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Peer-to-Peer (P2P) Communication across Network Address Translators (NATs)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5128-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5128-abs/</guid>
      <description>Pyda Srisuresh, Bryan Ford, and Dan Kegel   IETF RFC 5128
March 2008  Abstract: This memo documents the various methods known to be in use by applications to establish direct communication in the presence of Network Address Translators (NATs) at the current time. Although this memo is intended to be mainly descriptive, the Security Considerations section makes some purely advisory recommendations about how to deal with security vulnerabilities the applications could inadvertently create when using the methods described.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent Personal Names for Globally Connected Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, Robert Morris
 Massachusetts Institute of Technology Published in 7th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation, November 6-8, 2006. Abstract:  The  Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) provides zero-configuration connectivity among mobile devices through personal names. Users assign personal names through an ad hoc device introduction process requiring no central allocation. Once assigned, names bind securely to the global identities of their target devices independent of network location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User-Relative Names for Globally Connected Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-iptps-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-iptps-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, and Robert Morris Massachusetts Institute of Technology   5th International Workshop on Peer-to-Peer Systems
February 27-28, 2006  Abstract The User Information Architecture, or UIA, is a peer-to-peer connectivity architecture that provides users a simple, intuitive, and secure way to share information and services between personal devices by assigning ad hoc names that act like &amp;ldquo;virtual cables.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>