<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Technologizing Democracy or Democratizing Technology? A Layered-Architecture Perspective on Potentials and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</guid>
      <description> Bryan Ford Draft &amp;ndash; January 30, 2020
Final version to appear in forthcoming book Digital Technology and Democratic Theory by Lucy Bernholz, Hélène Landemore, and Rob Reich (editors) published by the University of Chicago Press
 Book chapter: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rationality is Self-Defeating in Permissionless Systems</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/09/23/rational/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/09/23/rational/</guid>
      <description>by Bryan Ford and Rainer Böhme &amp;mdash; PDF preprint version available   Many blockchain and cryptocurrency fans seem to prefer building and analyzing decentralized systems in a rational or &amp;ldquo;greedy behavior&amp;rdquo; failure model, rather than a Byzantine or &amp;ldquo;arbitrary behavior&amp;rdquo; failure model. Many of the same blockchain and cryptocurrency fans also like open, permissionless systems like Bitcoin and Ethereum, which anyone can join and participate in using weak identities such as anonymous cryptography key pairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Metadata Leakage from Encrypted Files and Communication with PURBs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/purb-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/purb-abs/</guid>
      <description>Kirill Nikitin, Ludovic Barman, Wouter Lueks, Matthew Underwood, Jean-Pierre Hubaux and Bryan Ford EPFL - IC - DEDIS   Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
July 2019.  Abstract: Most encrypted data formats leak metadata via their plaintext headers, such as format version, encryption schemes used, number of recipients who can decrypt the data, and even the recipients’ identities. This leakage can pose security and privacy risks to users, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Security of Two-Round Multi-Signatures</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/two-round-multisig-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/two-round-multisig-abs/</guid>
      <description>Manu Drijvers, Kasra Edalatnejad, Bryan Ford, Eike Kiltz, Julian Loss, Gregory Neven, and Igors Stepanovs   40th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy
May 2019  Abstract: A multi-signature scheme allows a group of signers to collaboratively sign a message, creating a single signature that convinces a verifier that every individual signer approved the message. The increased interest in technologies to decentralize trust has triggered the proposal of highly efficient two-round Schnorr-based multi-signature schemes designed to scale up to thousands of signers, namely BCJ by Bagherzandi et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Remote Voting Minefield: from North Carolina to Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/02/22/voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/02/22/voting/</guid>
      <description>The absentee ballot fraud in North Carolina shows how current vote-by-mail methods are fundamentally flawed and vulnerable to vote-buying and coercion. But banning remote voting of any kind would disenfranchise everyone not living in their country of citizenship; that is not a real option.
It is important to understand in this light the context of the Swiss e-voting project, one of whose two implementations was recently opened to public inspection by the Swiss Post for inspection and analysis by international experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So They&#39;re Selling You a Blockchain</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2018/09/11/blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2018/09/11/blockchain/</guid>
      <description>Blockchain is certainly one of the hot technology topics today. Yes, it&#39;s probably in part a hype bubble – but from my perspective as a long-time researcher in decentralized systems I believe there is also a lot of potential value in the concept, which is why my DEDIS lab at EPFL has been investing years of effort in building next generation blockchain architectures. I also believe the value of the blockchain concept is relatively independent of the unpredictable and scam-riddled &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://blockonomi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MedCo: Enabling Secure and Privacy-Conscious Exploration of Distributed Clinical and Genomic Data</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/medco-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/medco-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jean Louis Raisaro, Juan Ram&amp;oacute;n Troncoso-Pastoriza, Micka&amp;euml;l Misbach, Jo&amp;atilde;o S&amp;aacute; Sousa, Sylvain Pradervand, Edoardo Missiaglia, Olivier Michielin, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux   IEEE/ACM Transactions on Computational Biology and Bioinformatics,
July 13, 2018. Abstract: The increasing number of health-data breaches is creating a complicated environment for medical-data sharing and, consequently, for medical progress. Therefore, the development of new solutions that can reassure clinical sites by enabling privacy-preserving sharing of sensitive medical data in compliance with stringent regulations (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OmniLedger: A Secure, Scale-Out, Decentralized Ledger via Sharding</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/omniledger-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/omniledger-abs/</guid>
      <description>Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Philipp Jovanovic, Linus Gasser, Nicolas Gailly, Ewa Syta, and Bryan Ford
  IEEE Security &amp; Privacy (IEEE S&amp;P)
May 22, 2018 Abstract: Designing a secure permissionless distributed ledger (blockchain) that performs on par with centralized payment processors, such as Visa, is a challenging task. Most existing distributed ledgers are unable to scale-out, i.e., to grow their total processing capacity with the number of validators; and those that do, compromise security or decentralization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Enforcing the Digital Immunity of a Large Humanitarian Organization</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/immunity-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/immunity-abs/</guid>
      <description>Stevens Le Blond, Alejandro Cuevas, Juan Ram&amp;oacute;n Troncoso-Pastoriza, Philipp Jovanovic, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux
EPFL  Distinguished Paper Award   IEEE Security &amp; Privacy (IEEE S&amp;P)
May 22, 2018 Abstract: Humanitarian action, the process of aiding individuals in situations of crises, poses unique information-security challenges due to natural or manmade disasters, the adverse environments in which it takes place, and the scale and multidisciplinary nature of the problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAINIAC: Proactive Software-Update Transparency via Collectively Signed Skipchains and Verified Builds</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/chainiac-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/chainiac-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UnLynx: A Decentralized System for Privacy-Conscious Data Sharing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/unlynx-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/unlynx-abs/</guid>
      <description>David Froelicher, Patricia Egger, Jo&amp;atilde;o S&amp;aacute; Sousa, Jean Louis Raisaro, Zhicong Huang, Christian Mouchet, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux   Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium (PETS)
July 19, 2017 Abstract: Current solutions for privacy-preserving data sharing among multiple parties either depend on a centralized authority that must be trusted and provides only weakest-link security (e.g., the entity that manages private/secret cryptographic keys), or leverage on decentralized but impractical approaches (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Bias-Resistant Distributed Randomness</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/random-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/random-abs/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta, Philipp Jovanovic, Eleftherios Kokoris Kogias, Nicolas Gailly, Linus Gasser, Ismail Khoffi, Michael J. Fischer, and Bryan Ford
  IEEE Security &amp; Privacy (IEEE S&amp;P)
May 23, 2017 Abstract: Bias-resistant public randomness is a critical component in many (distributed) protocols. Generating public randomness is hard, however, because active adversaries may behave dishonestly to bias public random choices toward their advantage. Existing solutions do not scale to hundreds or thousands of participants, as is needed in many decentralized systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Objectives of Lawful-Surveillance Protocols</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/lawful-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/lawful-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untangling Mining Incentives in Bitcoin and ByzCoin</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/10/25/mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/10/25/mining/</guid>
      <description>--   As the first widely-deployed cryptocurrency, Bitcoin has proven hugely successful and inspired a blockchain fever (or is it a bubble?). Bitcoin&#39;s security and economic assumptions are showing significant fractures, however. Following previously-identified selfish mining and stubborn mining attacks, new research from Princeton being presented at CCS identifies further incentive weaknesses that appear as transaction fees supplant block rewards as the primary incentive for mining.
In short, miners motivated by transaction fees have even greater incentive to deviate strategically from the standard Bitcoin protocol in selfish and potentially destructive ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PriFi: A Low-Latency and Tracking-Resistant Protocol for Local-Area Anonymous Communication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/prifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/prifi/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-Preserving Lawful Contact Chaining</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/contact-chaining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/contact-chaining/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Bitcoin Security and Performance with Strong Consistency via Collective Signing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/byzcoin-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/byzcoin-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Efficient Communication System With Strong Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/riffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/riffle/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Authorities “Honest or Bust” with Decentralized Witness Cosigning</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cosi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cosi/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AnonRep: Towards Tracking-Resistant Anonymous Reputation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Privacy-Preserving Cryptographic Credentials from Federated Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book-codaspy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book-codaspy/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple, FBI, and Software Transparency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/03/10/apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/03/10/apple/</guid>
      <description>*This post [originally appeared](https://freedom-to-tinker.com/blog/bford/apple-fbi-and-software-transparency/) on the [Freedom to Tinker](https://freedom-to-tinker.com/) blog by the [Center for Information Technology Policy](https://citp.princeton.edu) at [Princeton University](http://www.princeton.edu/).*  The Apple versus FBI showdown has quickly become a crucial flashpoint of the “new Crypto War.” On February 16 the FBI invoked the All Writs Act of 1789, a catch-all authority for assistance of law enforcement, demanding that Apple create a custom version of its iOS to help the FBI decrypt an iPhone used by one of the San Bernardino shooters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collectively Witnessing Log Servers in CT</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2015-10-20-cosi-ct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2015-10-20-cosi-ct/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford   draft-ford-trans-witness-00  Abstract: This document proposes a backward-compatible extension to CT enabling log servers to obtain compact collective signatures from any number of well-known &#34;witness&#34; servers, which clients can check without gossip to verify that log server records have been widely witnessed. Collective signatures proactively protect clients from man-in-the- middle attackers who may have stolen the private keys of one or more log servers, even if the attacker controls the client&#39;s network access, the client is unwilling to gossip for privacy reasons, or the client does not wish to incur the network bandwidth and/or latency costs of gossip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deterministically Deterring Timing Attacks in Deterland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-timing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-timing/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Anonymity in an Internet Panopticon</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/panopticon-cacm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/panopticon-cacm/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Eyes: Secure Remote Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta, Michael J. Fischer, David Wolinsky, Abraham Silberschatz, Gina Gallegos-García, and Bryan Ford   12th International Conference on Security and Cryptography (SECRYPT)
July 2015.  Abstract: We propose an efficient remote biometric authentication protocol that gives strong protection to the user’s biometric data in case of two common kinds of security breaches: (1) loss or theft of the user’s token (smart card, handheld device, etc.), giving the attacker full access to any secrets embedded within it; (2) total penetration of the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certificate Cothority: Towards Trustworthy Collective CAs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/certco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/certco/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heading Off Correlated Failures through Independence-as-a-Service</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-indaas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-indaas/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching Bandits and Only Bandits: Privacy-Preserving Intersection Warrants for Lawful Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/bandits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/bandits/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing NymBoxes for Identity and Tracking Protection</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/nymboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/nymboxes/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Analysis of Accountable Anonymity in Dissent</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-analysis/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A TorPath to TorCoin: Proof-of-Bandwidth Altcoins for Compensating Relays</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/torcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/torcoin/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Onions to Shallots: Rewarding Tor Relays with TEARS</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/onions-to-shallots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/onions-to-shallots/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crypto-Book: An Architecture for Privacy Preserving Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Cloud Audits that Protect Private Information</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-psra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-psra/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conscript Your Friends into Larger Anonymity Sets with JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/conscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/conscript/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring High-Quality Randomness in Cryptographic Key Generation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/randomness-keygen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/randomness-keygen/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hang With Your Buddies to Resist Intersection Attacks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/buddies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/buddies/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Untold Story of Redundant Clouds: Making Your Service Deployment Truly Reliable</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/irec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/irec/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proactively Accountable Anonymous Messaging in Verdict</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/verdict/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/verdict/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Latency in Tor Circuits with Unordered Delivery</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/tor-unordered/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/tor-unordered/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the World of Human Rights: Please Make Yourself Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/human-rights-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/human-rights-abs/</guid>
      <description>   Henry Corrigan-Gibbs and Bryan Ford Yale University   Cyber-security Research Ethics Dialog &amp; Strategy Workshop (CREDS 2013)
May 23, 2013  Abstract: We draw an ethical analogy between Internet freedom efforts and humanitarian aid work. This parallel motivates a number of ethical questions relating to anonymity and censorship-circumvention research. Paper: PDF  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the OS against Security Threats in System Administration</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/middleware12-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/middleware12-abs/</guid>
      <description>Nuno Santos, Rodrigo Rodrigues, and Bryan Ford   ACM/IFIP/USENIX 13th International Conference on Middleware
December 2012  Abstract: The consequences of security breaches due to system administrator errors can be catastrophic. Software systems in general, and OSes in particular, ultimately depend on a fully trusted administrator whom is granted superuser privileges that allow him to fully control the system. Consequently, an administrator acting negligently or unethically can easily compromise user data in irreversible ways by leaking, modifying, or deleting data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissent in Numbers: Making Strong Anonymity Scale</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-in-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-in-numbers/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugging Side-Channel Leaks with Timing Information Flow Control</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/tifc-hotcloud12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/tifc-hotcloud12/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icebergs in the Clouds: the Other Risks of Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/icebergs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/icebergs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Theft-Proof Privacy-Preserving Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Anonymous Group Communication in the Anytrust Model</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/anytrust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/anytrust/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CertiKOS: A Certified Kernel for Secure Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/certikos-apsys11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/certikos-apsys11/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determinating Timing Channels in Compute Clouds</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/timing-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/timing-abs/</guid>
      <description>Amittai Aviram, Sen Hu, Bryan Ford
	Ramakrishna Gummadi
	Yale University 	University of Massachusetts Amherst  The ACM Cloud Computing Security Workshop (CCSW 2010) October 8, 2010, Chicago, IL, USA Abstract: Timing side-channels represent an insidious security challenge for cloud computing, because: (a) massive parallelism in the cloud makes timing channels pervasive and hard to control; (b) timing channels enable one customer to steal information from another without leaving a trail or raising alarms; (c) only the cloud provider can feasibly detect and report such attacks, but the provider&#39;s incentives are not to; and (d) resource partitioning schemes for timing channel control undermine statistical sharing efficiency, and, with it, the cloud computing business model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient System-Enforced Deterministic Parallelism</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-osdi10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-osdi10/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Development of Certified OS Kernels</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/certified-kernels-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/certified-kernels-abs/</guid>
      <description>Zhong Shao and Bryan Ford Department of Computer Science, Yale University   Yale University Technical Report TR1436
July 15, 2010  Abstract: Operating System (OS) kernels form the bedrock of all system software&amp;mdash;they can have the greatest impact on the resilience, extensibility, and security of today’s computing hosts. A single kernel bug can easily wreck the entire system’s integrity and protection. We propose to apply new advances in certified software to the development of a novel OS kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unintended Consequences of NAT Deployments with Overlapping Address Space</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5684-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5684-abs/</guid>
      <description>Pyda Srisuresh and Bryan Ford   IETF RFC 5684
February 2010  Abstract: This document identifies two deployment scenarios that have arisen from the unconventional network topologies formed using Network Address Translator (NAT) devices. First, the simplicity of administering networks through the combination of NAT and DHCP has increasingly lead to the deployment of multi-level inter-connected private networks involving overlapping private IP address spaces. Second, the proliferation of private networks in enterprises, hotels and conferences, and the wide-spread use of Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) to access an enterprise intranet from remote locations has increasingly lead to overlapping private IP address space between remote and corporate networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIA: A Global Connectivity Architecture for Mobile Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Ph.D. thesis, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, September 2008. Abstract:  The Internet&#39;s architecture, designed in the days of large, stationary computers tended by technically savvy and accountable administrators, fails to meet the demands of the emerging ubiquitous computing era. Nontechnical users now routinely own multiple personal devices, many of them mobile, and need to share information securely among them using interactive, delay-sensitive applications.  Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) is a novel, incrementally deployable network architecture for modern personal devices, which reconsiders three architectural cornerstones: naming, routing, and transport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vx32: Lightweight User-level Sandboxing on the x86</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/vx32-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/vx32-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Russ Cox
Massachusetts Institute of Technology USENIX Annual Technical Conference
Awarded Best Student Paper
June 22-27, 2008, Boston, Massachusetts. Abstract:  Code sandboxing is useful for many purposes, but most sandboxing techniques require kernel modifications, do not completely isolate guest code, or incur substantial performance costs. Vx32 is a multipurpose user-level sandbox that enables any application to load and safely execute one or more guest plug-ins, confining each guest to a system call API controlled by the host application and to a restricted memory region within the host&amp;rsquo;s address space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Offline Foundation for Online Accountable Pseudonyms</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Jacob Strauss 
Massachusetts Institute of Technology First Workshop on Social Network Systems
April 1, 2008 Abstract:  Online anonymity often appears to undermine accountability, offering little incentive for civil behavior, but accountability failures usually result not from anonymity itself but from the disposability of virtual identities. A user banned for misbehavior&amp;mdash;e.g., spamming from a free E-mail account or stuffing an online ballot box&amp;mdash;can simply open other accounts or connect from other IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured Streams: a New Transport Abstraction</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/sst-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/sst-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Massachusetts Institute of Technology Published in ACM SIGCOMM 2007, August 27-31, 2007, Kyoto, Japan. Abstract:  Internet applications currently have a choice between stream and datagram transport abstractions. Datagrams efficiently support small transactions and streams are suited for long-running conversations, but neither abstraction adequately supports applications like HTTP that exhibit a mixture of transaction sizes, or applications like FTP and SIP that use multiple transport instances. Structured Stream Transport (SST) enhances the traditional stream abstraction with a hierarchical hereditary structure, allowing applications to create lightweight child streams from any existing stream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent Personal Names for Globally Connected Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, Robert Morris
 Massachusetts Institute of Technology 7th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation
November 6-8, 2006 Abstract:  The  Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) provides zero-configuration connectivity among mobile devices through personal names. Users assign personal names through an ad hoc device introduction process requiring no central allocation. Once assigned, names bind securely to the global identities of their target devices independent of network location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User-Relative Names for Globally Connected Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-iptps-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-iptps-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, and Robert Morris Massachusetts Institute of Technology   5th International Workshop on Peer-to-Peer Systems
February 27-28, 2006  Abstract The User Information Architecture, or UIA, is a peer-to-peer connectivity architecture that provides users a simple, intuitive, and secure way to share information and services between personal devices by assigning ad hoc names that act like &amp;ldquo;virtual cables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VXA: A Virtual Architecture for Durable Compressed Archives</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/vxa-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/vxa-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Massachusetts Institute of Technology 4th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies (FAST &#39;05)
December 16, 2005, San Francisco, California, USA. Abstract:  Data compression algorithms change frequently, and obsolete decoders do not always run on new hardware and operating systems, threatening the long-term usability of content archived using those algorithms. Re-encoding content into new formats is cumbersome, and highly undesirable when lossy compression is involved. Processor architectures, in contrast, have remained comparatively stable over recent decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flux OSKit: A Substrate for Kernel and Language Research</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/oskit-sosp16-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/oskit-sosp16-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Godmar Back, Greg Benson, Jay Lepreau, Albert Lin, and Olin Shivers 
 Proceedings of the 16th ACM Symposium on Operating System Principles
October 5-8, 1997 Abstract:  Implementing new operating systems is tedious, costly, and often impractical except for large projects. The Flux OSKit addresses this problem in a novel way by providing clean, well-documented OS components designed to be reused in a wide variety of other environments, rather than defining a new OS structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flux OS Toolkit: Reusable Components for OS Implementation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/oskit-hotos6-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/oskit-hotos6-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Kevin Van Maren, Jay Lepreau, Stephen Clawson, Bart Robinson, and Jeff Turner
University of Utah 6th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS-VI)
May 5-6, 1997 Abstract:  To an unappreciated degree, research both in operating systems and their programming languages has been severely hampered by the lack of cleanly reusable code providing mundane low-level OS infrastructure such as bootstrap code and device drivers. The Flux OS Toolkit solves this problem by providing a set of clean, well-documented components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microkernels Meet Recursive Virtual Machines</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/fluke-rvm-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 1996 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/fluke-rvm-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Mike Hibler, Jay Lepreau, Patrick Tullmann, Godmar Back, and Stephen Clawson
University of Utah USENIX 2nd Symposium on OS Design and Implementation (OSDI &#39;96)
October 28-31, 1996, Seattle, Washington, USA. Abstract:  This paper describes a novel approach to providing modular and extensible operating system functionality and encapsulated environments based on a synthesis of microkernel and virtual machine concepts. We have developed a software-based virtualizable architecture called Fluke that allows recursive virtual machines (virtual machines running on other virtual machines) to be implemented efficiently by a microkernel running on generic hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Persistent Relevance of the Local Operating System to Global Applications</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/dist-vs-local-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 1996 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/dist-vs-local-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jay Lepreau, Bryan Ford, and Mike Hibler  Department of Computer Science, University of Utah  Proceedings of the Seventh ACM SIGOPS European Workshop
September 9-11, 1996  Abstract: The growth and popularity of loosely-coupled distributed systems such as the World Wide Web and the touting of Java-based systems as the solution to the issues of software maintenance, flexibility, and security are changing the research emphasis away from traditional single node operating system issues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>