<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Democracy on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Democracy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Democracy on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Democracy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Remote Voting Minefield: from North Carolina to Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/02/22/voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/02/22/voting/</guid>
      <description>The absentee ballot fraud in North Carolina shows how current vote-by-mail methods are fundamentally flawed and vulnerable to vote-buying and coercion. But banning remote voting of any kind would disenfranchise everyone not living in their country of citizenship; that is not a real option.
It is important to understand in this light the context of the Swiss e-voting project, one of whose two implementations was recently opened to public inspection by the Swiss Post for inspection and analysis by international experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Governs Us. Will it Govern Us Well?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2017/06/23/turing50/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2017/06/23/turing50/</guid>
      <description>*This blog post is a transcript of my opening remarks on the panel &#34;Restoring Personal Privacy without Compromising National Security&#34; at the [50 Years of the ACM Turing Award Celebration](https://www.acm.org/turing-award-50/conference).*   We now live in a world in which the rules coded into the technology we use plays as important a role in governing our lives as the formal laws written in the public law books. Code is law already, for better or worse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof-of-Personhood: Redemocratizing Permissionless Cryptocurrencies</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</guid>
      <description>Maria Borge, Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Philipp Jovanovic, Linus Gasser, Nicolas Gailly, and Bryan Ford
EPFL   IEEE Security &amp; Privacy on the Blockchain (IEEE S&amp;B)
April 29, 2017 Abstract: Permissionless blockchain-based cryptocurrencies commonly use proof-of-work (PoW) or proof-of-stake (PoS) to ensure their security, e.g. to prevent double spending attacks. However, both approaches have disadvantages: PoW leads to massive amounts of wasted electricity and re-centralization, whereas major stakeholders in PoS might be able to create a monopoly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegative Democracy Revisited</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2014/11/16/deleg.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2014/11/16/deleg.html</guid>
      <description>Over a decade ago I wrote up some ideas I called &amp;ldquo;Delegative Democracy,&amp;rdquo; which has also become known as &amp;ldquo;Liquid Democracy.&amp;rdquo; My draft paper from 2002 took a first stab at laying out the general idea, though I never finished or tried to publish it. Since a lot has happened in this space since then, and I get regular inquiries about it, I thought it was high time to revisit the idea and review more recent developments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Offline Foundation for Online Accountable Pseudonyms</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Jacob Strauss 
Massachusetts Institute of Technology First Workshop on Social Network Systems
April 1, 2008 Abstract:  Online anonymity often appears to undermine accountability, offering little incentive for civil behavior, but accountability failures usually result not from anonymity itself but from the disposability of virtual identities. A user banned for misbehavior&amp;mdash;e.g., spamming from a free E-mail account or stuffing an online ballot box&amp;mdash;can simply open other accounts or connect from other IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual Representation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2004/11/23/indrep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2004/11/23/indrep/</guid>
      <description>Real Choice for Voters, Democratic Currency for Activists Introduction The traditional purpose of popular elections is primarily to elect candidates to government offices or legislative seats, but this is not the only way we could use elections to facilitate democracy. Individual Representation, or indrep, provides a new and different reason to hold popular elections: as a tool for directly promoting the growth of grassroots social and political relationships throughout the basic fabric of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiki Democracy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2004/08/16/wiki-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2004/08/16/wiki-democracy/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegative Voting</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2002/10/21/deleg-voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2002/10/21/deleg-voting/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegative Democracy</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2002/05/15/deleg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2002/05/15/deleg/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>