<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anonymity on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Anonymity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anonymity on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Anonymity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrity and Metadata Protection in Data Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2021-nikitin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2021-nikitin/</guid>
      <description>Kirill Nikitin  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
November 26, 2021  Abstract: Secure retrieval of data requires integrity, confidentially, transparency, and metadata-privacy of the process. Existing protection mechanisms, however, provide only partially these properties: encryption schemes still expose cleartext metadata, protocols for private information retrieval neglect data integrity, and data-distribution architectures forego transparency. In this dissertation, by designing new cryptographic primitives and security architectures that provide a more comprehensive protection, we improve on the current security and privacy practices in data retrieval.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing and Protecting Communication Metadata</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2021-barman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2021-barman/</guid>
      <description>Ludovic Barman  Ph.D. thesis advised by Jean-Pierre Hubaux and Bryan Ford
September 17, 2021  Abstract:  Most communication systems (e.g., e-mails, instant messengers, VPNs) use encryption to prevent third parties from learning sensitive information. However, encrypted communications protect the contents but often leak metadata: the amount of data sent and the time it was sent, the way the data should be decrypted, the identity of the sender and the recipient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PriFi: Low-Latency Anonymity for Organizational Networks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/prifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/prifi/</guid>
      <description>Ludovic Barman, Italo Dacosta, Mahdi Zamani, Ennan Zhai, Apostolos Pyrgelis, Bryan Ford, Jean-Pierre Hubaux, and Joan Feigenbaum   Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium
July 13, 2020  Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
Volume 2020, Issue 4.  Abstract: Organizational networks are vulnerable to traffic-analysis attacks that enable adversaries to infer sensitive information from the network traffic &amp;ndash; even if encryption is used. Typical anonymous communication networks are tailored to the Internet and are poorly suited for organizational networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MorphIT: Morphing Packet Reports for Internet Transparency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/morphit-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/morphit-abs/</guid>
      <description>Georgia Fragkouli, Katerina Argyraki, and Bryan Ford EPFL Winner of Applied Networking Research Prize (ANRP)  Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
May 4, 2019. Abstract: Can we improve Internet transparency without worsening user anonymity? For a long time, researchers have been proposing transparency systems, where traffic reports produced at strategic network points help assess network behavior and verify service-level agreements or neutrality compliance. However, such reports necessarily reveal when certain traffic appeared at a certain network point, and this information could, in principle, be used to compromise low-latency anonymity networks like Tor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom: Horizontally Scaling Strong Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/atom-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/atom-abs/</guid>
      <description>Albert Kwon
MIT  Henry Corrigan-Gibbs
Stanford  Srinivas Devadas
MIT  Bryan Ford
EPFL    26th ACM Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP)
October 30, 2017 Abstract: Atom is an anonymous messaging system that protects against traffic-analysis attacks. Unlike many prior systems, each Atom server touches only a small fraction of the total messages routed through the network. As a result, the system’s capacity scales near-linearly with the number of servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof-of-Personhood: Redemocratizing Permissionless Cryptocurrencies</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</guid>
      <description>Maria Borge, Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Philipp Jovanovic, Linus Gasser, Nicolas Gailly, and Bryan Ford
EPFL   IEEE Security &amp; Privacy on the Blockchain (IEEE S&amp;B)
April 29, 2017 Abstract: Permissionless blockchain-based cryptocurrencies commonly use proof-of-work (PoW) or proof-of-stake (PoS) to ensure their security, e.g. to prevent double spending attacks. However, both approaches have disadvantages: PoW leads to massive amounts of wasted electricity and re-centralization, whereas major stakeholders in PoS might be able to create a monopoly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-Preserving Lawful Contact Chaining</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/contact-chaining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/contact-chaining/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riffle: An Efficient Communication System With Strong Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/riffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/riffle/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AnonRep: Towards Tracking-Resistant Anonymous Reputation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Privacy-Preserving Cryptographic Credentials from Federated Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book-codaspy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book-codaspy/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s verify real people, not real names.</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2015/10/07/names.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2015/10/07/names.html</guid>
      <description>On Monday the EFF, together with a &amp;ldquo;Nameless Coalition&amp;rdquo; of like-minded groups, escalated the backlash against Facebook&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;real names&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;authentic identities&amp;rdquo; policy with an open letter urging Facebook to end this policy like Google Plus did last year. Facebook&amp;rsquo;s response cites concerns about pseudonyms helping to hide &amp;ldquo;terrorist organizations&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;school bullies&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;criminal behavior.&amp;rdquo;
While I support anonymity and have spent years working to strengthen it, terrorist fearmongering aside, Facebook is right that anonymity is often abused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Anonymity in an Internet Panopticon</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/panopticon-cacm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/panopticon-cacm/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identity Management through Privacy-Preserving Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-syta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-syta/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
August 11, 2015  Abstract:  Maintaining privacy on the Internet is increasingly difficult in this ever-connected world. In most cases, our online interactions are a highly personalized experience and require some form of identity verification, most commonly, logging into an account. Unfortunately, people frequently give away a lot of information while obtaining accounts, reuse usernames and passwords across different services, or link their accounts to take advantage of single sign-on to avoid retyping passwords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Privacy-Preserving Cryptographic Credentials from Federated Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-maheswaran/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-maheswaran/</guid>
      <description>John Maheswaran  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
June 24, 2015  Abstract:  Third-party applications such as Quora or StackOverflow allow users to log in through a federated identity provider such as Facebook (Log in with Facebook), Google+ or Twitter. This process is called federated authentication. Examples of federated identity providers include social networks as well as other non-social network identity providers such as PayPal.  Federated identity providers have gained widespread popularity among users as a way to manage their online identity across the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching Bandits and Only Bandits: Privacy-Preserving Intersection Warrants for Lawful Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/bandits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/bandits/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing NymBoxes for Identity and Tracking Protection</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/nymboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/nymboxes/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Analysis of Accountable Anonymity in Dissent</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-analysis/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A TorPath to TorCoin: Proof-of-Bandwidth Altcoins for Compensating Relays</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/torcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/torcoin/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Onions to Shallots: Rewarding Tor Relays with TEARS</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/onions-to-shallots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/onions-to-shallots/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crypto-Book: An Architecture for Privacy Preserving Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conscript Your Friends into Larger Anonymity Sets with JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/conscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/conscript/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hang With Your Buddies to Resist Intersection Attacks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/buddies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/buddies/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proactively Accountable Anonymous Messaging in Verdict</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/verdict/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/verdict/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Latency in Tor Circuits with Unordered Delivery</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/tor-unordered/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/tor-unordered/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissent in Numbers: Making Strong Anonymity Scale</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-in-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-in-numbers/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scavenging for Anonymity with BlogDrop</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/blogdrop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/blogdrop/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faceless: Decentralized Anonymous Group Messaging for Online Social Networks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/faceless-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/faceless-abs/</guid>
      <description>Xiaoxiao Song, David Isaac Wolinsky, and Bryan Ford Yale University   5th Workshop on Social Network Systems
April 10, 2012  Abstract: Social networks (SNs) enable physically distributed groups to communicate seamlessly. Unfortunately such communi- cation can be easily mined by adversaries in attempts to breach users’ privacy or suppress open discussion on sensi- tive topics. While anonymous posting can help protect users by hiding the link between individuals and the messages they post, existing anonymization schemes are centralized or vul- nerable to well-known attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Anonymous Group Communication in the Anytrust Model</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/anytrust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/anytrust/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissent: Accountable Anonymous Group Messaging</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/dissent-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/dissent-abs/</guid>
      <description>Henry Corrigan-Gibbs and Bryan Ford Yale University Winner of ACM CCS Test-of-Time Award  17th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS 2010) October 4-8, 2010, Chicago, IL, USA Abstract:  Users often wish to participate in online groups anonymously, but misbehaving users may abuse this anonymity to disrupt the group&#39;s communication. Existing messaging protocols such as DC-nets leave groups vulnerable to denial-of-service and Sybil attacks, Mix-nets are difficult to protect against traffic analysis, and accountable voting protocols are unsuited to general anonymous messaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Offline Foundation for Online Accountable Pseudonyms</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Jacob Strauss 
Massachusetts Institute of Technology First Workshop on Social Network Systems
April 1, 2008 Abstract:  Online anonymity often appears to undermine accountability, offering little incentive for civil behavior, but accountability failures usually result not from anonymity itself but from the disposability of virtual identities. A user banned for misbehavior&amp;mdash;e.g., spamming from a free E-mail account or stuffing an online ballot box&amp;mdash;can simply open other accounts or connect from other IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sybil Parties: An Offline Foundation for Online Accountability</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/log/2006/0924-SybilParties.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/log/2006/0924-SybilParties.html</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford - September 24, 2006 Preliminary draft: see here for the final published paper  The Human Recognition Problem  Today&#39;s online ecosphere continually suffers from its inability to tell who is a genuine, unique human and who isn&#39;t. Because open-access messaging systems cannot isolate or authenticate the human source of messages for the purpose of suppressing abuses, spam has already relegated USENET to historical obscurity [Templeton01], threatens the usability of E-mail [Wouters05], and is even advancing on Skype.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
