<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Draft-rsses on Bryan Ford&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://bford.github.io/draft/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Draft-rsses on Bryan Ford&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bford.github.io/draft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure, Scalable Proof-of-Stake Blockchains</title>
      <link>https://bford.github.io/draft/stake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.github.io/draft/stake/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;proof-of-what&#34;&gt;Proof-of-What?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently-deployed permissionless blockchains
such as Bitcoin and Ethereum rely on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proof-of-work_system&#34;&gt;proof-of-work (PoW)&lt;/a&gt;
to distribute both the computational networking costs,
and the financial rewards,
of maintaining and extending the blockchain.
In proof-of-work systems, participating &lt;em&gt;miners&lt;/em&gt;
race (&amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo;) to compute solutions to cryptographic puzzles.
These puzzles effectively act like self-printed lottery tickets,
in that a miniscule fraction of these proof-of-work solutions
may be easily verified by anyone as &amp;ldquo;winning&amp;rdquo; the lucky miner
the right to add one block to the blockchain and collect associated rewards.
Proof-of-work has proven practical and relatively secure,
at least for cryptocurrencies with sufficient critical mass to deter
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cryptohustle.com/51-attack-crew-extorts-and-hijacks-blockchains-for-ransom&#34;&gt;ransom or hijacking by powerful attackers&lt;/a&gt;.
However, it has been
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pando.com/2013/12/16/bitcoin-has-a-dark-side-its-carbon-footprint/&#34;&gt;recognized for years&lt;/a&gt;
that proof-of-work blockchains are
&lt;a href=&#34;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/d3zn9a/ethereum-mining-transaction-electricity-consumption-bitcoin&#34;&gt;a tremendous waste of energy&lt;/a&gt;.
Recent estimates show that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://digiconomist.net/bitcoin-energy-consumption&#34;&gt;Bitcoin now consumes more energy than 60% of the world&amp;rsquo;s countries&lt;/a&gt;,
and that
&lt;a href=&#34;http://digiconomist.net/ethereum-energy-consumption&#34;&gt;Ethereum already consumes more energy
than Cyprus or Cambodia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motivated in part by this energy waste and its carbon footprint,
the cryptocurrency community has developed increasing interest
in alternative security foundations such as
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proof-of-stake&#34;&gt;proof-of-stake (PoS)&lt;/a&gt;.
The essence of this idea is to apportion consensus power
not according to energy wasted performing useless work,
but rather according to the amount of &amp;ldquo;stake&amp;rdquo;
that participants already hold in the system:
e.g., according to the number of coins they own.
The underlying principle is not unlike that of a traditional
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joint-stock_company&#34;&gt;joint-stock company&lt;/a&gt;,
in which voting power to affect a company&amp;rsquo;s decisions
(e.g., by electing board members who in turn choose executives)
is apportioned in proportion to shares of stock (&amp;ldquo;stake&amp;rdquo;)
held in the company.
The venerable underlying security principle is that stakeholders
have an interest in preserving and ideally increasing
the value of their stake &amp;ndash;
with bigger stakeholders having more to gain (or lose)
from good (or bad) decisions &amp;ndash;
thereby aligning their individual interests with those of the overall system.
While proof-of-stake conceptually represents
a sensible and promising alternative to proof-of-work,
&lt;em&gt;implementing&lt;/em&gt; proof-of-stake systems securely
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.sldx.com/whats-wrong-with-proof-of-stake-77d4f370be15&#34;&gt;is challenging&lt;/a&gt;,
due to many difficulties well-documented in
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bitfury.com/content/5-white-papers-research/pos-vs-pow-1.0.2.pdf&#34;&gt;a BitFury white paper&lt;/a&gt;
and elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-proof-of-investment-really-the-answer&#34;&gt;Is Proof-of-Investment Really the Answer?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proof-of-work and proof-of-stake are both
&lt;em&gt;investment-proportional&lt;/em&gt; security foundations,
in that they apportion consensus power and mining rewards
proportionally to prior investment
(in computational effort or coin purchases, respectively).
Many other alternatives such as
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proof-of-space&#34;&gt;proof of space&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dedis.cs.yale.edu/dissent/papers/hotpets14-torpath-abs&#34;&gt;proof of bandwidth&lt;/a&gt;,
and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eprint.iacr.org/2016/145.pdf&#34;&gt;proof of human work&lt;/a&gt;
similarly fit into the same broad category,
which might be accurately classified as &lt;em&gt;proof of investment&lt;/em&gt;.
In the long term,
I am skeptical that cryptocurrencies based on proof of investment
will fundamentally transform our society or economy for the better
(or at all really).
At the end of the day,
cryptocurrencies or
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decentralized_autonomous_organization&#34;&gt;decentralized autonomous organizations&lt;/a&gt;
based on proof of investment are merely a more-automated
functional equivalent to the stakeholder-driven joint-stock companies
that already dominate today&amp;rsquo;s global economy,
and hence are fundamentally nothing new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, proof-of-investment cryptocurrencies
may put more white-collar office workers out of work and hasten the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/brandlab/2015/04/rise-machines-future-lots-robots-jobs-humans/&#34;&gt;rise of the machines&lt;/a&gt;,
but will ultimately do little to address society&amp;rsquo;s fundamental challenges
such as
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2017/jan/11/inequality-world-economy-wef-brexit-donald-trump-world-economic-forum-risk-report&#34;&gt;rising economic inequality&lt;/a&gt;.
For that purpose, I see more promise in truly democratic alternatives
such as
&lt;a href=&#34;https://zerobyte.io/publications/2017-BKJGGF-pop.pdf&#34;&gt;proof-of-personhood&lt;/a&gt;
or
&lt;a href=&#34;http://proofofindividuality.online/&#34;&gt;proof-of-individuality&lt;/a&gt;,
which could create a sort of
&amp;ldquo;permissionless &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basic_income&#34;&gt;basic income&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ldquo;
by apportioning voting and consensus power and currency-mining rewards
to all &lt;em&gt;human&lt;/em&gt; participants, in a one-person-one-vote distribution.
But truly democratizing and decentralizing cryptocurrencies
will require solving many further challenges.
In the meantime, even if proof-of-stake achieves nothing but
ending the energy waste and environmental impact of proof-of-work,
that goal is easily worth pursuing.
And it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting technical challenge,
so the rest of this blog post will focus on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;will-the-one-true-blockchain-please-raise-your-hand&#34;&gt;Will the One True Blockchain Please Raise Your Hand?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;long-term-attacks&#34;&gt;Long-term Attacks&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selfish Mining in Bitcoin and ByzCoin</title>
      <link>https://bford.github.io/2016/xx/xx/selfish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.github.io/2016/xx/xx/selfish/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;XXX intro&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;summary of selfish mining&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;selfish mining as a transparency problem:
you get to build on a blockchain head you haven&amp;rsquo;t published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;same as transparency problem in Apple FBI case for example;
that&amp;rsquo;s what CoSi is for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;solution: any keyblock you build on is collectively signed,
and the next block&amp;rsquo;s hash covers the last block&amp;rsquo;s signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if you withhold a block, you can&amp;rsquo;t get a collective signature on it;
without that collective signature,
you can&amp;rsquo;t secretly mine a next block on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;selfish-mining&#34;&gt;Selfish Mining&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we consider the now much more well-understood problem of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://hackingdistributed.com/2013/11/04/bitcoin-is-broken/&#34;&gt;selfish mining&lt;/a&gt;.
A selfish miner strategically withholds some of its successfully mined blocks
in attempt to gain a higher share of mining rewards,
by causing other miners to waste effort mining redundant blocks.
For example, if Greedy Greg successfully mines a new block,
he might deliberately delay announcing it.
If Innocent Ivan announces a competing block,
Greg quickly races to announce and widely distribute his,
which may reliably overtake Ivan&amp;rsquo;s if Greg is fast and well-connected.
Alternatively, if Greg manages to mine a &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt; block in private
before a competing first block appears,
then Greg is in the enviable position of being able to &amp;ldquo;trump&amp;rdquo;
and eliminate that competing block once it does appear,
simply by revealing his longer private blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While ByzCoin&amp;rsquo;s keyblock mining mechanism alone is still
vulnerable to selfish mining,
its microblock commitment process using Byzantine consensus
provides a clean, simple defense against selfish mining.
Any transaction microblock the consensus group commits
contains a cryptographic hash of the latest known keyblock at the time,
and any newly-mined keyblock must similarly contain
a cryptographic hash of a recently-committed microblock
(e.g., within a few microblocks from the head).
Whenever the consensus group commits a new microblock,
all honest members verify that the keyblock pointer in the new microblock
is consistent with those in all prior microblocks,
ensuring that any new keyblock is &amp;ldquo;locked in&amp;rdquo;
irreversably once the new keyblock is known.
This leaves only seconds, rather than minutes,
in which a selfish miner could
try to announce and distribute a competing keyblock.
Further, because each keyblock must reference a recent microblock,
any newly-mined keyblock becomes invalid and useless
if its owner fails to announce it
within a few microblock commitment cycles &amp;mdash;
again, on the order of seconds rather than minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence, ByzCoin&amp;rsquo;s microblock commit mechanism
enforces transparency on the keyblock mining process,
ensuring that a selfish ByzCoin miner would likely be faced with
a vanishingly small probability of profiting from
any keyblock-withholding strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post of course represents only an informal,
and no doubt incomplete, analysis
of the differences in incentives between Bitcoin and ByzCoin,
focusing primarily on mining incentives.
It is quite possible that a full, rigorous incentive analysis of ByzCoin
may reveal new incentive-compatibility issues that its architecture introduces.
Further, ByzCoin is still an experimental protocol
under rapid development and evoluation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given these caveats, however,
ByzCoin&amp;rsquo;s architecture at least appears to be much more resilient
to the known strategic mining attacks against Bitcoin,
whether through block withholding or deliberate forking.
In particular,
by replacing Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s instant-gratification, winner-take-all reward model
with a delayed-gratification, investment-dividend model,
ByzCoin ensures that the distribution of mining profits are fixed
long before any strategic miner might know about or be able to respond to
the appearance of a goose egg or other transaction fee variance.
By ensuring that keyblocks and microblocks track each other cryptographically,
ByzCoin forces miners either to announce new keyblocks quickly
or else lose them,
making selfish mining unprofitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, it does not appear necessary for new cryptocurrencies to
&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://freedom-to-tinker.com/2016/10/21/bitcoin-is-unstable-without-the-block-reward/&#34;&gt;make the block reward permanent and accept monetary inflation
as inevitable&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;
as Narayanan suggests.
Whether inflationary or deflationary monetary policies are preferable
is an important and highly debatable question,
but it need not be constrained by technical weaknesses of Bitcoin.
With more sophisticated blockchain architectures such as ByzCoin,
there is plenty of hope that mining incentives can work
independent of monetary policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
---

*I wish to thank ...
for helpful feedback on early drafts of this post.*
--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An advanced crypto library for Go</title>
      <link>https://bford.github.io/2016/03/08/crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.github.io/2016/03/08/crypto/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;page-title&#34;&gt;{{ page.title }}&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;An abstract group arithmetic framework for public-key cryptography
based on the discrete logarithm problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several alternative concrete instantiations of this abstract
group arithmetic framework,
based on the NIST elliptic curve implementations in the Go standard library
and in the OpenSSL crypto library,
and implementations of both generic Edwards curves
and an adaptation of Adam Langley&amp;rsquo;s Ed25519-curve-specific
optimized group arithmetic code to the abstract group API.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Implementations of a number of advanced crypto algorithms
built on this abstract group arithmetic framework,
and hence automatically compatible woth both integer group
and any suitable elliptic curves:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shamir Verifiable Secret Sharing (VSS),
the standard foundation for t-of-n threshold cryptographic techniques.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;An implementation of the general Camenisch/Stadler framework
for proofs of knowledge based on the discrete-logarithm problem.
For example&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anonymous and pseudonymous public-key encryption and signatures,
where the sender or receiver are identified only as an anonymous member
of some explicit &lt;em&gt;set&lt;/em&gt; of public keys, without revealing anything
about which member of the set signed the message or is to receive it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;C. Andrew Neff&amp;rsquo;s cryptographic protocol for proving
the correctness of a shuffle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backdoors, Trusted Servers, and Deanonymization</title>
      <link>https://bford.github.io/2016/03/08/backdoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.github.io/2016/03/08/backdoors/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;page-title&#34;&gt;{{ page.title }}&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my knowledge there are currently only two fundamentally distinct approaches
to achieving strong anonymity online,
and the same legendary computing figure, David Chaum,
pioneered both.
His first approach,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freehaven.net/anonbib/cache/chaum-mix.pdf&#34;&gt;mixes&lt;/a&gt;,
relay messages over multi-hop paths around the network
to obscure their source and destinations.
State-of-the-art deployed anonymity systems such as
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt;
are highly evolved and performance-optimized variants
of this basic relaying idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chaum&amp;rsquo;s second approach,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freehaven.net/anonbib/cache/chaum-dc.pdf&#34;&gt;dining cryptographers&lt;/a&gt;,
instead uses information-coding principles to hide the sender of a message
among a group of nodes all of whom seem to be spewing gibberish at once.
It&amp;rsquo;s as if you are listening to a crowd
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.christianpublishers.org/Speaking%20in%20Tongues-1.jpg&#34;&gt;speaking in tongues&lt;/a&gt;
but what you hear is a single unified voice,
emanating from no one in particular,
elucidating the Ten Commandments with perfect clarity.
Chaum then moved away from anonymity systems
to other projects such as the first major attempt at practical electronic cash
(yes, he was also the &amp;ldquo;first&amp;rdquo; Satoshi Nakamoto),
and secure electronic voting systems.
While several research projects,
including Cornell&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.cornell.edu/people/egs/herbivore/&#34;&gt;Herbivore&lt;/a&gt;
and my own
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dedis.cs.yale.edu/dissent/&#34;&gt;Dissent&lt;/a&gt;
have made progress toward making the dining cryptographers practical,
it has not (yet) made it into widely-deployed systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given Chaum&amp;rsquo;s status as &amp;ldquo;the father of online anonymity&amp;rdquo;,
it stands to reason
that his first venture &lt;em&gt;back&lt;/em&gt; into anonymity in many years
would get some attention.
Today at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.realworldcrypto.com/rwc2016&#34;&gt;Real World Crypto&lt;/a&gt;,
he presented
&lt;a href=&#34;http://eprint.iacr.org/2016/008.pdf&#34;&gt;cMix&lt;/a&gt;,
an interesting new take on the mix approach
that aims to achieve better scalability, lower latencies,
and sufficiently low computation costs on client devices
to be practical for use in energy-conscious mobile phone apps.
I had the pleasure of learning about cMix directly from David
and discussing it with him at some length last year,
but my recent move to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.epfl.ch/&#34;&gt;EPFL&lt;/a&gt; and other time demands
prevented me from being able to take a more active role in the project.
The design of cMix is definitely interesting and contains some promising ideas,
but that is not what this blog post is about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ending-the-crypto-war-or-stoking-the-flames&#34;&gt;Ending the Crypto War, or Stoking the Flames?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier today before Chaum&amp;rsquo;s talk, Wired also released
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/2016/01/david-chaum-father-of-online-anonymity-plan-to-end-the-crypto-wars/&#34;&gt;an article on it&lt;/a&gt;
containing a statement that will doubtless attract
a lot more attention than anything in the technical paper on cMix:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Chaum is also building into PrivaTegrity another feature that’s sure to be far more controversial: a carefully controlled backdoor that allows anyone doing something “generally recognized as evil” to have their anonymity and privacy stripped altogether.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well before Chaum&amp;rsquo;s talk even began,
Twitter was ablaze with discussion about Chaum&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;backdoor&amp;rdquo; in PrivaTegrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;The main benefit of Chaum&amp;#39;s new system, as far as I can tell, is that it is a political gift to FBI Director Comey. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/64Au0lXxuL&#34;&gt;https://t.co/64Au0lXxuL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Christopher Soghoian (@csoghoian) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/csoghoian/status/684730483503149056&#34;&gt;January 6, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I&amp;#39;m heartbroken to see that Chaum is proposing key escrow for everyone on the planet: &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/zWZ3bUQsJf&#34;&gt;https://t.co/zWZ3bUQsJf&lt;/a&gt; What happened to David Chaum?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jacob Appelbaum (@ioerror) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ioerror/status/684763375260270592&#34;&gt;January 6, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;but-where-s-the-backdoor&#34;&gt;But Where&amp;rsquo;s the Backdoor?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One important observation, however, is that the word &amp;ldquo;backdoor&amp;rdquo;
appears nowhere in the actual
&lt;a href=&#34;http://eprint.iacr.org/2016/008.pdf&#34;&gt;technical paper on cMix&lt;/a&gt; written by
Chaum and his collaborators.
While cMix is the anonymous communication protocol Chaum is proposing,
PrivaTegrity is a larger system built on cMix
to provide anonymous chat and other anonymous interaction applications
directly usable to ordinary users.
In essence, cMix is just an &amp;ldquo;engine&amp;rdquo; whereas PrivaTegrity is the car.
So where is this supposed &amp;ldquo;backdoor&amp;rdquo; &amp;emdash; in the engine or the car?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only part of the technical cMix paper that even suggests
the &amp;ldquo;backdoor&amp;rdquo; idea (without using that term)
is section IX.B., two brief paragraphs on the paper&amp;rsquo;s second-to-last page.
The first is the most crucial:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Independent from cMix, PrivaTegrity addresses potential
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;abuse of anonymity services by establishing a trust model
that offers a balance of anonymity and accountability. On the
one hand, PrivaTegrity aims to provide privacy at a technical
level that is not penetrable by nation states. On the other
hand, PrivaTegrity aims to provide integrity, both prior restraint
and accountability after the fact, that is inescapably tied to
individuals. Only if all of the mixing nodes cooperate, can the
senders and receivers of messages be linked or identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence, cMix routes users&amp;rsquo; messages through a series of mixing nodes
(the Wired article talks about nine servers in different countries),
such that none of the servers can individually unmask an anonymous user,
but all of the servers (or their operators) together can unmask a user
that they collectively agree to be deserving of such treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This property is by no means new, unusual, or unique to cMix, however:
in fact a huge number of cryptographic and distributed systems
have this essential security property.
No one really knows how to build secure systems
in which you need to trust &lt;em&gt;no one at all&lt;/em&gt;.
Instead the best we can really do is to &lt;em&gt;split&lt;/em&gt; trust across multiple entities
that we hope are at least somewhat independent,
so that no one entity needs to be fully trusted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is exactly the same security principle that motivates
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deansafe.com/uncodrsawisa.html&#34;&gt;safes with two keys&lt;/a&gt;.
If both keys are required to open the safe and are held by different employees,
then a single dishonest employee working alone will be unable to raid it
without somehow aquiring the other key.
But if the two key-holders conspire,
the two-key mechanism will do nothing to stop them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;trust-splitting-in-anonymity-systems&#34;&gt;Trust Splitting in Anonymity Systems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially all of the practical anonymity systems,
both deployed and proposed in research,
embody this limited trust-splitting property in some fashion.
Several years ago my group
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dedis.cs.yale.edu/dissent/papers/eurosec12-abs&#34;&gt;coined the term &amp;ldquo;anytrust&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;
for this security model in the context of anonymity systems,
because users need only assume that &amp;ldquo;any one&amp;rdquo; of the servers is honest
and not colluding with all the others against them.
Users don&amp;rsquo;t even need to know or guess which server is honest;
one merely &lt;em&gt;needs to exist&lt;/em&gt;.
Once again, we did not by any means invent this security model;
it has been in use in many ways and under many names for decades
in cryptography and distributed systems practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users of the well-known &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt; anonymity system,
for example,
depend for their security on a small group of
&lt;em&gt;directory authorities&lt;/em&gt; &amp;emdash;
of which &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kristovatlas/status/684845884576796673&#34;&gt;there are currently 10&lt;/a&gt; &amp;emdash;
to keep track of and let Tor clients know the set of relays
available to help anonymize their messages.
If &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PrivaTegrity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;is Chaum&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;backdoor&amp;rdquo; a technical feature?
no, just a common architectural weakness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tor has it&amp;hellip; (examples)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we eliminate such trusted server groups?  Yes, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does CT fix it?  Not quite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The policy question: are backdoors needed/good in an anonymity systems?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would the processes be for controlled deanonymization of a user,
supposing one created a system and set it up like Chaum&amp;rsquo;s
on the (policy) basis that server operators would cooperate
to deanonymize users under &amp;ldquo;the right conditions&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;who picks those 9 server operators?  Who funds them?
(The power of the purse is strong&amp;hellip;)
If a nation-state comes to them and says,
&amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;ll block your service and thus destroy a big part of your legal business
unless you help us deanonymize these people who we call &amp;lsquo;terrorists&amp;rsquo;
but the rest of the world calls &amp;lsquo;political dissidents&amp;rsquo;&amp;ldquo;,
what do they do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sybil problem, multiple possible levels of response&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to prove DNSSEC isn&#39;t a key escrow scheme</title>
      <link>https://bford.github.io/2016/03/08/dnssec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.github.io/2016/03/08/dnssec/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;page-title&#34;&gt;{{ page.title }}&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bford.github.io/draft/async/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.github.io/draft/async/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For another thing, I’m personally not a big believer in the practical value of the asynchronous model anyway.  I know I’m at odds here with most people with a theory/algorithms background; reasonable people may differ. :)  Almost every practical distributed system that ever actually gets deployed has timeouts and such buried in it here, there, everywhere.  User-experience expectations are synchronous, not asynchronous: even if the underlying protocol is in principle perfectly capable of tolerating arbitrarily-long adversary-controlled propagation delays among honest nodes, the real users relying on the system are going to start complaining rather soon after the expected/normal amount of transaction time elapses.  And in environments where we’re truly exposed to hugely-varying latencies and actually need to adapt to them - such as delay-tolerant or interplanetary networking scenarios - then asynchronous consensus protocols and the like are never useful in practice there either because they slow &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; down to the least-common denominator: e.g., if &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; of the participants in an async BFT protocol are on Mars, then everyone’s transactions everywhere must necessarily slow down to account for the Mars-Earth latency, which no one doing transactions only on Earth (or only on Mars) will accept.  The only real, practical solution to those kinds of problems are locality-preserving approaches such as Cristina’s Crux project (&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1405.0637&#34;&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/1405.0637&lt;/a&gt;), which of course is a whole different ball game.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Social Media to Escape the Echo Chamber</title>
      <link>https://bford.github.io/2016/11/13/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.github.io/2016/11/13/info/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hillary Clinton&amp;rsquo;s [electoral college defeat]()
has provoked many questions about how so many Americans
could have choosen a
[misogynistic](),
[xenophobic](),
[pathologically lying](),
[authoritarian]()
[ideologue]()
as their next President &amp;ndash;
and one of many targets of their blame is
[social media]().
Compounding its
[polarizing &amp;ldquo;echo chamber&amp;rdquo; effect](),
online discussions were tarnished with
[deliberate misinformation](),
including
[incorrect instructions on how to vote]().
But is the solution for social media companies like Facebook
to ``do a better job&amp;rdquo; at curating the world&amp;rsquo;s content
to suppress out false or hateful speech?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asking technology companies
to serve as the world&amp;rsquo;s arbiters of truth and civility
is not only counterproductive but
just as profoundly dangerous as the social maladies
that social media creates or exacerbates.
We need to rethink social media from the ground up
to make it &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; open and transparent, not less &amp;ndash;
and most importantly, to infuse online debate with
some semblance of democratic legitimacy.
The purpose of this blog post is not to dwell on
[the many flaws of social media]()
but to explore how we could get it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would an ethical, secure, and democratic alternative
to either conventional ``elitist&amp;rdquo; media
or the polarizing echo chamber of social media look like?
It would need to be built on a foundation of equality among
all &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; people;
it would ensure &lt;em&gt;proportional&lt;/em&gt; speech and accurately expose biases;
it would counteract polarization by ensuring that
all participants are exposed to all viewpoints;
and it would provide strong but proportionate and abuse-resistant
protections for anonymity and free speech &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the ballot box,
in order to head off unpleasant surprises being revealed
only &lt;em&gt;at&lt;/em&gt; the ballot box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;foundation-the-equality-of-real-people&#34;&gt;Foundation: The Equality of &lt;em&gt;Real&lt;/em&gt; People&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a story or claim appears with 1,000 ``likes&amp;rdquo;,
how do we know whether 1,000 &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; people liked the story,
or only one real troll and his 999 [sock puppet accounts]()?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean all people are equally smart, equally capable, equally right,
or should end up having equal power or influence &lt;em&gt;in the end&lt;/em&gt;.
It means all people should be given an equal &lt;em&gt;starting point&lt;/em&gt;
in apportioning power,
and be free to ``become unequal&amp;rdquo; as their words and actions
are subject to the review of their peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need to be able to quantify the number of people&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need a mechanism to ensure that these are &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; people we are counting,
not fake accounts created
by whoever has the most time, money, or determination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content-based analysis versus account validation.
Content-based analysis [has often proven successful](),
but relies on complex algorithms that &lt;em&gt;someone&lt;/em&gt; must keep updating
(and making still more complex)
to keep up with the ``arms race&amp;rdquo;,
as attackers develop more sophisticated algorithms
to farm fake accounts that remain under the detection radar.
Relying on complex algorithms that need to adapt constantly
creates inherent risks that they will become opaque and vulnerable
to accidental bias or deliberate attacks,
such as the secret inclusion of &amp;ldquo;back doors&amp;rdquo; that produces false positives
designed to close the accounts of and hence disenfranchise populations
disfavored by the attacker.
While I believe content-based analysis plays an important scientific role,
it is unsuitable as a &lt;em&gt;foundation&lt;/em&gt; for ensuring the equality of real people
in online public discourse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;proportional-speech-and-bias-transparency&#34;&gt;Proportional Speech and Bias Transparency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need an objective way to avoid bias,
or clearly and quantitatively expose it when it exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;like wearing blinders&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pressuring Mark Zuckerberg to deploy Facebook&amp;rsquo;s minions
to do a better job of censoring fake or misleading social media posts
does not solve the problem,
but instead shifts the power to decide between ultimate truth and falsehood
to precisely the place it does not belong:
to the anonymous employees and proprietary algorithms
of corporations that are accountable to no one but their shareholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All relevant algorithms need to be public and accountable.
Algorithms need to be as simple as possible
[but no simpler]():
in particular, not so simplistic as to ignore the many lessons
from past failures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fake or misleading claim on social media,
as soon as it starts collecting nontrivial interest,
needs to become inextricably attached to the counter-claims that debunk it.
These counter-claims must prominently include
accurate, quantitative evidence that the debunking experts are trustworthy
and not &lt;a href=&#34;Ebell guy&#34;&gt;paid lobbyists masquerading as scientists&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash;
together with accurate quantitative measures of the number of people
(&lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; people) who support the false statement despite its being debunked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;depolarizing-echo-chambers-with-soft-focus-feeds&#34;&gt;Depolarizing Echo Chambers with Soft-Focus Feeds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even when people are willing to hear viewpoints they don&amp;rsquo;t like,
there is a matter of scalability:
everyone simply does not have time to listen to everything everyone else says.
Speech needs to be filtered or summarized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;anonymity-and-free-speech-before-the-ballot-box&#34;&gt;Anonymity and Free Speech &lt;em&gt;Before&lt;/em&gt; the Ballot Box&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;one of many explanations, possibly contributing but probably not only factor&amp;hellip;
other explanations include
[normal polling errors](),
[hacking of the election system](),
[the FBI](), &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some Trump supporters are certainly racist and xenophobic;
most of them are probably not,
but voted Trump for other reasons.
In order to protect our civilization,
we the people need to be fully aware of size and malignancy of
any malignancy affecting it:
you do not beat a cancerous tumor by ignoring it
or sanitizing the doctor&amp;rsquo;s diagnosis.
We need &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; the true, complex set of reasons that
people are inclined to support someone like Trump&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need regular opportunities for speech
ensuring that &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; voices are represented,
and [building anger over policies]()
actually have [a chance to influence policy]()
before that anger
explodes in a self-defeating electoral choice
of an [authoritarian]() [con-artist]()
and [places freedom and democracy in existential risk]().&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;incentives-who-will-finance-a-decentralized-social-forum&#34;&gt;Incentives: Who Will Finance a Decentralized Social Forum?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--
---

*I wish to thank ...
for helpful feedback on early drafts of this post.*
--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So They&#39;re Selling You a Blockchain</title>
      <link>https://bford.github.io/2018/xx/xx/blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.github.io/2018/xx/xx/blockchain/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I think blockchain has a lot of potential,
but it is also still a very immature area of technology.
There is a lot of noise and confusion about what it is
and what properties specific blockchains do and don&amp;rsquo;t provide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blockchain-architecture-questions&#34;&gt;Blockchain Architecture Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;has-the-technical-architecture-and-design-been-validated-through-peer-review-in-independently-peer-reviewed-publication-venues&#34;&gt;Has the technical architecture and design been validated through peer review in independently peer-reviewed publication venues?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which venues, and how reputable and selective are they?
(For reference,
the top systems venues are
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sigops.org/sosp/sosp17/&#34;&gt;SOSP&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/conference/osdi18&#34;&gt;OSDI&lt;/a&gt;,
the top security/privacy venues are
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ieee-security.org/TC/SP2018/&#34;&gt;IEEE Security &amp;amp; Privacy&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity17&#34;&gt;USENIX Security&lt;/a&gt;, and
the top cryptography venue is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://crypto.iacr.org/&#34;&gt;CRYPTO&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-runs-consensus-nodes-in-the-blockchain-architecture-and-how-is-membership-decided&#34;&gt;Who runs consensus nodes in the blockchain architecture, and how is membership decided?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is the blockchain open to anyone (permissionless)
or run among a fixed set of participants (permissioned)?
What is the process for adding or removing members,
and how is that process secured?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-is-the-consensus-group-membership-governed-organizationally-and-technically&#34;&gt;How is the consensus group membership governed, organizationally and technically?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who decides when and how to deploy blockchain upgrades
that might not be backward-compatible, thus requiring a hard-fork?
How are software update roll-outs managed and secured?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-decentralized-will-the-intended-deployment-be-in-practice&#34;&gt;How decentralized will the intended deployment be in practice?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many independent organizations will be expected to run consensus nodes,
initially and in the long term?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;does-the-architecture-rely-on-energy-intensive-proof-of-work-mining&#34;&gt;Does the architecture rely on energy-intensive proof-of-work mining?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who deploys and operates the mining nodes?
What are the energy and environmental costs of this mining,
and are the trends sustainable?
How decentralized is the distribution of mining power:
e.g., how many of the largest miners or pools would need to collude
to execute a 51% attack, or a 33% attack, on the blockchain?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;security-and-robustness-questions&#34;&gt;Security and Robustness Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;does-the-system-have-an-open-independent-security-and-privacy-review-and-analysis&#34;&gt;Does the system have an open, independent security and privacy review and analysis?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If so, where may that independent security/privacy analysis be found?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;does-the-blockchain-system-implement-true-byzantine-consensus&#34;&gt;Does the blockchain system implement true Byzantine consensus?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is the consensus scheme fully robust not just to failed (crashed)
but also fully-compromised (hacked, adversarial) consensus group participants?
Or does the system rely on non-Byzantine consensus algorithms like Paxos
that assume all parties are well-behaved and cannot ensure integrity
if even just one participant is compromised?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
### What is the smallest number or fraction of independent organizations holding enough consensus power to compromise the blockchain?
(see arewedecentralizedyet)
could be through rewriting history, double-spending,
quietly censoring transactions to deny service to a competitor,
creating a prive fake blockchain to show to just one victim
during a high-value transaction, etc.
--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-many-compromised-participants-can-the-consensus-protocol-tolerate&#34;&gt;How many compromised participants can the consensus protocol tolerate?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What number or percentage of consensus group members participants
can be fully compromised (e.g., hacked, colluding, or under adversarial control)
without compromising the integrity of the blockchain
or the confidentiality of the deta entrusted to it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;are-there-single-points-of-failure-or-compromise-outside-of-consensus&#34;&gt;Are there single points of failure or compromise outside of consensus?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:
Does the system depend on a centralized Certificate Authority (CA)
for naming and membership, which if compromised could allow the attacker
to impersonate any and all of the blockchain participants simultaneously?
Does the system rely on centralized &amp;ldquo;oracles&amp;rdquo;
to obtain and report information from the outside world
that smart contracts might need to depend on,
such that smart contracts can be misled if that oracle service is hacked?
Does the system rely on centralized off-chain data- or key-storage services
to ensure the confidentiality of data or encryption keys
entrusted to the blockchain,
such that the compromise of that storage service could make
all the stored data and/or keys readable and decryptable in bulk
by an attacker without necessarily leaving access records on the blockchain?
Does the system rely on a centralized cloud-based
login, control, and provisioning services that,
if compromised, could enable an attacker to gain control of
most or all of the blockchain nodes at once?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-can-i-know-the-blockchain-will-be-available-and-have-adequate-transaction-processing-capacity-when-my-business-needs-it&#34;&gt;How can I know the blockchain will be available and have adequate transaction processing capacity when my business needs it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the risks that the potentially-independent actions
of other parties using the blockchain innocently or deliberately
consuming enough resources to deny service or limit availability to my business&amp;rsquo;s needs,
as occurred in
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coindesk.com/ethereums-cryptokitties-blockchain-deluge-sparks-ico-delay/&#34;&gt;the Crypto-Kitties incident&lt;/a&gt;
for example?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-provisions-prevent-misbehaving-consensus-nodes-from-censoring-transactions&#34;&gt;What provisions prevent misbehaving consensus nodes from censoring transactions?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do relying parties (e.g., mobile apps accessing the blockchain)
maintain connections to multiple consensus nodes or just one,
which could be a single point of failure, compromise, or censorship?
How can relying parties detect and recover if their access attempts
are manipulated or censored?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;can-offline-or-poorly-connected-devices-securely-verify-blockchain-transactions&#34;&gt;Can offline or poorly-connected devices securely verify blockchain transactions?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do edge devices designed to scan and verify blockchain-secured credentials
become inoperative or insecure if they cannot connect to the consensus nodes?
Or can edge devices such as credential scanners
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bford.github.io/2017/08/01/skipchain/&#34;&gt;cryptographically verify transactions offline&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cost-related-questions&#34;&gt;Cost-related Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-the-financial-costs-of-blockchain-transactions-currently-and-historically&#34;&gt;What are the financial costs of blockchain transactions, currently and historically?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can I mitigate the risk that unexpected future
increases in transaction costs,
whether temporary or permanent,
could impose economically prohibitive costs to my blockchain-dependent business?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-the-energy-and-network-bandwidth-costs-to-resource-constrained-edge-devices-needing-to-interact-with-the-blockchain&#34;&gt;What are the energy and network bandwidth costs to resource-constrained edge devices needing to interact with the blockchain?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do resource-constrained edge devices or mobile apps
need to maintain connections and gossip with
multiple consensus group members, or with just one?
In the former case, what are the energy and bandwidth costs of this gossip?
In the latter case, can that one reference node, if compromised,
potentially censor the relying party&amp;rsquo;s access to the blockchain
or trick it into using
an &amp;ldquo;alternate-reality&amp;rdquo; blockchain inconsistent with the public one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;performance-and-scalability-questions&#34;&gt;Performance and Scalability Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-scalable-is-the-architecture-to-many-consensus-participants&#34;&gt;How scalable is the architecture to many consensus participants?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the maximum number of widely-distributed participants
for which the blockchain system has been validated and performance-tested?
Tens, hundreds, thousands, tens of thousands?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-long-does-it-take-to-commit-a-transaction-securely&#34;&gt;How long does it take to commit a transaction securely?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How are transaction latencies affected by consensus group size?
When can I be overwhelmingly certain that a transaction
can&amp;rsquo;t be reverted or rewritten after commitment?
Were these transaction latencies tested on a wide-area deployment
with global speed-of-light delays between consensus nodes,
or in a local-area environment where all participants are close together?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-the-system-s-maximum-demonstrated-transaction-throughput&#34;&gt;What is the system&amp;rsquo;s maximum demonstrated transaction throughput?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was this throughput demonstrated in a wide-area or local-area deployment?
What processing power and network bandwidth was required?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-the-system-s-maximum-transaction-throughput-depend-on&#34;&gt;What does the system&amp;rsquo;s maximum transaction throughput depend on?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can the system&amp;rsquo;s transaction-processing capacity scale gracefully
as more participants and hardware resources are added to the system
(e.g., via &lt;a href=&#34;http://bford.info/pub/dec/omniledger-abs&#34;&gt;sharding&lt;/a&gt;),
or is processing throughput limited to the slowest consensus group member?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;privacy-and-confidentiality-questions&#34;&gt;Privacy and Confidentiality Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-can-the-blockchain-handle-private-confidential-transaction-data&#34;&gt;How can the blockchain handle private, confidential transaction data?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do all the consensus group members see all transaction data,
or just the participants that are directly involved in a given transaction?
If confidential transaction data is encrypted,
how are the secret encryption keys managed, and who holds those keys?
Are the encryption keys held by a centralized party that, if compromised,
could leak confidential data in bulk to an attacker?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;can-the-blockchain-enforce-global-invariants-on-confidential-transaction-data&#34;&gt;Can the blockchain enforce global invariants on confidential transaction data?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the amounts of coin or token in a transaction are encrypted
and only known to the direct parties to the transaction, for example,
can those parties collude to create fake coins or tokens &amp;ldquo;out of thin air&amp;rdquo;
without the knowledge of the other validators or consensus group members?
Or can the system somehow ensure that &amp;ldquo;the books balance&amp;rdquo; globally
without revealing transaction amounts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;can-the-blockchain-hide-data-that-smart-contracts-depend-on&#34;&gt;Can the blockchain hide data that smart contracts depend on?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does all the data that a smart contract uses in its calculations and decisions
need to be exposed to all the blockchain miners or validators?
Is there any approach available if a smart contract
needs to make a decision based on sensitive confidential data?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;does-the-blockchain-provide-any-form-of-metadata-privacy-for-transactions&#34;&gt;Does the blockchain provide any form of metadata privacy for transactions?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can the blockchain hide the identities of parties involved in transactions,
or does it effectively reveal who&amp;rsquo;s transacting with whom
even if the actual content of the transaction is encrypted?
Can the blockchain hide or obscure the timing, pattern, or rate of transactions
in any way,
limiting information leakage to an observer who might, for example,
infer that a burst of activity signifies
an upcoming product release, merger, major trade, or other announcement??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Even if a spy or competitor can&#39;t decrypt the blockchain transactions
you&#39;re involved in,
if they can observe the *rate*, *timing*, and *pattern*
of transactions your business submits
-- and especially who else is involved in those transactions --
then they can potentially learn or guess a lot about what you&#39;re doing:
e.g., guess that a big event is upcoming if they see a burst of transactions
with your name on it,
or guess that you&#39;ve signed a major deal with a particular company
if they start seeing many transactions tagged with your and their identity.
--&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;smart-contract-questions&#34;&gt;Smart Contract Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;which-language-s-are-smart-contracts-written-in&#34;&gt;Which language(s) are smart contracts written in?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does the language have a clear and rigorous specification?
What measures does the language take for mitigating risks
of critical smart contract bugs?
Has the specification been validated through independent security analysis
and/or publication in peer-reviewed venues?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-the-costs-of-running-simple-or-complex-smart-contracts&#34;&gt;What are the costs of running simple, or complex, smart contracts?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the financial cost and latency to run a simple &amp;ldquo;if-then&amp;rdquo; type contract?
What is the financial cost and latency to run complex smart contract code
that, for example, needs to include cryptographic algorithms
to verify non-native signatures or zero-knowledge proofs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-the-recourse-if-something-goes-wrong-due-to-a-smart-contract-bug&#34;&gt;What is the recourse if something goes wrong due to a smart contract bug?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does the blockchain architecture provide a systematic means
to roll-back or correct for the effects of smart contract bugs?
How costly are those measures, e.g., do they require a global hard-fork
as was used to address
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coindesk.com/understanding-dao-hack-journalists/&#34;&gt;the DAO incident&lt;/a&gt;
for example?
If there are less-costly measures,
how are they activated,
and how does the architecture protect against abuse
(e.g., via costly over-use or &amp;ldquo;crying wolf&amp;rdquo; attacks)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;does-the-smart-contract-virtual-machine-enforce-strict-determinism-in-the-smart-contract-code&#34;&gt;Does the smart contract virtual machine enforce strict determinism in the smart contract code?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or can buggy or maliciously-written smart contract code potentially
inject random or other nondeterministic results into their output,
and thereby preventing the validators from agreeing
on the results of a transaction?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
---

*I wish to thank ...
for helpful feedback on early drafts of this post.*
--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>