<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drafts on Bryan Ford&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/draft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drafts on Bryan Ford&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bford.info/draft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure, Scalable Proof-of-Stake Blockchains</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/stake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/stake/</guid>
      <description>Proof-of-What? Currently-deployed permissionless blockchains such as Bitcoin and Ethereum rely on proof-of-work (PoW) to distribute both the computational networking costs, and the financial rewards, of maintaining and extending the blockchain. In proof-of-work systems, participating miners race (&amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo;) to compute solutions to cryptographic puzzles. These puzzles effectively act like self-printed lottery tickets, in that a miniscule fraction of these proof-of-work solutions may be easily verified by anyone as &amp;ldquo;winning&amp;rdquo; the lucky miner the right to add one block to the blockchain and collect associated rewards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selfish Mining in Bitcoin and ByzCoin</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/xx/xx/selfish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/xx/xx/selfish/</guid>
      <description>XXX intro
summary of selfish mining
selfish mining as a transparency problem: you get to build on a blockchain head you haven&amp;rsquo;t published.
same as transparency problem in Apple FBI case for example; that&amp;rsquo;s what CoSi is for.
solution: any keyblock you build on is collectively signed, and the next block&amp;rsquo;s hash covers the last block&amp;rsquo;s signature.
if you withhold a block, you can&amp;rsquo;t get a collective signature on it; without that collective signature, you can&amp;rsquo;t secretly mine a next block on top of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An advanced crypto library for Go</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/03/08/crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/03/08/crypto/</guid>
      <description>{{ page.title }} Interesting features:
 An abstract group arithmetic framework for public-key cryptography based on the discrete logarithm problem.
 Several alternative concrete instantiations of this abstract group arithmetic framework, based on the NIST elliptic curve implementations in the Go standard library and in the OpenSSL crypto library, and implementations of both generic Edwards curves and an adaptation of Adam Langley&amp;rsquo;s Ed25519-curve-specific optimized group arithmetic code to the abstract group API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backdoors, Trusted Servers, and Deanonymization</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/03/08/backdoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/03/08/backdoors/</guid>
      <description>{{ page.title }} To my knowledge there are currently only two fundamentally distinct approaches to achieving strong anonymity online, and the same legendary computing figure, David Chaum, pioneered both. His first approach, mixes, relay messages over multi-hop paths around the network to obscure their source and destinations. State-of-the-art deployed anonymity systems such as Tor are highly evolved and performance-optimized variants of this basic relaying idea.
Chaum&amp;rsquo;s second approach, dining cryptographers, instead uses information-coding principles to hide the sender of a message among a group of nodes all of whom seem to be spewing gibberish at once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to prove DNSSEC isn&#39;t a key escrow scheme</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/03/08/dnssec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/03/08/dnssec/</guid>
      <description>{{ page.title }} &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bford.info/draft/async/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/draft/async/</guid>
      <description>For another thing, I’m personally not a big believer in the practical value of the asynchronous model anyway. I know I’m at odds here with most people with a theory/algorithms background; reasonable people may differ. :) Almost every practical distributed system that ever actually gets deployed has timeouts and such buried in it here, there, everywhere. User-experience expectations are synchronous, not asynchronous: even if the underlying protocol is in principle perfectly capable of tolerating arbitrarily-long adversary-controlled propagation delays among honest nodes, the real users relying on the system are going to start complaining rather soon after the expected/normal amount of transaction time elapses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Social Media to Escape the Echo Chamber</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/11/13/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/11/13/info/</guid>
      <description>Hillary Clinton&amp;rsquo;s [electoral college defeat]() has provoked many questions about how so many Americans could have choosen a [misogynistic](), [xenophobic](), [pathologically lying](), [authoritarian]() [ideologue]() as their next President &amp;ndash; and one of many targets of their blame is [social media](). Compounding its [polarizing &amp;ldquo;echo chamber&amp;rdquo; effect](), online discussions were tarnished with [deliberate misinformation](), including [incorrect instructions on how to vote](). But is the solution for social media companies like Facebook to ``do a better job&amp;rdquo; at curating the world&amp;rsquo;s content to suppress out false or hateful speech?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>