<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers – Bryan Ford on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/pub/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Papers – Bryan Ford on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/pub/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Immunizing Systems from Distant Failures by Limiting Lamport Exposure</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/limix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/limix/</guid>
      <description>Cristina Băsescu and Bryan Ford  Twentieth ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets)
November 10-12, 2021 Abstract: Failures far away from a user should intuitively be less likely to affect that user. Today&#39;s ecosystem miserably fails this test, however, despite high-availability best practices. Correlated and cascading failures &amp;ndash; triggered by misconfigurations, bugs, and network partitions &amp;ndash; often invalidate assumptions of failure independence. We propose that distributed services need not and should not expose local activities to distant failures or partitions, no matter how severe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CALYPSO: Private Data Management for Decentralized Ledgers</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/calypso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/calypso/</guid>
      <description>Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Enis Ceyhun Alp, Linus Gasser, Philipp Jovanovic, Ewa Syta, and Bryan Ford  47th International Conference on Very Large Data Bases (VLDB 2021)
Copenhagen, Denmark &amp;ndash; August 16-20, 2021 Abstract: Distributed ledgers provide high availability and integrity, making them a key enabler for practical and secure computation of distributed workloads among mutually distrustful parties. Many practical applications also require strong confidentiality, however, the third pillar of the CIA triad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technologizing Democracy or Democratizing Technology? A Layered-Architecture Perspective on Potentials and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Appears in Digital Technology and Democratic Theory by Lucy Bernholz, Hélène Landemore, and Rob Reich (editors) published by the University of Chicago Press 
Abstract While technology is often claimed to be “democratizing”, the technologizing of society has more often yielded undemocratic or even anti-democratic outcomes. Is technology fundamentally at odds with democracy, or is it merely a rich and infinitely-adaptable toolbox that we’re using the wrong way?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identity and Personhood in Digital Democracy: Evaluating Inclusion, Equality, Security, and Privacy in Pseudonym Parties and Other Proofs of Personhood</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/personhood/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford  November 2020 (first draft)  arXiv preprint
 Abstract: Digital identity seems at first like a prerequisite for digital democracy: how can we ensure &amp;ldquo;one person, one vote&amp;rdquo; online without identifying voters? But the full gamut of digital identity solutions &amp;ndash; e.g., online ID checking, biometrics, self-sovereign identity, and social/trust networks &amp;ndash; all present severe flaws in security, privacy, and transparency, leaving users vulnerable to exclusion, identity loss or theft, and coercion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design choices for Central Bank Digital Currency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cbdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cbdc/</guid>
      <description>Sarah Allen, Srdjan Capkun, Ittay Eyal, Giulia Fanti, Bryan Ford, James Grimmelmann, Ari Juels, Kari Kostiainen, Sarah Meiklejohn, Andrew Miller, Eswar Prasad, Karl Wüst, and Fan Zhang   Global Economy &amp; Development Working Paper 140,
Brookings Institution,
July 23, 2020. Abstract:  Central banks around the world are exploring and in some cases even piloting central bank digital currencies (CBDCs). CBDCs promise to realize a broad range of new capabilities, including direct government disbursements to citizens, frictionless consumer payment and money-transfer systems, and a range of new financial instruments and monetary policy levers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PriFi: Low-Latency Anonymity for Organizational Networks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/prifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/prifi/</guid>
      <description>Ludovic Barman, Italo Dacosta, Mahdi Zamani, Ennan Zhai, Apostolos Pyrgelis, Bryan Ford, Jean-Pierre Hubaux, and Joan Feigenbaum   Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium
July 13, 2020  Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
Volume 2020, Issue 4.  Abstract: Organizational networks are vulnerable to traffic-analysis attacks that enable adversaries to infer sensitive information from the network traffic &amp;ndash; even if encryption is used. Typical anonymous communication networks are tailored to the Internet and are poorly suited for organizational networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Que Sera Consensus: Simple Asynchronous Agreement with Private Coins and Threshold Logical Clocks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/qsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/qsc/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Philipp Jovanovic, and Ewa Syta
 March 4, 2020  arXiv preprint
 Abstract: It is commonly held that asynchronous consensus is much more complex, difficult, and costly than partially-synchronous algorithms, especially without using common coins. This paper challenges that conventional wisdom with que sera consensus QSC, an approach to consensus that cleanly decomposes the agreement problem from that of network asynchrony. QSC uses only private coins and reaches consensus in O(1) expected communication rounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Metadata Leakage from Encrypted Files and Communication with PURBs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/purb-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/purb-abs/</guid>
      <description>Kirill Nikitin, Ludovic Barman, Wouter Lueks, Matthew Underwood, Jean-Pierre Hubaux and Bryan Ford EPFL - IC - DEDIS   Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium
July 2019.  Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
Volume 2019, Issue 4.  Abstract: Most encrypted data formats leak metadata via their plaintext headers, such as format version, encryption schemes used, number of recipients who can decrypt the data, and even the recipients’ identities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threshold Logical Clocks for Asynchronous Distributed Coordination and Consensus</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/tlc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/tlc/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford  July 16, 2019  arXiv preprint
 Abstract: Consensus protocols for asynchronous networks are usually complex and inefficient, leading practical systems to rely on synchronous protocols. This paper attempts to simplify asynchronous consensus by building atop a novel threshold logical clock abstraction, which enables upper layers to operate as if on a synchronous network. This approach yields an asynchronous consensus protocol for fail-stop nodes that may be simpler and more robust than Paxos and its leader-based variants, requiring no common coins and achieving consensus in a constant expected number of rounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Security of Two-Round Multi-Signatures</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/two-round-multisig-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/two-round-multisig-abs/</guid>
      <description>Manu Drijvers, Kasra Edalatnejad, Bryan Ford, Eike Kiltz, Julian Loss, Gregory Neven, and Igors Stepanovs   40th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy
May 2019  Abstract: A multi-signature scheme allows a group of signers to collaboratively sign a message, creating a single signature that convinces a verifier that every individual signer approved the message. The increased interest in technologies to decentralize trust has triggered the proposal of highly efficient two-round Schnorr-based multi-signature schemes designed to scale up to thousands of signers, namely BCJ by Bagherzandi et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking General-Purpose Decentralized Computing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/protean-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/protean-abs/</guid>
      <description>Enis Ceyhun Alp, Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Georgia Fragkouli, and Bryan Ford EPFL - IC - DEDIS   17th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS XVII)
May 12-15, 2019.  Abstract: While showing great promise, smart contracts are difficult to program correctly, as they need a deep understanding of cryptography and distributed algorithms, and offer limited functionality, as they have to be deterministic and cannot operate on secret data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MorphIT: Morphing Packet Reports for Internet Transparency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/morphit-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/morphit-abs/</guid>
      <description>Georgia Fragkouli, Katerina Argyraki, and Bryan Ford EPFL Winner of Applied Networking Research Prize (ANRP)  Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
May 4, 2019. Abstract: Can we improve Internet transparency without worsening user anonymity? For a long time, researchers have been proposing transparency systems, where traffic reports produced at strategic network points help assess network behavior and verify service-level agreements or neutrality compliance. However, such reports necessarily reveal when certain traffic appeared at a certain network point, and this information could, in principle, be used to compromise low-latency anonymity networks like Tor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MedChain: Accountable and Auditable Data Sharing in Distributed Medical Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/medchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/medchain/</guid>
      <description>Juan Ram&amp;oacute;n Troncoso-Pastoriza, Jean Louis Raisaro, Linus Gasser, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux   AMIA Informatics Summit,
March 25&amp;mdash;28, 2019. Abstract: The current trend towards personalized medicine creates an urgent need to share data among different hospitals and health institutions, which endangers the privacy of the data subjects if not done with the appropriate precautions. Conversely, the frequency of data breaches in the healthcare industry has been rising since 2010, severely holding back health institutions from exposing and sharing their data for the fear of being the next target of cyberattacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Liquid Perspective on Democratic Choice</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/liquid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/liquid/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford  November 2018 (first draft)  arXiv preprint
 Abstract: The idea of liquid democracy responds to a widely-felt desire to make democracy more &#34;fluid&#34; and continuously participatory. Its central premise is to enable users to employ networked technologies to control and delegate voting power, to approximate the ideal of direct democracy in a scalable fashion that accounts for time and attention limits. There are many potential definitions, meanings, and ways to implement liquid democracy, however, and many distinct purposes to which it might be deployed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MedCo: Enabling Secure and Privacy-Conscious Exploration of Distributed Clinical and Genomic Data</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/medco-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/medco-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jean Louis Raisaro, Juan Ram&amp;oacute;n Troncoso-Pastoriza, Micka&amp;euml;l Misbach, Jo&amp;atilde;o S&amp;aacute; Sousa, Sylvain Pradervand, Edoardo Missiaglia, Olivier Michielin, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux   IEEE/ACM Transactions on Computational Biology and Bioinformatics,
July 13, 2018. Abstract: The increasing number of health-data breaches is creating a complicated environment for medical-data sharing and, consequently, for medical progress. Therefore, the development of new solutions that can reassure clinical sites by enabling privacy-preserving sharing of sensitive medical data in compliance with stringent regulations (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratic Value and Money for Decentralized Digital Society</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/money/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford  June 2018 (first draft)  arXiv preprint
 Abstract: Classical monetary systems regularly subject the most vulnerable majority of the world&#39;s population to debilitating financial shocks, and have manifestly allowed uncontrolled global inequality over the long term. Given these basic failures, how can we avoid asking whether mainstream macroeconomic principles are actually compatible with democratic principles such as equality or the protection of human rights and dignity?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OmniLedger: A Secure, Scale-Out, Decentralized Ledger via Sharding</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/omniledger-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/omniledger-abs/</guid>
      <description>Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Philipp Jovanovic, Linus Gasser, Nicolas Gailly, Ewa Syta, and Bryan Ford
  IEEE Security &amp; Privacy (IEEE S&amp;P)
May 22, 2018 Abstract: Designing a secure permissionless distributed ledger (blockchain) that performs on par with centralized payment processors, such as Visa, is a challenging task. Most existing distributed ledgers are unable to scale-out, i.e., to grow their total processing capacity with the number of validators; and those that do, compromise security or decentralization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Enforcing the Digital Immunity of a Large Humanitarian Organization</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/immunity-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/immunity-abs/</guid>
      <description>Stevens Le Blond, Alejandro Cuevas, Juan Ram&amp;oacute;n Troncoso-Pastoriza, Philipp Jovanovic, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux
EPFL Winner of Distinguished Paper Award  IEEE Security &amp; Privacy (IEEE S&amp;P)
May 22, 2018 Abstract: Humanitarian action, the process of aiding individuals in situations of crises, poses unique information-security challenges due to natural or manmade disasters, the adverse environments in which it takes place, and the scale and multidisciplinary nature of the problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom: Horizontally Scaling Strong Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/atom-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/atom-abs/</guid>
      <description>Albert Kwon
MIT  Henry Corrigan-Gibbs
Stanford  Srinivas Devadas
MIT  Bryan Ford
EPFL    26th ACM Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP)
October 30, 2017 Abstract: Atom is an anonymous messaging system that protects against traffic-analysis attacks. Unlike many prior systems, each Atom server touches only a small fraction of the total messages routed through the network. As a result, the system’s capacity scales near-linearly with the number of servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAINIAC: Proactive Software-Update Transparency via Collectively Signed Skipchains and Verified Builds</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/chainiac-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/chainiac-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UnLynx: A Decentralized System for Privacy-Conscious Data Sharing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/unlynx-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/unlynx-abs/</guid>
      <description>David Froelicher, Patricia Egger, Jo&amp;atilde;o S&amp;aacute; Sousa, Jean Louis Raisaro, Zhicong Huang, Christian Mouchet, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux   Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium (PETS)
July 19, 2017 Abstract: Current solutions for privacy-preserving data sharing among multiple parties either depend on a centralized authority that must be trusted and provides only weakest-link security (e.g., the entity that manages private/secret cryptographic keys), or leverage on decentralized but impractical approaches (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Bias-Resistant Distributed Randomness</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/random-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/random-abs/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta, Philipp Jovanovic, Eleftherios Kokoris Kogias, Nicolas Gailly, Linus Gasser, Ismail Khoffi, Michael J. Fischer, and Bryan Ford
  IEEE Security &amp; Privacy (IEEE S&amp;P)
May 23, 2017 Abstract: Bias-resistant public randomness is a critical component in many (distributed) protocols. Generating public randomness is hard, however, because active adversaries may behave dishonestly to bias public random choices toward their advantage. Existing solutions do not scale to hundreds or thousands of participants, as is needed in many decentralized systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof-of-Personhood: Redemocratizing Permissionless Cryptocurrencies</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</guid>
      <description>Maria Borge, Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Philipp Jovanovic, Linus Gasser, Nicolas Gailly, and Bryan Ford
EPFL   IEEE Security &amp; Privacy on the Blockchain (IEEE S&amp;B)
April 29, 2017 Abstract: Permissionless blockchain-based cryptocurrencies commonly use proof-of-work (PoW) or proof-of-stake (PoS) to ensure their security, e.g. to prevent double spending attacks. However, both approaches have disadvantages: PoW leads to massive amounts of wasted electricity and re-centralization, whereas major stakeholders in PoS might be able to create a monopoly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Objectives of Lawful-Surveillance Protocols</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/lawful-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/lawful-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-Preserving Lawful Contact Chaining</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/contact-chaining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/contact-chaining/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Bitcoin Security and Performance with Strong Consistency via Collective Signing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/byzcoin-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/byzcoin-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riffle: An Efficient Communication System With Strong Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/riffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/riffle/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open, privacy-preserving protocols for lawful surveillance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/open-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/open-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Authorities “Honest or Bust” with Decentralized Witness Cosigning</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cosi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cosi/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AnonRep: Towards Tracking-Resistant Anonymous Reputation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Privacy-Preserving Cryptographic Credentials from Federated Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book-codaspy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book-codaspy/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metadata Protection Considerations for TLS Present and Future</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/tlsmeta-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/tlsmeta-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
EPFL   TLS 1.3 Ready or Not (TRON) Workshop
February 21, 2016 Abstract: TLS 1.3 takes important steps to improve both performance and security, so far offers little protection against traffic analysis or fingerprinting using unencrypted metadata or other side-channels such as transmission lengths and timings. This paper explores metadata protection mechanisms for TLS, including already-included provisions (e.g., record padding), provisions not yet included but potentially feasible in TLS 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deterministically Deterring Timing Attacks in Deterland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-timing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-timing/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Anonymity in an Internet Panopticon</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/panopticon-cacm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/panopticon-cacm/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Eyes: Secure Remote Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta, Michael J. Fischer, David Wolinsky, Abraham Silberschatz, Gina Gallegos-García, and Bryan Ford   12th International Conference on Security and Cryptography (SECRYPT)
July 2015.  Abstract: We propose an efficient remote biometric authentication protocol that gives strong protection to the user’s biometric data in case of two common kinds of security breaches: (1) loss or theft of the user’s token (smart card, handheld device, etc.), giving the attacker full access to any secrets embedded within it; (2) total penetration of the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certificate Cothority: Towards Trustworthy Collective CAs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/certco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/certco/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPUfs: The Case for Operating System Services on GPUs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/gpufs-cacm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/gpufs-cacm/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heading Off Correlated Failures through Independence-as-a-Service</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-indaas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-indaas/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching Bandits and Only Bandits: Privacy-Preserving Intersection Warrants for Lawful Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/bandits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/bandits/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing NymBoxes for Identity and Tracking Protection</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/nymboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/nymboxes/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Analysis of Accountable Anonymity in Dissent</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-analysis/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A TorPath to TorCoin: Proof-of-Bandwidth Altcoins for Compensating Relays</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/torcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/torcoin/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Onions to Shallots: Rewarding Tor Relays with TEARS</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/onions-to-shallots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/onions-to-shallots/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TAQ: Enhancing Fairness and Performance Predictability in Small Packet Regimes</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/taq-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/taq-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crypto-Book: An Architecture for Privacy Preserving Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Cloud Audits that Protect Private Information</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-psra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/cloud-psra/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conscript Your Friends into Larger Anonymity Sets with JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/conscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/conscript/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring High-Quality Randomness in Cryptographic Key Generation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/randomness-keygen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/randomness-keygen/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hang With Your Buddies to Resist Intersection Attacks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/buddies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/buddies/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Untold Story of Redundant Clouds: Making Your Service Deployment Truly Reliable</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/irec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/irec/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proactively Accountable Anonymous Messaging in Verdict</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/verdict/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/verdict/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maple: Simplifying SDN Programming Using Algorithmic Policies</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/maple-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/maple-abs/</guid>
      <description>Andreas Voellmy, Junchang Wang, Y. Richard Yang, Bryan Ford, and Paul Hudak   ACM SIGCOMM 2013
August 12-16, 2013  Abstract: Software-Defined Networking offers the appeal of a simple, centralized programming model for managing complex networks. However, challenges in managing low-level details, such as setting up and maintaining correct and efficient forwarding tables on distributed switches, often compromise this conceptual simplicity. In this paper, we present Maple, a system that simplifies SDN programming by (1) allowing a programmer to use a standard programming language to design an arbitrary, centralized algorithm, which we call an algorithmic policy, to decide the behaviors of an entire network, and (2) providing an abstraction that the programmer-defined, centralized policy runs, conceptually, &amp;ldquo;afresh&amp;rdquo; on every packet entering a network, and hence is oblivious to the challenge of translating a high-level policy into sets of rules on distributed individual switches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Latency in Tor Circuits with Unordered Delivery</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/tor-unordered/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/tor-unordered/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy Tree Mapping: Generalizing and Scaling Deterministic Parallelism</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/lazy-tree-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/lazy-tree-mapping/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the World of Human Rights: Please Make Yourself Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/human-rights-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/human-rights-abs/</guid>
      <description>   Henry Corrigan-Gibbs and Bryan Ford Yale University   Cyber-security Research Ethics Dialog &amp; Strategy Workshop (CREDS 2013)
May 23, 2013  Abstract: We draw an ethical analogy between Internet freedom efforts and humanitarian aid work. This parallel motivates a number of ethical questions relating to anonymity and censorship-circumvention research. Paper: PDF  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPUfs: Integrating a File System with GPUs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/gpufs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/gpufs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the OS against Security Threats in System Administration</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/middleware12-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/middleware12-abs/</guid>
      <description>Nuno Santos, Rodrigo Rodrigues, and Bryan Ford   ACM/IFIP/USENIX 13th International Conference on Middleware
December 2012  Abstract: The consequences of security breaches due to system administrator errors can be catastrophic. Software systems in general, and OSes in particular, ultimately depend on a fully trusted administrator whom is granted superuser privileges that allow him to fully control the system. Consequently, an administrator acting negligently or unethically can easily compromise user data in irreversible ways by leaking, modifying, or deleting data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissent in Numbers: Making Strong Anonymity Scale</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-in-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-in-numbers/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scavenging for Anonymity with BlogDrop</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/blogdrop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/blogdrop/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Software-Defined Network Controllers on Multicore Servers</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/scaling-sdn-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/scaling-sdn-abs/</guid>
      <description>Andreas Voellmy, Bryan Ford, Paul Hudak, and Y. Richard Yang Yale University Department of Computer Science
  Technical Report YALEU/DCS/TR-1468
July 2012  Abstract: Software defined networks (SDN) introduce centralized controllers to drastically increase network programmability. The simplicity of a logical centralized controller, however, can come at the cost of controller programming complexity and scalability. In this paper, we present McNettle, an extensible SDN controller system whose control event processing throughput scales with the number of system CPU cores and which supports control algorithms requiring globally visible state changes occurring at flow arrival rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-Linear Compression: Gzip Me Not!</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/non-linear/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/non-linear/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugging Side-Channel Leaks with Timing Information Flow Control</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/tifc-hotcloud12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/tifc-hotcloud12/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icebergs in the Clouds: the Other Risks of Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/icebergs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/icebergs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Theft-Proof Privacy-Preserving Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitting Square Pegs Through Round Pipes: Unordered Delivery Wire-Compatible with TCP and TLS</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/nsdi12-minion-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/nsdi12-minion-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faceless: Decentralized Anonymous Group Messaging for Online Social Networks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/faceless-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/faceless-abs/</guid>
      <description>Xiaoxiao Song, David Isaac Wolinsky, and Bryan Ford Yale University   5th Workshop on Social Network Systems
April 10, 2012  Abstract: Social networks (SNs) enable physically distributed groups to communicate seamlessly. Unfortunately such communi- cation can be easily mined by adversaries in attempts to breach users’ privacy or suppress open discussion on sensi- tive topics. While anonymous posting can help protect users by hiding the link between individuals and the messages they post, existing anonymization schemes are centralized or vul- nerable to well-known attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Anonymous Group Communication in the Anytrust Model</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/anytrust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/anytrust/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Virtual Memory Foundation for Scalable Deterministic Parallelism</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-vm/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CertiKOS: A Certified Kernel for Secure Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/certikos-apsys11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/certikos-apsys11/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eyo: Device-Transparent Personal Storage</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/eyo-usenix-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/eyo-usenix-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jacob Strauss, Justin Mazzola Paluska, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Bryan Ford, Robert Morris, and Frans Kaashoek
 2011 USENIX Annual Technical Conference June 15-17, 2011, Portland, OR, USA Abstract: Users increasingly store data collections such as digital photographs on multiple personal devices, each of which typically offers a storage management interface oblivious to the contents of the user’s other devices. As a result, collections become disorganized and drift out of sync.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deterministic OpenMP for Race-Free Parallelism</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-openmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-openmp/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspace Consistency: A Programming Model for Shared Memory Parallelism</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/workspace-consistency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/workspace-consistency/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dynamic Recursive Unified Internet Design (DRUID)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/druid-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/druid-abs/</guid>
      <description>Joe Touch, Ilia Baldine, Rudra Dutta, Gregory G. Finn, Bryan Ford, Scott Jordan, Dan Massey, Abraham Matta, Christos Papadopoulos, Peter Reiher, George Rouskas   Computer Networks December 24, 2010 Abstract: The Dynamic Recursive Unified Internet Design (DRUID) is a future Internet design that unifies overlay networks with conventional layered network architectures. DRUID is based on the fundamental concept of recursion, enabling a simple and direct network architecture that unifies the data, control, management, and security aspects of the current Internet, leading to a more trustworthy network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minion: an all-terrain packet packhorse to jump-start stalled internet transports</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/pfldnet10-minion-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/pfldnet10-minion-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determinating Timing Channels in Compute Clouds</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/timing-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/timing-abs/</guid>
      <description>Amittai Aviram, Sen Hu, Bryan Ford
	Ramakrishna Gummadi
	Yale University 	University of Massachusetts Amherst  The ACM Cloud Computing Security Workshop (CCSW 2010) October 8, 2010, Chicago, IL, USA Abstract: Timing side-channels represent an insidious security challenge for cloud computing, because: (a) massive parallelism in the cloud makes timing channels pervasive and hard to control; (b) timing channels enable one customer to steal information from another without leaving a trail or raising alarms; (c) only the cloud provider can feasibly detect and report such attacks, but the provider&#39;s incentives are not to; and (d) resource partitioning schemes for timing channel control undermine statistical sharing efficiency, and, with it, the cloud computing business model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient System-Enforced Deterministic Parallelism</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-osdi10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/determ-osdi10/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissent: Accountable Anonymous Group Messaging</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/dissent-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/dissent-abs/</guid>
      <description>Henry Corrigan-Gibbs and Bryan Ford Yale University Winner of ACM CCS Test-of-Time Award  17th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS 2010) October 4-8, 2010, Chicago, IL, USA Abstract:  Users often wish to participate in online groups anonymously, but misbehaving users may abuse this anonymity to disrupt the group&#39;s communication. Existing messaging protocols such as DC-nets leave groups vulnerable to denial-of-service and Sybil attacks, Mix-nets are difficult to protect against traffic analysis, and accountable voting protocols are unsuited to general anonymous messaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Development of Certified OS Kernels</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/certified-kernels-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/certified-kernels-abs/</guid>
      <description>Zhong Shao and Bryan Ford Department of Computer Science, Yale University   Yale University Technical Report TR1436
July 15, 2010  Abstract: Operating System (OS) kernels form the bedrock of all system software&amp;mdash;they can have the greatest impact on the resilience, extensibility, and security of today’s computing hosts. A single kernel bug can easily wreck the entire system’s integrity and protection. We propose to apply new advances in certified software to the development of a novel OS kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unintended Consequences of NAT Deployments with Overlapping Address Space</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5684-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5684-abs/</guid>
      <description>Pyda Srisuresh and Bryan Ford   IETF RFC 5684
February 2010  Abstract: This document identifies two deployment scenarios that have arisen from the unconventional network topologies formed using Network Address Translator (NAT) devices. First, the simplicity of administering networks through the combination of NAT and DHCP has increasingly lead to the deployment of multi-level inter-connected private networks involving overlapping private IP address spaces. Second, the proliferation of private networks in enterprises, hotels and conferences, and the wide-spread use of Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) to access an enterprise intranet from remote locations has increasingly lead to overlapping private IP address space between remote and corporate networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Cross-Layer Negotiation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/nego-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/nego-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
	Janardhan Iyengar
	Yale University 	Franklin &amp;amp; Marshall College  Published in Eighth ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets-VIII) October 22-23, 2009, New York City, NY, USA Abstract: Internet evolution often depends on either inserting new protocol layers or upgrading existing layers to new protocols, but both of these evolutionary paths are obstructed by the difficulty and inefficiency of determining which protocols a pair of hosts mutually support and prefer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Device Transparency: a New Model for Mobile Storage</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/devtransp-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/devtransp-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jacob Strauss
	Chris Lesniewski-Laas
	Justin Mazzola Paluska
	Bryan Ford
	Robert Morris
	Frans Kaashoek
 Published in SOSP Workshop on Hot Topics in Storage and File Systems (HotStorage &#39;09) October 11, 2009, Big Sky, MT, USA Abstract: This paper proposes a new storage model, device transparency, in which users view and manage their entire data collection from any of their devices, even from disconnected storage-limited devices holding only a subset of the entire collection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAT Behavioral Requirements for ICMP</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5508-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5508-abs/</guid>
      <description>Pyda Srisuresh, Bryan Ford, Senthil Sivakumar, and Saikat Guha   IETF RFC 5508
April 2009  Abstract: This document specifies the behavioral properties required of the Network Address Translator (NAT) devices in conjunction with the Internet Control Message Protocol (ICMP). The objective of this memo is to make NAT devices more predictable and compatible with diverse application protocols that traverse the devices. Companion documents provide behavioral recommendations specific to TCP, UDP, and other protocols.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Up the Transport Logjam</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/logjam-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/logjam-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
	Janardhan Iyengar
	Massachusetts Institute of Technology 	Franklin &amp;amp; Marshall College  Published in Seventh ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets-VII) October 6-7, 2008, Calgary, Alberta, Canada Abstract: Current Internet transports conflate transport semantics with endpoint addressing and flow regulation, creating roadblocks to Internet evolution that we propose to address with a new layering model. Factoring endpoint addressing (port numbers) into a separate Endpoint Layer permits incremental rollout of new or improved transports at OS or application level, enables transport-oblivious firewall/NAT traversal, improves transport negotiation efficiency, and simplifies endpoint address space administration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAT Behavioral Requirements for TCP</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5382-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5382-abs/</guid>
      <description>   Saikat Guha, Kaushik Biswas, Bryan Ford, Senthil Sivakumar, and Pyda Srisuresh   IETF RFC 5382
October 2008  Abstract: This document defines a set of requirements for NATs that handle TCP that would allow many applications, such as peer-to-peer applications and online games to work consistently. Developing NATs that meet this set of requirements will greatly increase the likelihood that these applications will function properly. Final RFC: Plain text  Early drafts:   IETF working group draft versions: 06 05 04 03 02 01 00  Individual draft versions: 02 01 00  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIA: A Global Connectivity Architecture for Mobile Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Ph.D. thesis, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, September 2008. Abstract:  The Internet&#39;s architecture, designed in the days of large, stationary computers tended by technically savvy and accountable administrators, fails to meet the demands of the emerging ubiquitous computing era. Nontechnical users now routinely own multiple personal devices, many of them mobile, and need to share information securely among them using interactive, delay-sensitive applications.  Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) is a novel, incrementally deployable network architecture for modern personal devices, which reconsiders three architectural cornerstones: naming, routing, and transport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vx32: Lightweight User-level Sandboxing on the x86</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/vx32-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/vx32-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Russ Cox
Massachusetts Institute of Technology  Winnder of Best Student Paper Award  USENIX Annual Technical Conference
June 22-27, 2008, Boston, Massachusetts. Abstract:  Code sandboxing is useful for many purposes, but most sandboxing techniques require kernel modifications, do not completely isolate guest code, or incur substantial performance costs. Vx32 is a multipurpose user-level sandbox that enables any application to load and safely execute one or more guest plug-ins, confining each guest to a system call API controlled by the host application and to a restricted memory region within the host&amp;rsquo;s address space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Offline Foundation for Online Accountable Pseudonyms</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Jacob Strauss 
Massachusetts Institute of Technology First Workshop on Social Network Systems
April 1, 2008 Abstract:  Online anonymity often appears to undermine accountability, offering little incentive for civil behavior, but accountability failures usually result not from anonymity itself but from the disposability of virtual identities. A user banned for misbehavior&amp;mdash;e.g., spamming from a free E-mail account or stuffing an online ballot box&amp;mdash;can simply open other accounts or connect from other IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Peer-to-Peer (P2P) Communication across Network Address Translators (NATs)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5128-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/rfc5128-abs/</guid>
      <description>Pyda Srisuresh, Bryan Ford, and Dan Kegel   IETF RFC 5128
March 2008  Abstract: This memo documents the various methods known to be in use by applications to establish direct communication in the presence of Network Address Translators (NATs) at the current time. Although this memo is intended to be mainly descriptive, the Security Considerations section makes some purely advisory recommendations about how to deal with security vulnerabilities the applications could inadvertently create when using the methods described.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Directions in Internet Transport Evolution</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/transport-ietf-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/transport-ietf-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpaca: Extensible Authorization for Distributed Services</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/alpaca-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/alpaca-abs/</guid>
      <description>Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Robert Morris, and M. Frans Kaashoek
Massachusetts Institute of Technology Published in 14th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security, Oct 29-Nov 2, 2007, Alexandria, VA. Abstract:  Traditional Public Key Infrastructures (PKI) have not lived up to their promise because there are too many ways to define PKIs, too many cryptographic primitives to build them with, and too many administrative domains with incompatible roots of trust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured Streams: a New Transport Abstraction</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/sst-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/sst-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Massachusetts Institute of Technology Published in ACM SIGCOMM 2007, August 27-31, 2007, Kyoto, Japan. Abstract:  Internet applications currently have a choice between stream and datagram transport abstractions. Datagrams efficiently support small transactions and streams are suited for long-running conversations, but neither abstraction adequately supports applications like HTTP that exhibit a mixture of transaction sizes, or applications like FTP and SIP that use multiple transport instances. Structured Stream Transport (SST) enhances the traditional stream abstraction with a hierarchical hereditary structure, allowing applications to create lightweight child streams from any existing stream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi/</guid>
      <description>Persistent Personal Names for Globally Connected Mobile Devices Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, Robert Morris
	Massachusetts Institute of Technology Published in 7th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation, November 6-8, 2006.   Abstract:   The  Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) provides zero-configuration connectivity among mobile devices through personal names. Users assign personal names through an ad hoc device introduction process requiring no central allocation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent Personal Names for Globally Connected Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, Robert Morris
 Massachusetts Institute of Technology 7th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation
November 6-8, 2006 Abstract:  The  Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) provides zero-configuration connectivity among mobile devices through personal names. Users assign personal names through an ad hoc device introduction process requiring no central allocation. Once assigned, names bind securely to the global identities of their target devices independent of network location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sybil Parties: An Offline Foundation for Online Accountability</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/log/2006/0924-SybilParties.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/log/2006/0924-SybilParties.html</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford - September 24, 2006 Preliminary draft: see here for the final published paper  The Human Recognition Problem  Today&#39;s online ecosphere continually suffers from its inability to tell who is a genuine, unique human and who isn&#39;t. Because open-access messaging systems cannot isolate or authenticate the human source of messages for the purpose of suppressing abuses, spam has already relegated USENET to historical obscurity [Templeton01], threatens the usability of E-mail [Wouters05], and is even advancing on Skype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User-Relative Names for Globally Connected Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-iptps-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-iptps-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, and Robert Morris Massachusetts Institute of Technology   5th International Workshop on Peer-to-Peer Systems
February 27-28, 2006  Abstract The User Information Architecture, or UIA, is a peer-to-peer connectivity architecture that provides users a simple, intuitive, and secure way to share information and services between personal devices by assigning ad hoc names that act like &amp;ldquo;virtual cables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VXA: A Virtual Architecture for Durable Compressed Archives</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/vxa-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/vxa-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Massachusetts Institute of Technology 4th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies (FAST &#39;05)
December 16, 2005, San Francisco, California, USA. Abstract:  Data compression algorithms change frequently, and obsolete decoders do not always run on new hardware and operating systems, threatening the long-term usability of content archived using those algorithms. Re-encoding content into new formats is cumbersome, and highly undesirable when lossy compression is involved. Processor architectures, in contrast, have remained comparatively stable over recent decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer-to-Peer Communication Across Network Address Translators</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/p2pnat-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/p2pnat-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Massachusetts Institute of Technology baford (at) mit.edu Pyda Srisuresh Caymas Systems, Inc. srisuresh (at) yahoo.com Dan Kegel dank (at) kegel.com   Presented at the USENIX Annual Technical Conference, April 10-15, 2005. Abstract:  Network Address Translation (NAT) causes well-known difficulties for peer-to-peer (P2P) communication, since the peers involved may not be reachable at any globally valid IP address. Several NAT traversal techniques are known, but their documentation is slim, and data about their robustness or relative merits is slimmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/p2pnat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/p2pnat/</guid>
      <description>Peer-to-Peer Communication Across Network Address Translators Bryan Ford Massachusetts Institute of Technology baford (at) mit.edu Pyda Srisuresh Caymas Systems, Inc. srisuresh (at) yahoo.com Dan Kegel dank (at) kegel.com    J&#39;fais des trous, des petits troustoujours des petits trous &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; - S. Gainsbourg  Abstract:  Network Address Translation (NAT) causes well-known difficulties for peer-to-peer (P2P) communication, since the peers involved may not be reachable at any globally valid IP address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parsing Expression Grammars: A Recognition-Based Syntactic Foundation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/peg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/peg/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Massachusetts Institute of Technology  Symposium on Principles of Programming Languages, January 14-16, 2004, Venice, Italy   Abstract For decades we have been using Chomsky&#39;s generative system of grammars, particularly context-free grammars (CFGs) and regular expressions (REs), to express the syntax of programming languages and protocols. The power of generative grammars to express ambiguity is crucial to their original purpose of modelling natural languages, but this very power makes it unnecessarily difficult both to express and to parse machine-oriented languages using CFGs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unmanaged Internet Protocol: Taming the Edge Network Management Crisis</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-case-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-case-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Massachusetts Institute of Technology   Second Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks
November 20-21, 2003  Abstract: Though appropriate for core Internet infrastructure, the Internet Protocol is unsuited to routing within and between emerging ad-hoc edge networks due to its dependence on hierarchical, administratively assigned addresses. Existing ad-hoc routing protocols address the management problem but do not scale to Internet-wide networks. The promise of ubiquitous network computing cannot be fulfilled until we develop an Unmanaged Internet Protocol (UIP), a scalable routing protocol that manages itself automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Internet Routing on Topology-Independent Node Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Massachusetts Institute of Technology   Technical Report MIT-LCS-TR-926
October 31, 2003  Abstract: Unmanaged Internet Protocol (UIP) is a fully self-organizing network-layer protocol that implements scalable identity-based routing. In contrast with address-based routing protocols, which depend for scalability on centralized hierarchical address management, UIP nodes use a flat namespace of cryptographic node identifiers. Node identities can be created locally on demand and remain stable across network changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packrat Parsing: Simple, Powerful, Lazy, Linear Time</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/packrat-icfp02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/packrat-icfp02/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Massachusetts Institute of Technology  International Conference on Functional Programming, October 4-6, 2002, Pittsburgh   Abstract Packrat parsing is a novel technique for implementing parsers in a lazy functional programming language. A packrat parser provides the power and flexibility of top-down parsing with backtracking and unlimited lookahead, but nevertheless guarantees linear parse time. Any language defined by an LL(k) or LR(k) grammar can be recognized by a packrat parser, in addition to many languages that conventional linear-time algorithms do not support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packrat Parsing: a Practical Linear-Time Algorithm with Backtracking</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/thesis/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Master&#39;s Thesis
Massachusetts Institute of Technology   Abstract  Packrat parsing is a novel and practical method for implementing linear-time parsers for grammars defined in Top-Down Parsing Language (TDPL). While TDPL was originally created as a formal model for top-down parsers with backtracking capability, this thesis extends TDPL into a powerful general-purpose notation for describing language syntax, providing a compelling alternative to traditional context-free grammars (CFGs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interface and Execution Models in the Fluke Kernel</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/atomic-osdi99-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/atomic-osdi99-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Mike Hibler, Jay Lepreau, Roland McGrath, and Patrick Tullmann 
Department of Computer Science, University of Utah  3rd Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation
February 22-25, 1999 Abstract:  We have defined and implemented a kernel API that makes every exported operation fully interruptible and restartable, thereby appearing atomic to the user. To achieve interruptibility, all possible kernel states in which a thread may become blocked for a &amp;ldquo;long&amp;rdquo; time are represented as kernel system calls, without requiring the kernel to retain any unexposable internal state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flux OSKit: A Substrate for Kernel and Language Research</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/oskit-sosp16-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/oskit-sosp16-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Godmar Back, Greg Benson, Jay Lepreau, Albert Lin, and Olin Shivers 
 Proceedings of the 16th ACM Symposium on Operating System Principles
October 5-8, 1997 Abstract:  Implementing new operating systems is tedious, costly, and often impractical except for large projects. The Flux OSKit addresses this problem in a novel way by providing clean, well-documented OS components designed to be reused in a wide variety of other environments, rather than defining a new OS structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flick: A Flexible, Optimizing IDL Compiler</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/flick-pldi97-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/flick-pldi97-abs/</guid>
      <description>Eric Eide, Kevin Frei, Bryan Ford, Jay Lepreau, and Gary Lindstrom University of Utah, Department of Computer Science   ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation
June 15-18, 1997.  Abstract: Modern operating systems must support a wide variety of services for a diverse set of users. Designers of these systems face a tradeoff between functionality and performance. Systems like Mach provide a set of general abstractions and attempt to handle every situation, which can lead to poor performance for common cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flux OS Toolkit: Reusable Components for OS Implementation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/oskit-hotos6-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/oskit-hotos6-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Kevin Van Maren, Jay Lepreau, Stephen Clawson, Bart Robinson, and Jeff Turner
University of Utah 6th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS-VI)
May 5-6, 1997 Abstract:  To an unappreciated degree, research both in operating systems and their programming languages has been severely hampered by the lack of cleanly reusable code providing mundane low-level OS infrastructure such as bootstrap code and device drivers. The Flux OS Toolkit solves this problem by providing a set of clean, well-documented components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CPU Inheritance Scheduling</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/inherit-sched-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 1996 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/inherit-sched-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Sai R. Susarla  Department of Computer Science, University of Utah  Proceedings of the Second Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation
October 28-31, 1996  Abstract: Traditional processor scheduling mechanisms in operating systems are fairly rigid, often supporting only one fixed scheduling policy, or, at most, a few &amp;ldquo;scheduling classes&amp;rdquo; whose implementations are closely tied together in the OS kernel. This paper presents CPU inheritance scheduling, a novel processor scheduling framework in which arbitrary threads can act as schedulers for other threads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microkernels Meet Recursive Virtual Machines</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/fluke-rvm-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 1996 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/fluke-rvm-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Mike Hibler, Jay Lepreau, Patrick Tullmann, Godmar Back, and Stephen Clawson
University of Utah USENIX 2nd Symposium on OS Design and Implementation (OSDI &#39;96)
October 28-31, 1996, Seattle, Washington, USA. Abstract:  This paper describes a novel approach to providing modular and extensible operating system functionality and encapsulated environments based on a synthesis of microkernel and virtual machine concepts. We have developed a software-based virtualizable architecture called Fluke that allows recursive virtual machines (virtual machines running on other virtual machines) to be implemented efficiently by a microkernel running on generic hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User-level Checkpointing Through Exportable Kernel State</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/iwooos96-flobs-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 1996 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/iwooos96-flobs-abs/</guid>
      <description>Patrick Tullmann, Jay Lepreau, Bryan Ford, and Mike Hibler  Department of Computer Science, University of Utah  Proceedings of the Fifth IEEE International Workshop on Object Orientation in Operating Systems (IWOOOS)
October 27-28, 1996  Abstract: Checkpointing, process migration, and similar services need to have access not only to the memory of the constituent processes, but also to the complete state of all kernel provided objects (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Persistent Relevance of the Local Operating System to Global Applications</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/dist-vs-local-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 1996 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/dist-vs-local-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jay Lepreau, Bryan Ford, and Mike Hibler  Department of Computer Science, University of Utah  Proceedings of the Seventh ACM SIGOPS European Workshop
September 9-11, 1996  Abstract: The growth and popularity of loosely-coupled distributed systems such as the World Wide Web and the touting of Java-based systems as the solution to the issues of software maintenance, flexibility, and security are changing the research emphasis away from traditional single node operating system issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Annotated Interface Definitions to Optimize RPC</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/presint3-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 1995 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/presint3-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Mike Hibler, and Jay Lepreau University of Utah, Department of Computer Science   Technical Report UUCS-95-014
March 1995.  Abstract: In RPC-based communication, it is useful to distinguish the RPC interface, which is the “network contract” be- tween the client and the server, from the presentation, which is the “programmer’s contract” between the RPC stubs and the code that calls or is called by them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Separating Presentation from Interface in RPC and IDLs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/presint2-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 1994 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/presint2-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Mike Hibler, and Jay Lepreau University of Utah, Department of Computer Science   Technical Report UUCS-95-018
December 1994.  Abstract: In RPC-based communication, we term the interface the set of remote procedures and the types of their arguments; the presentation is the way these procedures and types are mapped to the target language environment in a particular client or server, including semantic requirements. For example, presentation includes the local names assigned to RPC stubs, the physical representation of a logical block of data (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolving Mach 3.0 to A Migrating Thread Model</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/thread-migrate-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 1994 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/thread-migrate-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Jay Lepreau  Department of Computer Science, University of Utah  Proceedings of the Winter 1994 USENIX Technical Conference
January 17-21, 1994  Abstract: We have modified Mach 3.0 to treat cross-domain remote procedure call (RPC) as a single entity, instead of a sequence of message passing operations. With RPC thus elevated, we improved the transfer of control during RPC by changing the thread model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microkernels Should Support Passive Objects</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/passive-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 1993 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/passive-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Jay Lepreau  Department of Computer Science, University of Utah  International Workshop on Object Orientation in Operating Systems (IWOOOS)
December 9-10, 1993  Abstract: We believe that a passive object model, in which the active entities or threads migrate between passive objects, is more appropriate than an active object model, as the basic structure of a microkernel-based operating system. A passive object model provides enhanced performance and simplicity because it is more closely matched to the basic nature of microprocessors and the requirements of applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FLEX: A Tool for Building Efficient and Flexible Systems</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/flex-wwos4-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 1993 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/flex-wwos4-abs/</guid>
      <description>John B. Carter, Bryan Ford, Mike Hibler, Ravindra Kuramkote, Jeffrey Law, Jay Lepreau, Douglas B. Orr, Leigh Stoller, and Mark Swanson University of Utah, Department of Computer Science   4th IEEE Workshop on Workstation Operating Systems (WWOS)
October 14-15, 1993.  Abstract: Modern operating systems must support a wide variety of services for a diverse set of users. Designers of these systems face a tradeoff between functionality and performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-Kernel Servers on Mach 3.0: Implementation and Performance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/inks-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 1993 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/inks-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jay Lepreau, Mike Hibler, Bryan Ford, and Jeffrey Law  Department of Computer Science, University of Utah  Proceedings of the Third USENIX Mach Symposium
April 1993  Abstract: The advantages in modularity and power of microkernel-based operating systems such as Mach 3.0 are well known. The existing performance problems of these systems, however, are significant. Much of the performance degradation is due to the cost of maintaining separate protection domains, traversing software layers, and using a semantically rich inter-process communication mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Thread Models in Mach 3.0</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/threadmodel-93-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 1993 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/threadmodel-93-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Mike Hibler, and Jay Lepreau Department of Computer Science, University of Utah   Technical Report UUCS-93-012
April 1993  Abstract: During the Mach In-Kernel Servers work, we explored two alternate thread models that could be used to support traps to in-kernel servers. In the &amp;ldquo;migrating threads&amp;rdquo; model we used, the client&#39;s thread temporarily moves into the server&#39;s task for the duration of the call. In the &amp;ldquo;thread switching&amp;rdquo; model, an actual server thread is dispatched to handle client traps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Die Datenpresse</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/datenpresse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 1992 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/datenpresse/</guid>
      <description>  Urban D. Mueller, Christian Schneider, and Bryan Ford
 AmigaPlus, August 1992.   Article: unavailable online to my knowledge ☹️  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object-Oriented Display Refreshing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/lang/call-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 1992 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/lang/call-lists/</guid>
      <description> &amp;ldquo;CallLists is a refreshing way to keep your interactive programs up to date.&amp;rdquo;  Bryan Ford
 AmigaWorld Tech Journal
Volume 2 Number 2, April 1992   Article: PDF  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/vx32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/vx32/</guid>
      <description>Vx32: Lightweight, User-level Sandboxing on the x86    Vx32: Lightweight, User-level Sandboxing on the x86  Bryan Ford and Russ Cox Massachusetts Institute of Technology {baford,rsc}@pdos.csail.mit.edu  Abstract Code sandboxing is useful for many purposes, but most sandboxing techniques require kernel modifications, do not completely isolate guest code, or incur substantial performance costs. Vx32 is a multipurpose user-level sandbox that enables any application to load and safely execute one or more guest plug-ins, confining each guest to a system call API controlled by the host application and to a restricted memory region within the host&amp;rsquo;s address space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/vxa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/vxa/</guid>
      <description>VXA: A Virtual Architecture for Durable Compressed Archives Bryan Ford 	Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory 	Massachusetts Institute of Technology   Abstract:  Data compression algorithms change frequently, and obsolete decoders do not always run on new hardware and operating systems, threatening the long-term usability of content archived using those algorithms. Re-encoding content into new formats is cumbersome, and highly undesirable when lossy compression is involved. Processor architectures, in contrast, have remained comparatively stable over recent decades.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
