<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bryan Ford&#39;s Publications on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/pub/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bryan Ford&#39;s Publications on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bford.info/pub/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MorphIT: Morphing Packet Reports for Internet Transparency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/morphit-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/morphit-abs/</guid>
      <description>Georgia Fragkouli, Katerina Argyraki, and Bryan Ford EPFL   Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
May 4, 2019.  Abstract: Can we improve Internet transparency without worsening user anonymity? For a long time, researchers have been proposing transparency systems, where traffic reports produced at strategic network points help assess network behavior and verify service-level agreements or neutrality compliance. However, such reports necessarily reveal when certain traffic appeared at a certain network point, and this information could, in principle, be used to compromise low-latency anonymity networks like Tor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Metadata Leakage from Encrypted Files and Communication with PURBs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/purb-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/purb-abs/</guid>
      <description>Kirill Nikitin, Ludovic Barman, Wouter Lueks, Matthew Underwood, Jean-Pierre Hubaux and Bryan Ford EPFL - IC - DEDIS   Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
July 2019.  Abstract: Most encrypted data formats leak metadata via their plaintext headers, such as format version, encryption schemes used, number of recipients who can decrypt the data, and even the recipients’ identities. This leakage can pose security and privacy risks to users, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking General-Purpose Decentralized Computing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/protean-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/protean-abs/</guid>
      <description>Enis Ceyhun Alp, Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Georgia Fragkouli, and Bryan Ford EPFL - IC - DEDIS   17th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS XVII)
May 12-15, 2019.  Abstract: While showing great promise, smart contracts are difficult to program correctly, as they need a deep understanding of cryptography and distributed algorithms, and offer limited functionality, as they have to be deterministic and cannot operate on secret data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>