<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cryptography on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Cryptography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cryptography on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Cryptography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Design choices for Central Bank Digital Currency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cbdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cbdc/</guid>
      <description>Sarah Allen, Srdjan Capkun, Ittay Eyal, Giulia Fanti, Bryan Ford, James Grimmelmann, Ari Juels, Kari Kostiainen, Sarah Meiklejohn, Andrew Miller, Eswar Prasad, Karl Wüst, and Fan Zhang   Global Economy &amp; Development Working Paper 140,
Brookings Institution,
July 23, 2020. Abstract:  Central banks around the world are exploring and in some cases even piloting central bank digital currencies (CBDCs). CBDCs promise to realize a broad range of new capabilities, including direct government disbursements to citizens, frictionless consumer payment and money-transfer systems, and a range of new financial instruments and monetary policy levers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PriFi: Low-Latency Anonymity for Organizational Networks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/prifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/prifi/</guid>
      <description>Ludovic Barman, Italo Dacosta, Mahdi Zamani, Ennan Zhai, Apostolos Pyrgelis, Bryan Ford, Jean-Pierre Hubaux, and Joan Feigenbaum   Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium
July 13, 2020  Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
Volume 2020, Issue 4.  Abstract: Organizational networks are vulnerable to traffic-analysis attacks that enable adversaries to infer sensitive information from the network traffic &amp;ndash; even if encryption is used. Typical anonymous communication networks are tailored to the Internet and are poorly suited for organizational networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure, Confidential Blockchains Providing High Throughput and Low Latency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2019-kokoris-kogias/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2019-kokoris-kogias/</guid>
      <description>Eleftherios Kokoris Kogias  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
September 27, 2019  Abstract:  One of the core promises of blockchain technology is that of enabling trustworthy data dissemination in a trustless environment. What current blockchain systems deliver, however, is slow dissemination of public data, rendering blockchain technology unusable in settings where latency, transaction capacity or data confidentiality is important. In this thesis, we focus on providing solutions on two of the most pressing problems blockchain technology currently faces: scalability and data confidentiality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Metadata Leakage from Encrypted Files and Communication with PURBs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/purb-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/purb-abs/</guid>
      <description>Kirill Nikitin, Ludovic Barman, Wouter Lueks, Matthew Underwood, Jean-Pierre Hubaux and Bryan Ford EPFL - IC - DEDIS   Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium
July 2019.  Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies
Volume 2019, Issue 4.  Abstract: Most encrypted data formats leak metadata via their plaintext headers, such as format version, encryption schemes used, number of recipients who can decrypt the data, and even the recipients’ identities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Security of Two-Round Multi-Signatures</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/two-round-multisig-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/two-round-multisig-abs/</guid>
      <description>Manu Drijvers, Kasra Edalatnejad, Bryan Ford, Eike Kiltz, Julian Loss, Gregory Neven, and Igors Stepanovs   40th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy
May 2019  Abstract: A multi-signature scheme allows a group of signers to collaboratively sign a message, creating a single signature that convinces a verifier that every individual signer approved the message. The increased interest in technologies to decentralize trust has triggered the proposal of highly efficient two-round Schnorr-based multi-signature schemes designed to scale up to thousands of signers, namely BCJ by Bagherzandi et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MedCo: Enabling Secure and Privacy-Conscious Exploration of Distributed Clinical and Genomic Data</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/medco-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/medco-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jean Louis Raisaro, Juan Ram&amp;oacute;n Troncoso-Pastoriza, Micka&amp;euml;l Misbach, Jo&amp;atilde;o S&amp;aacute; Sousa, Sylvain Pradervand, Edoardo Missiaglia, Olivier Michielin, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux   IEEE/ACM Transactions on Computational Biology and Bioinformatics,
July 13, 2018. Abstract: The increasing number of health-data breaches is creating a complicated environment for medical-data sharing and, consequently, for medical progress. Therefore, the development of new solutions that can reassure clinical sites by enabling privacy-preserving sharing of sensitive medical data in compliance with stringent regulations (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAINIAC: Proactive Software-Update Transparency via Collectively Signed Skipchains and Verified Builds</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/chainiac-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/chainiac-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do You Know It&#39;s On the Blockchain? With a SkipChain.</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2017/08/01/skipchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2017/08/01/skipchain/</guid>
      <description>A blockchain, or distributed ledger, is a log maintained collectively by a distributed group of participants who agree on and record transactions without relying for security on any single trusted party. While initially popularized by Bitcoin and its derivatives, the blockchain abstraction is not specific to currencies, and there is exploding industry interest in many non-currency uses.
  Many of these diverse use-cases, however, require users to be able to verify whether or not some transaction has been committed to a blockchain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UnLynx: A Decentralized System for Privacy-Conscious Data Sharing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/unlynx-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/unlynx-abs/</guid>
      <description>David Froelicher, Patricia Egger, Jo&amp;atilde;o S&amp;aacute; Sousa, Jean Louis Raisaro, Zhicong Huang, Christian Mouchet, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux   Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium (PETS)
July 19, 2017 Abstract: Current solutions for privacy-preserving data sharing among multiple parties either depend on a centralized authority that must be trusted and provides only weakest-link security (e.g., the entity that manages private/secret cryptographic keys), or leverage on decentralized but impractical approaches (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Bias-Resistant Distributed Randomness</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/random-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/random-abs/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta, Philipp Jovanovic, Eleftherios Kokoris Kogias, Nicolas Gailly, Linus Gasser, Ismail Khoffi, Michael J. Fischer, and Bryan Ford
  IEEE Security &amp; Privacy (IEEE S&amp;P)
May 23, 2017 Abstract: Bias-resistant public randomness is a critical component in many (distributed) protocols. Generating public randomness is hard, however, because active adversaries may behave dishonestly to bias public random choices toward their advantage. Existing solutions do not scale to hundreds or thousands of participants, as is needed in many decentralized systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Objectives of Lawful-Surveillance Protocols</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/lawful-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/lawful-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-Preserving Lawful Contact Chaining</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/contact-chaining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/contact-chaining/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Bitcoin Security and Performance with Strong Consistency via Collective Signing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/byzcoin-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/byzcoin-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Efficient Communication System With Strong Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/riffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/riffle/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open, privacy-preserving protocols for lawful surveillance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/open-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/open-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Authorities “Honest or Bust” with Decentralized Witness Cosigning</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cosi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cosi/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AnonRep: Towards Tracking-Resistant Anonymous Reputation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Privacy-Preserving Cryptographic Credentials from Federated Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book-codaspy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book-codaspy/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple, FBI, and Software Transparency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2016/03/10/apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2016/03/10/apple/</guid>
      <description>*This post [originally appeared](https://freedom-to-tinker.com/blog/bford/apple-fbi-and-software-transparency/) on the [Freedom to Tinker](https://freedom-to-tinker.com/) blog by the [Center for Information Technology Policy](https://citp.princeton.edu) at [Princeton University](http://www.princeton.edu/).*  The Apple versus FBI showdown has quickly become a crucial flashpoint of the “new Crypto War.” On February 16 the FBI invoked the All Writs Act of 1789, a catch-all authority for assistance of law enforcement, demanding that Apple create a custom version of its iOS to help the FBI decrypt an iPhone used by one of the San Bernardino shooters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collectively Witnessing Log Servers in CT</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2015-10-20-cosi-ct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2015-10-20-cosi-ct/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford   draft-ford-trans-witness-00  Abstract: This document proposes a backward-compatible extension to CT enabling log servers to obtain compact collective signatures from any number of well-known &#34;witness&#34; servers, which clients can check without gossip to verify that log server records have been widely witnessed. Collective signatures proactively protect clients from man-in-the- middle attackers who may have stolen the private keys of one or more log servers, even if the attacker controls the client&#39;s network access, the client is unwilling to gossip for privacy reasons, or the client does not wish to incur the network bandwidth and/or latency costs of gossip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Anonymity in an Internet Panopticon</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/panopticon-cacm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/panopticon-cacm/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identity Management through Privacy-Preserving Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-syta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-syta/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
August 11, 2015  Abstract:  Maintaining privacy on the Internet is increasingly difficult in this ever-connected world. In most cases, our online interactions are a highly personalized experience and require some form of identity verification, most commonly, logging into an account. Unfortunately, people frequently give away a lot of information while obtaining accounts, reuse usernames and passwords across different services, or link their accounts to take advantage of single sign-on to avoid retyping passwords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Eyes: Secure Remote Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta, Michael J. Fischer, David Wolinsky, Abraham Silberschatz, Gina Gallegos-García, and Bryan Ford   12th International Conference on Security and Cryptography (SECRYPT)
July 2015.  Abstract: We propose an efficient remote biometric authentication protocol that gives strong protection to the user’s biometric data in case of two common kinds of security breaches: (1) loss or theft of the user’s token (smart card, handheld device, etc.), giving the attacker full access to any secrets embedded within it; (2) total penetration of the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certificate Cothority: Towards Trustworthy Collective CAs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/certco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/certco/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Privacy-Preserving Cryptographic Credentials from Federated Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-maheswaran/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-maheswaran/</guid>
      <description>John Maheswaran  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
June 24, 2015  Abstract:  Third-party applications such as Quora or StackOverflow allow users to log in through a federated identity provider such as Facebook (Log in with Facebook), Google+ or Twitter. This process is called federated authentication. Examples of federated identity providers include social networks as well as other non-social network identity providers such as PayPal.  Federated identity providers have gained widespread popularity among users as a way to manage their online identity across the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/post/2014-10-22-open-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/post/2014-10-22-open-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching Bandits and Only Bandits: Privacy-Preserving Intersection Warrants for Lawful Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/bandits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/bandits/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Analysis of Accountable Anonymity in Dissent</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-analysis/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A TorPath to TorCoin: Proof-of-Bandwidth Altcoins for Compensating Relays</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/torcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/torcoin/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Onions to Shallots: Rewarding Tor Relays with TEARS</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/onions-to-shallots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/onions-to-shallots/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crypto-Book: An Architecture for Privacy Preserving Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conscript Your Friends into Larger Anonymity Sets with JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/conscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/conscript/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring High-Quality Randomness in Cryptographic Key Generation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/randomness-keygen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/randomness-keygen/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hang With Your Buddies to Resist Intersection Attacks</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/buddies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/buddies/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proactively Accountable Anonymous Messaging in Verdict</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/verdict/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/verdict/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissent in Numbers: Making Strong Anonymity Scale</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-in-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-in-numbers/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scavenging for Anonymity with BlogDrop</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/blogdrop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/blogdrop/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Theft-Proof Privacy-Preserving Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Anonymous Group Communication in the Anytrust Model</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/anytrust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/anytrust/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eyo: Device-Transparent Personal Storage</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/eyo-usenix-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/eyo-usenix-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jacob Strauss, Justin Mazzola Paluska, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Bryan Ford, Robert Morris, and Frans Kaashoek
 2011 USENIX Annual Technical Conference June 15-17, 2011, Portland, OR, USA Abstract: Users increasingly store data collections such as digital photographs on multiple personal devices, each of which typically offers a storage management interface oblivious to the contents of the user’s other devices. As a result, collections become disorganized and drift out of sync.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissent: Accountable Anonymous Group Messaging</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/dissent-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/dissent-abs/</guid>
      <description>Henry Corrigan-Gibbs and Bryan Ford
	Yale University  To appear in 17th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS 2010) October 4-8, 2010, Chicago, IL, USA Abstract:  Users often wish to participate in online groups anonymously, but misbehaving users may abuse this anonymity to disrupt the group&#39;s communication. Existing messaging protocols such as DC-nets leave groups vulnerable to denial-of-service and Sybil attacks, Mix-nets are difficult to protect against traffic analysis, and accountable voting protocols are unsuited to general anonymous messaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Cross-Layer Negotiation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/nego-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/nego-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
	Janardhan Iyengar
	Yale University 	Franklin &amp;amp; Marshall College  Published in Eighth ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets-VIII) October 22-23, 2009, New York City, NY, USA Abstract: Internet evolution often depends on either inserting new protocol layers or upgrading existing layers to new protocols, but both of these evolutionary paths are obstructed by the difficulty and inefficiency of determining which protocols a pair of hosts mutually support and prefer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIA: A Global Connectivity Architecture for Mobile Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Ph.D. thesis, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, September 2008. Abstract:  The Internet&#39;s architecture, designed in the days of large, stationary computers tended by technically savvy and accountable administrators, fails to meet the demands of the emerging ubiquitous computing era. Nontechnical users now routinely own multiple personal devices, many of them mobile, and need to share information securely among them using interactive, delay-sensitive applications.  Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) is a novel, incrementally deployable network architecture for modern personal devices, which reconsiders three architectural cornerstones: naming, routing, and transport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpaca: Extensible Authorization for Distributed Services</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/alpaca-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/alpaca-abs/</guid>
      <description>Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Robert Morris, and M. Frans Kaashoek
Massachusetts Institute of Technology Published in 14th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security, Oct 29-Nov 2, 2007, Alexandria, VA. Abstract:  Traditional Public Key Infrastructures (PKI) have not lived up to their promise because there are too many ways to define PKIs, too many cryptographic primitives to build them with, and too many administrative domains with incompatible roots of trust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured Streams: a New Transport Abstraction</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/sst-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/sst-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Massachusetts Institute of Technology Published in ACM SIGCOMM 2007, August 27-31, 2007, Kyoto, Japan. Abstract:  Internet applications currently have a choice between stream and datagram transport abstractions. Datagrams efficiently support small transactions and streams are suited for long-running conversations, but neither abstraction adequately supports applications like HTTP that exhibit a mixture of transaction sizes, or applications like FTP and SIP that use multiple transport instances. Structured Stream Transport (SST) enhances the traditional stream abstraction with a hierarchical hereditary structure, allowing applications to create lightweight child streams from any existing stream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unmanaged Internet Protocol: Taming the Edge Network Management Crisis</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-case-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-case-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Massachusetts Institute of Technology   Second Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks
November 20-21, 2003  Abstract: Though appropriate for core Internet infrastructure, the Internet Protocol is unsuited to routing within and between emerging ad-hoc edge networks due to its dependence on hierarchical, administratively assigned addresses. Existing ad-hoc routing protocols address the management problem but do not scale to Internet-wide networks. The promise of ubiquitous network computing cannot be fulfilled until we develop an Unmanaged Internet Protocol (UIP), a scalable routing protocol that manages itself automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>