<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biometrics on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Biometrics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Biometrics on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Biometrics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Identity Management through Privacy-Preserving Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-syta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-syta/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta  Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
August 11, 2015  Abstract:  Maintaining privacy on the Internet is increasingly difficult in this ever-connected world. In most cases, our online interactions are a highly personalized experience and require some form of identity verification, most commonly, logging into an account. Unfortunately, people frequently give away a lot of information while obtaining accounts, reuse usernames and passwords across different services, or link their accounts to take advantage of single sign-on to avoid retyping passwords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Eyes: Secure Remote Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta, Michael J. Fischer, David Wolinsky, Abraham Silberschatz, Gina Gallegos-García, and Bryan Ford   12th International Conference on Security and Cryptography (SECRYPT)
July 2015.  Abstract: We propose an efficient remote biometric authentication protocol that gives strong protection to the user’s biometric data in case of two common kinds of security breaches: (1) loss or theft of the user’s token (smart card, handheld device, etc.), giving the attacker full access to any secrets embedded within it; (2) total penetration of the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Theft-Proof Privacy-Preserving Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>