<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rights on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Rights/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rights on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Rights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Identity and Personhood in Digital Democracy: Evaluating Inclusion, Equality, Security, and Privacy in Pseudonym Parties and Other Proofs of Personhood</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/personhood/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford  November 2020 (first draft)  preprint
 Abstract: Digital identity seems at first like a prerequisite for digital democracy: how can we ensure &amp;ldquo;one person, one vote&amp;rdquo; online without identifying voters? But the full gamut of digital identity solutions &amp;ndash; e.g., online ID checking, biometrics, self-sovereign identity, and social/trust networks &amp;ndash; all present severe flaws in security, privacy, and transparency, leaving users vulnerable to exclusion, identity loss or theft, and coercion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Remote Voting Minefield: from North Carolina to Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/02/22/voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/02/22/voting/</guid>
      <description>The absentee ballot fraud in North Carolina shows how current vote-by-mail methods are fundamentally flawed and vulnerable to vote-buying and coercion. But banning remote voting of any kind would disenfranchise everyone not living in their country of citizenship; that is not a real option.
It is important to understand in this light the context of the Swiss e-voting project, one of whose two implementations was recently opened to public inspection by the Swiss Post for inspection and analysis by international experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Priorities: Should Identity Systems Divide or Unite People?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/02/08/identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/02/08/identity/</guid>
      <description>Note: this is a brief, rough, first-draft sketch of a longer paper paper I intend to flesh out further in the near future.
The problem of identity has become a hot topic, with the idea of self-sovereign identity in particular attracting significant excitement. The essence of the idea, in short, is to put users in charge of how their identities and personal data are used. Self-sovereign identity posits that users should decide how much and what aspects of their identities to disclose in any situation, and should know and have control over what that information is used for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Governs Us. Will it Govern Us Well?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2017/06/23/turing50/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2017/06/23/turing50/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is a transcript of my opening remarks on the panel &#34;Restoring Personal Privacy without Compromising National Security&#34; at the 50 Years of the ACM Turing Award Celebration.   We now live in a world in which the rules coded into the technology we use plays as important a role in governing our lives as the formal laws written in the public law books. Code is law already, for better or worse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Objectives of Lawful-Surveillance Protocols</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/lawful-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/lawful-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open, privacy-preserving protocols for lawful surveillance</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/open-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/open-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the World of Human Rights: Please Make Yourself Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/human-rights-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/human-rights-abs/</guid>
      <description>   Henry Corrigan-Gibbs and Bryan Ford Yale University   Cyber-security Research Ethics Dialog &amp; Strategy Workshop (CREDS 2013)
May 23, 2013  Abstract: We draw an ethical analogy between Internet freedom efforts and humanitarian aid work. This parallel motivates a number of ethical questions relating to anonymity and censorship-circumvention research. Paper: PDF  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
