<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Verifiable Shuffles on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Verifiable-Shuffles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Verifiable Shuffles on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Verifiable-Shuffles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Auditing the Swiss Post E-voting System: An Architectural Perspective</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/swisspost-evoting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/swisspost-evoting/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Swiss Federal Chancellery – Independent examination of Swiss Post system 2021 Scopes 1, 2 and 3 Final Report – April 4, 2022 Abstract: Switzerland is one of the few countries globally that has a national program for electronic voting (E-voting), which has been evolving in several stages for well over a decade. For the past several years, the program’s most recent stage has focused on introducing strong cryptographic verifiability into the system, together with security features such as trust splitting and a software implementation open to public inspection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MedCo: Enabling Secure and Privacy-Conscious Exploration of Distributed Clinical and Genomic Data</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/medco-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/medco-abs/</guid>
      <description>Jean Louis Raisaro, Juan Ram&amp;oacute;n Troncoso-Pastoriza, Micka&amp;euml;l Misbach, Jo&amp;atilde;o S&amp;aacute; Sousa, Sylvain Pradervand, Edoardo Missiaglia, Olivier Michielin, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux IEEE/ACM Transactions on Computational Biology and Bioinformatics,
July 13, 2018. Abstract: The increasing number of health-data breaches is creating a complicated environment for medical-data sharing and, consequently, for medical progress. Therefore, the development of new solutions that can reassure clinical sites by enabling privacy-preserving sharing of sensitive medical data in compliance with stringent regulations (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom: Horizontally Scaling Strong Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/atom-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/atom-abs/</guid>
      <description>Albert Kwon
MIT Henry Corrigan-Gibbs
Stanford Srinivas Devadas
MIT Bryan Ford
EPFL 26th ACM Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP)
October 30, 2017 Abstract: Atom is an anonymous messaging system that protects against traffic-analysis attacks. Unlike many prior systems, each Atom server touches only a small fraction of the total messages routed through the network. As a result, the system’s capacity scales near-linearly with the number of servers. At the same time, each Atom user benefits from &amp;ldquo;best possible&amp;rdquo; anonymity: a user is anonymous among all honest users of the system, even against an active adversary who monitors the entire network, a portion of the system’s servers, and any number of malicious users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UnLynx: A Decentralized System for Privacy-Conscious Data Sharing</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/unlynx-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/unlynx-abs/</guid>
      <description>David Froelicher, Patricia Egger, Jo&amp;atilde;o S&amp;aacute; Sousa, Jean Louis Raisaro, Zhicong Huang, Christian Mouchet, Bryan Ford, and Jean-Pierre Hubaux Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium (PETS)
July 19, 2017 Abstract: Current solutions for privacy-preserving data sharing among multiple parties either depend on a centralized authority that must be trusted and provides only weakest-link security (e.g., the entity that manages private/secret cryptographic keys), or leverage on decentralized but impractical approaches (e.g., secure multi-party computation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riffle: An Efficient Communication System With Strong Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/riffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/riffle/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Anonymity in an Internet Panopticon</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/panopticon-cacm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/panopticon-cacm/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Analysis of Accountable Anonymity in Dissent</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-analysis/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conscript Your Friends into Larger Anonymity Sets with JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/conscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/conscript/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proactively Accountable Anonymous Messaging in Verdict</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/verdict/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/verdict/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissent in Numbers: Making Strong Anonymity Scale</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-in-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/dissent-in-numbers/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Anonymous Group Communication in the Anytrust Model</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/anytrust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/anytrust/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissent: Accountable Anonymous Group Messaging</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/dissent-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/dissent-abs/</guid>
      <description>Henry Corrigan-Gibbs and Bryan Ford Yale University Winner of ACM CCS Test-of-Time Award 17th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS 2010) October 4-8, 2010, Chicago, IL, USA Abstract: Users often wish to participate in online groups anonymously, but misbehaving users may abuse this anonymity to disrupt the group&#39;s communication. Existing messaging protocols such as DC-nets leave groups vulnerable to denial-of-service and Sybil attacks, Mix-nets are difficult to protect against traffic analysis, and accountable voting protocols are unsuited to general anonymous messaging.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
