<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Identity on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Identity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Identity on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Identity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Technologizing Democracy or Democratizing Technology? A Layered-Architecture Perspective on Potentials and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</guid>
      <description> Bryan Ford Draft &amp;ndash; January 30, 2020
Final version to appear in forthcoming book published by the University of Chicago Press 
Book chapter: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Priorities: Should Identity Systems Divide or Unite People?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/02/08/identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/02/08/identity/</guid>
      <description>Note: this is a brief, rough, first-draft sketch of a longer paper paper I intend to flesh out further in the near future.
The problem of identity has become a hot topic, with the idea of self-sovereign identity in particular attracting significant excitement. The essence of the idea, in short, is to put users in charge of how their identities and personal data are used. Self-sovereign identity posits that users should decide how much and what aspects of their identities to disclose in any situation, and should know and have control over what that information is used for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof-of-Personhood: Redemocratizing Permissionless Cryptocurrencies</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</guid>
      <description>Maria Borge, Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Philipp Jovanovic, Linus Gasser, Nicolas Gailly, and Bryan Ford
EPFL   IEEE Security &amp; Privacy on the Blockchain (IEEE S&amp;B)
April 29, 2017 Abstract: Permissionless blockchain-based cryptocurrencies commonly use proof-of-work (PoW) or proof-of-stake (PoS) to ensure their security, e.g. to prevent double spending attacks. However, both approaches have disadvantages: PoW leads to massive amounts of wasted electricity and re-centralization, whereas major stakeholders in PoS might be able to create a monopoly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Authorities “Honest or Bust” with Decentralized Witness Cosigning</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cosi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cosi/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AnonRep: Towards Tracking-Resistant Anonymous Reputation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collectively Witnessing Log Servers in CT</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2015-10-20-cosi-ct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2015-10-20-cosi-ct/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford   draft-ford-trans-witness-00  Abstract: This document proposes a backward-compatible extension to CT enabling log servers to obtain compact collective signatures from any number of well-known &#34;witness&#34; servers, which clients can check without gossip to verify that log server records have been widely witnessed. Collective signatures proactively protect clients from man-in-the- middle attackers who may have stolen the private keys of one or more log servers, even if the attacker controls the client&#39;s network access, the client is unwilling to gossip for privacy reasons, or the client does not wish to incur the network bandwidth and/or latency costs of gossip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s verify real people, not real names.</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2015/10/07/names.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2015/10/07/names.html</guid>
      <description>On Monday the EFF, together with a &amp;ldquo;Nameless Coalition&amp;rdquo; of like-minded groups, escalated the backlash against Facebook&#39;s &amp;ldquo;real names&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;authentic identities&amp;rdquo; policy with an open letter urging Facebook to end this policy like Google Plus did last year. Facebook&#39;s response cites concerns about pseudonyms helping to hide &amp;ldquo;terrorist organizations&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;school bullies&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;criminal behavior.&amp;rdquo;
While I support anonymity and have spent years working to strengthen it, terrorist fearmongering aside, Facebook is right that anonymity is often abused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Eyes: Secure Remote Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta, Michael J. Fischer, David Wolinsky, Abraham Silberschatz, Gina Gallegos-García, and Bryan Ford   12th International Conference on Security and Cryptography (SECRYPT)
July 2015.  Abstract: We propose an efficient remote biometric authentication protocol that gives strong protection to the user’s biometric data in case of two common kinds of security breaches: (1) loss or theft of the user’s token (smart card, handheld device, etc.), giving the attacker full access to any secrets embedded within it; (2) total penetration of the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certificate Cothority: Towards Trustworthy Collective CAs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/certco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/certco/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing NymBoxes for Identity and Tracking Protection</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/nymboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/nymboxes/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Theft-Proof Privacy-Preserving Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dynamic Recursive Unified Internet Design (DRUID)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/druid-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/druid-abs/</guid>
      <description>Joe Touch, Ilia Baldine, Rudra Dutta, Gregory G. Finn, Bryan Ford, Scott Jordan, Dan Massey, Abraham Matta, Christos Papadopoulos, Peter Reiher, George Rouskas   Computer Networks December 24, 2010 Abstract: The Dynamic Recursive Unified Internet Design (DRUID) is a future Internet design that unifies overlay networks with conventional layered network architectures. DRUID is based on the fundamental concept of recursion, enabling a simple and direct network architecture that unifies the data, control, management, and security aspects of the current Internet, leading to a more trustworthy network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Cross-Layer Negotiation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/nego-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/nego-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
	Janardhan Iyengar
	Yale University 	Franklin &amp;amp; Marshall College  Published in Eighth ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets-VIII) October 22-23, 2009, New York City, NY, USA Abstract: Internet evolution often depends on either inserting new protocol layers or upgrading existing layers to new protocols, but both of these evolutionary paths are obstructed by the difficulty and inefficiency of determining which protocols a pair of hosts mutually support and prefer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIA: A Global Connectivity Architecture for Mobile Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Ph.D. thesis, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, September 2008. Abstract:  The Internet&#39;s architecture, designed in the days of large, stationary computers tended by technically savvy and accountable administrators, fails to meet the demands of the emerging ubiquitous computing era. Nontechnical users now routinely own multiple personal devices, many of them mobile, and need to share information securely among them using interactive, delay-sensitive applications.  Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) is a novel, incrementally deployable network architecture for modern personal devices, which reconsiders three architectural cornerstones: naming, routing, and transport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Offline Foundation for Online Accountable Pseudonyms</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Jacob Strauss 
Massachusetts Institute of Technology First Workshop on Social Network Systems
April 1, 2008 Abstract:  Online anonymity often appears to undermine accountability, offering little incentive for civil behavior, but accountability failures usually result not from anonymity itself but from the disposability of virtual identities. A user banned for misbehavior&amp;mdash;e.g., spamming from a free E-mail account or stuffing an online ballot box&amp;mdash;can simply open other accounts or connect from other IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpaca: Extensible Authorization for Distributed Services</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/alpaca-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/alpaca-abs/</guid>
      <description>Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Robert Morris, and M. Frans Kaashoek
Massachusetts Institute of Technology Published in 14th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security, Oct 29-Nov 2, 2007, Alexandria, VA. Abstract:  Traditional Public Key Infrastructures (PKI) have not lived up to their promise because there are too many ways to define PKIs, too many cryptographic primitives to build them with, and too many administrative domains with incompatible roots of trust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent Personal Names for Globally Connected Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, Robert Morris
 Massachusetts Institute of Technology 7th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation
November 6-8, 2006 Abstract:  The  Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) provides zero-configuration connectivity among mobile devices through personal names. Users assign personal names through an ad hoc device introduction process requiring no central allocation. Once assigned, names bind securely to the global identities of their target devices independent of network location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User-Relative Names for Globally Connected Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-iptps-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-iptps-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, and Robert Morris Massachusetts Institute of Technology   5th International Workshop on Peer-to-Peer Systems
February 27-28, 2006  Abstract The User Information Architecture, or UIA, is a peer-to-peer connectivity architecture that provides users a simple, intuitive, and secure way to share information and services between personal devices by assigning ad hoc names that act like &amp;ldquo;virtual cables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unmanaged Internet Protocol: Taming the Edge Network Management Crisis</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-case-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-case-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Massachusetts Institute of Technology   Second Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks
November 20-21, 2003  Abstract: Though appropriate for core Internet infrastructure, the Internet Protocol is unsuited to routing within and between emerging ad-hoc edge networks due to its dependence on hierarchical, administratively assigned addresses. Existing ad-hoc routing protocols address the management problem but do not scale to Internet-wide networks. The promise of ubiquitous network computing cannot be fulfilled until we develop an Unmanaged Internet Protocol (UIP), a scalable routing protocol that manages itself automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Internet Routing on Topology-Independent Node Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Massachusetts Institute of Technology   Technical Report MIT-LCS-TR-926
October 31, 2003  Abstract: Unmanaged Internet Protocol (UIP) is a fully self-organizing network-layer protocol that implements scalable identity-based routing. In contrast with address-based routing protocols, which depend for scalability on centralized hierarchical address management, UIP nodes use a flat namespace of cryptographic node identifiers. Node identities can be created locally on demand and remain stable across network changes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>