<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Identity on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Identity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Identity on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Identity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>E-Vote Your Conscience: Perceptions of Coercion and Vote Buying, and the Usability of Fake Credentials in Online Voting</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/trip-usability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/trip-usability/</guid>
      <description>Louis-Henri Merino, Alaleh Azhir, Haoqian Zhang, Simone Colombo, Bernhard Tellenbach, Vero Estrada-Galiñanes, Bryan Ford To appear in 45th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy May 20-23, 2024 Abstract: Online voting is attractive for convenience and accessibility, but is more susceptible to voter coercion and vote buying than in-person voting. One mitigation is to give voters fake voting credentials that they can yield to a coercer. Fake credentials appear identical to real ones, but cast votes that are silently omitted from the final tally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authenticated Private Information Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/apir/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/apir/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford 32nd USENIX Security Symposium August 10, 2023 Abstract: This paper introduces protocols for authenticated private information retrieval. These schemes enable a client to fetch a record from a remote database server such that (a) the server does not learn which record the client reads, and (b) the client either obtains the “authentic” record or detects server misbehavior and safely aborts. Both properties are crucial for many applications. Standard private-information-retrieval schemes either do not ensure this form of output authenticity, or they require multiple database replicas with an honest majority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who – Or What – Will Our Distributed Metaverse Serve?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2022-07-06-metaverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2022-07-06-metaverse/</guid>
      <description> Invited talk at INRIA prospective seminar on Distributed Systems and Middleware July 6, 2022 – Rungis, France Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3PBCS: A Privacy-Preserving, Personhood-Based Credential System</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2022-apostoli/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2022-apostoli/</guid>
      <description>Ksandros Apostoli M.S. thesis advised by Simone Colombo and Bryan Ford March 22, 2022 Abstract Recent anonymous credential schemes present major advances in the way digital identities are treated, empowering users with fine-grained control over their personal data. While limiting the amount of user-data that is accessible to third parties paves the way to stronger privacy guarantees, it also leads to new challenges in preserving accountability and Sybil-Resistance. In this work, we present 3PBCS, a novel credential system, which integrates existing anonymous credential schemes with the notion of Proof-of-Personhood to achieve privacy, accountability and Sybil-Protection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Personhood: Towards Technology that Securely Serves People</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/talk/2022-02-17-personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/talk/2022-02-17-personhood/</guid>
      <description> Invited talk at SI Summit 2022 February 17, 2022 – Virtual Slides: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIP: Trustless Coercion-Resistant In-Person Voter Registration</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/trip/</guid>
      <description>Louis-Henri Merino, Simone Colombo, Jeff Allen, Vero Estrada-Galiñanes, and Bryan Ford arXiv preprint Abstract: Most existing remote electronic voting systems are vulnerable to voter coercion and vote buying. While coercion-resistant voting systems address this challenge, current schemes assume that the voter has access to an untappable, incorruptible device during voter registration. We present TRIP, an in-person voter registration scheme enabling voters to create verifiable and indistinguishable real and fake credentials using an untrusted kiosk inside a privacy booth at a supervised location, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technologizing Democracy or Democratizing Technology? A Layered-Architecture Perspective on Potentials and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/dt2-chapter-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Appears in Digital Technology and Democratic Theory by Lucy Bernholz, Hélène Landemore, and Rob Reich (editors) published by the University of Chicago Press
Abstract While technology is often claimed to be “democratizing”, the technologizing of society has more often yielded undemocratic or even anti-democratic outcomes. Is technology fundamentally at odds with democracy, or is it merely a rich and infinitely-adaptable toolbox that we’re using the wrong way? We explore how technology has failed to support robust democracy – but could do better – in the context of four basic social processes: collective deliberation and choice, information distribution and filtering, economic commerce, and identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identity and Personhood in Digital Democracy: Evaluating Inclusion, Equality, Security, and Privacy in Pseudonym Parties and Other Proofs of Personhood</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/personhood/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford November 2020 (first draft) arXiv preprint
Abstract: Digital identity seems at first like a prerequisite for digital democracy: how can we ensure &amp;ldquo;one person, one vote&amp;rdquo; online without identifying voters? But the full gamut of digital identity solutions &amp;ndash; e.g., online ID checking, biometrics, self-sovereign identity, and social/trust networks &amp;ndash; all present severe flaws in security, privacy, and transparency, leaving users vulnerable to exclusion, identity loss or theft, and coercion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design choices for Central Bank Digital Currency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cbdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cbdc/</guid>
      <description>Sarah Allen, Srdjan Capkun, Ittay Eyal, Giulia Fanti, Bryan Ford, James Grimmelmann, Ari Juels, Kari Kostiainen, Sarah Meiklejohn, Andrew Miller, Eswar Prasad, Karl Wüst, and Fan Zhang Global Economy &amp; Development Working Paper 140,
Brookings Institution,
July 23, 2020. Abstract: Central banks around the world are exploring and in some cases even piloting central bank digital currencies (CBDCs). CBDCs promise to realize a broad range of new capabilities, including direct government disbursements to citizens, frictionless consumer payment and money-transfer systems, and a range of new financial instruments and monetary policy levers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Priorities: Should Identity Systems Divide or Unite People?</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2019/02/08/identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2019/02/08/identity/</guid>
      <description>Note: this blog post was a brief sketch of ideas elaborated in a longer paper written later.
The problem of identity has become a hot topic, with the idea of self-sovereign identity in particular attracting significant excitement. The essence of the idea, in short, is to put users in charge of how their identities and personal data are used. Self-sovereign identity posits that users should decide how much and what aspects of their identities to disclose in any situation, and should know and have control over what that information is used for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Liquid Perspective on Democratic Choice</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/liquid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/liquid/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford November 2018 (first draft) arXiv preprint
Abstract: The idea of liquid democracy responds to a widely-felt desire to make democracy more &#34;fluid&#34; and continuously participatory. Its central premise is to enable users to employ networked technologies to control and delegate voting power, to approximate the ideal of direct democracy in a scalable fashion that accounts for time and attention limits. There are many potential definitions, meanings, and ways to implement liquid democracy, however, and many distinct purposes to which it might be deployed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratic Value and Money for Decentralized Digital Society</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/soc/money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/soc/money/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford June 2018 (first draft) arXiv preprint
Abstract: Classical monetary systems regularly subject the most vulnerable majority of the world&#39;s population to debilitating financial shocks, and have manifestly allowed uncontrolled global inequality over the long term. Given these basic failures, how can we avoid asking whether mainstream macroeconomic principles are actually compatible with democratic principles such as equality or the protection of human rights and dignity? This idea paper takes a constructive look at this question, by exploring how alternate monetary principles might result in a form of money more compatible with democratic principles -- dare we call it &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof-of-Personhood: Redemocratizing Permissionless Cryptocurrencies</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/pop-abs/</guid>
      <description>Maria Borge, Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Philipp Jovanovic, Linus Gasser, Nicolas Gailly, and Bryan Ford
EPFL IEEE Security &amp; Privacy on the Blockchain (IEEE S&amp;B)
April 29, 2017 Abstract: Permissionless blockchain-based cryptocurrencies commonly use proof-of-work (PoW) or proof-of-stake (PoS) to ensure their security, e.g. to prevent double spending attacks. However, both approaches have disadvantages: PoW leads to massive amounts of wasted electricity and re-centralization, whereas major stakeholders in PoS might be able to create a monopoly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Authorities “Honest or Bust” with Decentralized Witness Cosigning</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cosi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/cosi/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AnonRep: Towards Tracking-Resistant Anonymous Reputation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/dec/anonrep-abs/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Privacy-Preserving Cryptographic Credentials from Federated Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book-codaspy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book-codaspy/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collectively Witnessing Log Servers in CT</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2015-10-20-cosi-ct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2015-10-20-cosi-ct/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford draft-ford-trans-witness-00 Abstract: This document proposes a backward-compatible extension to CT enabling log servers to obtain compact collective signatures from any number of well-known &#34;witness&#34; servers, which clients can check without gossip to verify that log server records have been widely witnessed. Collective signatures proactively protect clients from man-in-the- middle attackers who may have stolen the private keys of one or more log servers, even if the attacker controls the client&#39;s network access, the client is unwilling to gossip for privacy reasons, or the client does not wish to incur the network bandwidth and/or latency costs of gossip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s verify real people, not real names.</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2015/10/07/names.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2015/10/07/names.html</guid>
      <description>On Monday the EFF, together with a &amp;ldquo;Nameless Coalition&amp;rdquo; of like-minded groups, escalated the backlash against Facebook&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;real names&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;authentic identities&amp;rdquo; policy with an open letter urging Facebook to end this policy like Google Plus did last year. Facebook&amp;rsquo;s response cites concerns about pseudonyms helping to hide &amp;ldquo;terrorist organizations&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;school bullies&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;criminal behavior.&amp;rdquo;
While I support anonymity and have spent years working to strengthen it, terrorist fearmongering aside, Facebook is right that anonymity is often abused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identity Management through Privacy-Preserving Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-syta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-syta/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
August 11, 2015 Abstract: Maintaining privacy on the Internet is increasingly difficult in this ever-connected world. In most cases, our online interactions are a highly personalized experience and require some form of identity verification, most commonly, logging into an account. Unfortunately, people frequently give away a lot of information while obtaining accounts, reuse usernames and passwords across different services, or link their accounts to take advantage of single sign-on to avoid retyping passwords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Eyes: Secure Remote Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/private-eyes-abs/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta, Michael J. Fischer, David Wolinsky, Abraham Silberschatz, Gina Gallegos-García, and Bryan Ford 12th International Conference on Security and Cryptography (SECRYPT)
July 2015. Abstract: We propose an efficient remote biometric authentication protocol that gives strong protection to the user’s biometric data in case of two common kinds of security breaches: (1) loss or theft of the user’s token (smart card, handheld device, etc.), giving the attacker full access to any secrets embedded within it; (2) total penetration of the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certificate Cothority: Towards Trustworthy Collective CAs</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/certco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/certco/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Privacy-Preserving Cryptographic Credentials from Federated Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-maheswaran/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-maheswaran/</guid>
      <description>John Maheswaran Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
June 24, 2015 Abstract: Third-party applications such as Quora or StackOverflow allow users to log in through a federated identity provider such as Facebook (Log in with Facebook), Google+ or Twitter. This process is called federated authentication. Examples of federated identity providers include social networks as well as other non-social network identity providers such as PayPal. Federated identity providers have gained widespread popularity among users as a way to manage their online identity across the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing NymBoxes for Identity and Tracking Protection</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/nymboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/nymboxes/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crypto-Book: An Architecture for Privacy Preserving Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/crypto-book/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Theft-Proof Privacy-Preserving Biometric Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/sec/biometric-auth/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dynamic Recursive Unified Internet Design (DRUID)</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/druid-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/druid-abs/</guid>
      <description>Joe Touch, Ilia Baldine, Rudra Dutta, Gregory G. Finn, Bryan Ford, Scott Jordan, Dan Massey, Abraham Matta, Christos Papadopoulos, Peter Reiher, George Rouskas Computer Networks December 24, 2010 Abstract: The Dynamic Recursive Unified Internet Design (DRUID) is a future Internet design that unifies overlay networks with conventional layered network architectures. DRUID is based on the fundamental concept of recursion, enabling a simple and direct network architecture that unifies the data, control, management, and security aspects of the current Internet, leading to a more trustworthy network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Cross-Layer Negotiation</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/nego-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/nego-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Janardhan Iyengar
Yale University Franklin &amp;amp; Marshall College Published in Eighth ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets-VIII) October 22-23, 2009, New York City, NY, USA Abstract: Internet evolution often depends on either inserting new protocol layers or upgrading existing layers to new protocols, but both of these evolutionary paths are obstructed by the difficulty and inefficiency of determining which protocols a pair of hosts mutually support and prefer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIA: A Global Connectivity Architecture for Mobile Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/phd-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford
Ph.D. thesis, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, September 2008. Abstract: The Internet&#39;s architecture, designed in the days of large, stationary computers tended by technically savvy and accountable administrators, fails to meet the demands of the emerging ubiquitous computing era. Nontechnical users now routinely own multiple personal devices, many of them mobile, and need to share information securely among them using interactive, delay-sensitive applications. Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) is a novel, incrementally deployable network architecture for modern personal devices, which reconsiders three architectural cornerstones: naming, routing, and transport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Offline Foundation for Online Accountable Pseudonyms</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/sybil-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford and Jacob Strauss Massachusetts Institute of Technology First Workshop on Social Network Systems
April 1, 2008 Abstract: Online anonymity often appears to undermine accountability, offering little incentive for civil behavior, but accountability failures usually result not from anonymity itself but from the disposability of virtual identities. A user banned for misbehavior&amp;mdash;e.g., spamming from a free E-mail account or stuffing an online ballot box&amp;mdash;can simply open other accounts or connect from other IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpaca: Extensible Authorization for Distributed Services</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/alpaca-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/alpaca-abs/</guid>
      <description>Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Robert Morris, and M. Frans Kaashoek
Massachusetts Institute of Technology Published in 14th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security, Oct 29-Nov 2, 2007, Alexandria, VA. Abstract: Traditional Public Key Infrastructures (PKI) have not lived up to their promise because there are too many ways to define PKIs, too many cryptographic primitives to build them with, and too many administrative domains with incompatible roots of trust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent Personal Names for Globally Connected Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-osdi-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, Robert Morris
Massachusetts Institute of Technology 7th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation
November 6-8, 2006 Abstract: The Unmanaged Internet Architecture (UIA) provides zero-configuration connectivity among mobile devices through personal names. Users assign personal names through an ad hoc device introduction process requiring no central allocation. Once assigned, names bind securely to the global identities of their target devices independent of network location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sybil Parties: An Offline Foundation for Online Accountability</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/log/2006/0924-SybilParties.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/log/2006/0924-SybilParties.html</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford - September 24, 2006 Preliminary draft: see here for the final published paper The Human Recognition Problem Today&#39;s online ecosphere continually suffers from its inability to tell who is a genuine, unique human and who isn&#39;t. Because open-access messaging systems cannot isolate or authenticate the human source of messages for the purpose of suppressing abuses, spam has already relegated USENET to historical obscurity [Templeton01], threatens the usability of E-mail [Wouters05], and is even advancing on Skype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User-Relative Names for Globally Connected Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-iptps-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/net/uia-iptps-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford, Jacob Strauss, Chris Lesniewski-Laas, Sean Rhea, Frans Kaashoek, and Robert Morris Massachusetts Institute of Technology 5th International Workshop on Peer-to-Peer Systems
February 27-28, 2006 Abstract The User Information Architecture, or UIA, is a peer-to-peer connectivity architecture that provides users a simple, intuitive, and secure way to share information and services between personal devices by assigning ad hoc names that act like &amp;ldquo;virtual cables.&amp;rdquo; Users assign names by &amp;ldquo;introducing&amp;rdquo; devices to each other on a common network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unmanaged Internet Protocol: Taming the Edge Network Management Crisis</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-case-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-case-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Massachusetts Institute of Technology Second Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks
November 20-21, 2003 Abstract: Though appropriate for core Internet infrastructure, the Internet Protocol is unsuited to routing within and between emerging ad-hoc edge networks due to its dependence on hierarchical, administratively assigned addresses. Existing ad-hoc routing protocols address the management problem but do not scale to Internet-wide networks. The promise of ubiquitous network computing cannot be fulfilled until we develop an Unmanaged Internet Protocol (UIP), a scalable routing protocol that manages itself automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Internet Routing on Topology-Independent Node Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-abs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/pub/os/uip-abs/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Ford Massachusetts Institute of Technology Technical Report MIT-LCS-TR-926
October 31, 2003 Abstract: Unmanaged Internet Protocol (UIP) is a fully self-organizing network-layer protocol that implements scalable identity-based routing. In contrast with address-based routing protocols, which depend for scalability on centralized hierarchical address management, UIP nodes use a flat namespace of cryptographic node identifiers. Node identities can be created locally on demand and remain stable across network changes. Unlike location-independent name services, the UIP routing protocol can stitch together many conventional address-based networks with disjoint or discontinuous address domains, providing connectivity between any pair of participating nodes even when no underlying network provides direct connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
