<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/topics/Research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bford.info/topics/Research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>International Scientific Conferences Must Leave the U.S.</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2018/06/27/muslim-ban/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2018/06/27/muslim-ban/</guid>
      <description>So the U.S. Supreme Court has upheld Trump&amp;rsquo;s so-called “travel ban” – more honestly labeled a Muslim ban. More precisely, it is a ban on people from Muslim-majority countries not hosting Trump business properties (see map and fact check).
Where to Hold Conferences? This development naturally and rightfully raises again to prominence the question of where responsible scientists should hold their international conferences. We may soon see renewed calls to boycott US-based conferences, in solidarity with the many scientists around the world who can no longer attend conferences held in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faculty size and growth in the top 20 Computer Science departments</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/2014/10/22/cs-growth.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/2014/10/22/cs-growth.html</guid>
      <description>Yesterday the Yale Daily News ran an article on our CS department&amp;rsquo;s faculty shortage, which generated some discussion among CS colleagues. Yale&amp;rsquo;s CS faculty shortage is not really news: for example, another YDN article over a year ago made basically the same point, and that probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t the first.
Setting aside Yale in particular, however, it is interesting to notice some broader trends in CS department growth. So here are a couple charts I recently put together.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>