<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theses on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://bford.info/thesis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theses on Bryan Ford&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bford.info/thesis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Strongly-Consistent Systems Resilient to Failures, Partitions, and Slowdowns</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2023-basescu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2023-basescu/</guid>
      <description>Cristina Băsescu Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
May 26, 2023 Abstract: Distributed systems designers typically strive to improve performance and preserve availability despite failures or attacks; but, when strong consistency is also needed, they encounter fundamental limitations. The bottleneck is in replica coordination, which is impacted by partitions and slowdowns that can occur anywhere. We believe the present ecosystem fails to recognize that not all failures and partitions are supposed to be equal — at least from a user-centric performance and availability standpoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward Internet Performance Transparency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2022-fragkouli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2022-fragkouli/</guid>
      <description>Georgia Fragkouli Ph.D. thesis co-advised by Katerina Argyraki and Bryan Ford
August 29, 2022 Abstract: From medical support to education and remote work, our everyday lives increasingly depend on Internet performance. When users experience poor performance, however, the decentralization of the Internet allows limited visibility into which network is responsible. As a result, users are promised Service Level Agreements (SLAs) they cannot verify, regulators make rules they cannot enforce, and networks with competitive performance cannot reliably showcase it to attract new customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3PBCS: A Privacy-Preserving, Personhood-Based Credential System</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2022-apostoli/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2022-apostoli/</guid>
      <description>Ksandros Apostoli M.S. thesis advised by Simone Colombo and Bryan Ford March 22, 2022 Abstract Recent anonymous credential schemes present major advances in the way digital identities are treated, empowering users with fine-grained control over their personal data. While limiting the amount of user-data that is accessible to third parties paves the way to stronger privacy guarantees, it also leads to new challenges in preserving accountability and Sybil-Resistance. In this work, we present 3PBCS, a novel credential system, which integrates existing anonymous credential schemes with the notion of Proof-of-Personhood to achieve privacy, accountability and Sybil-Protection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrity and Metadata Protection in Data Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2021-nikitin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2021-nikitin/</guid>
      <description>Kirill Nikitin Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
November 26, 2021 Abstract: Secure retrieval of data requires integrity, confidentially, transparency, and metadata-privacy of the process. Existing protection mechanisms, however, provide only partially these properties: encryption schemes still expose cleartext metadata, protocols for private information retrieval neglect data integrity, and data-distribution architectures forego transparency. In this dissertation, by designing new cryptographic primitives and security architectures that provide a more comprehensive protection, we improve on the current security and privacy practices in data retrieval.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-Preserving Federated Analytics using Multiparty Homomorphic Encryption</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2021-froelicher/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2021-froelicher/</guid>
      <description>David Jules Froelicher Ph.D. thesis advised by Jean-Pierre Hubaux and Bryan Ford
October 1, 2021 Abstract: Analyzing and processing data that are siloed and dispersed among multiple distrustful stakeholders is difficult and can even become impossible when the data are sensitive or confidential. Current data-protection and privacy regulations (e.g., GDPR) highly restrict the sharing and outsourcing of personal information among stakeholders that are in different jurisdictions. Sharing data is, however, required in many domains such as finance and medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing and Protecting Communication Metadata</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2021-barman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2021-barman/</guid>
      <description>Ludovic Barman Ph.D. thesis advised by Jean-Pierre Hubaux and Bryan Ford
September 17, 2021 Abstract: Most communication systems (e.g., e-mails, instant messengers, VPNs) use encryption to prevent third parties from learning sensitive information. However, encrypted communications protect the contents but often leak metadata: the amount of data sent and the time it was sent, the way the data should be decrypted, the identity of the sender and the recipient. These metadata are a pervasive threat to privacy: They enable a variety of attacks that range from recovering plaintext contents from encrypted communications to inferring communicating parties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure, Confidential Blockchains Providing High Throughput and Low Latency</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2019-kokoris-kogias/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2019-kokoris-kogias/</guid>
      <description>Eleftherios Kokoris Kogias Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
September 27, 2019 Abstract: One of the core promises of blockchain technology is that of enabling trustworthy data dissemination in a trustless environment. What current blockchain systems deliver, however, is slow dissemination of public data, rendering blockchain technology unusable in settings where latency, transaction capacity or data confidentiality is important. In this thesis, we focus on providing solutions on two of the most pressing problems blockchain technology currently faces: scalability and data confidentiality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Flexible Architecture for Structural Reliability Auditing to the Clouds</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-zhai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-zhai/</guid>
      <description>Ennan Zhai Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
August 11, 2015 Abstract: Today’s cloud computing systems pervasively rely on redundancy techniques to enhance reliability and availability. In complex multi-layered hardware/software stacks, however, seemingly independent components used redundantly might share deep, hidden dependencies. These common dependencies may potentially result in unexpected correlated failures, thus undermining redundancy efforts. Heading off correlated failures is extremely challenging in cloud-scale systems for the following three reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identity Management through Privacy-Preserving Authentication</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-syta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-syta/</guid>
      <description>Ewa Syta Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
August 11, 2015 Abstract: Maintaining privacy on the Internet is increasingly difficult in this ever-connected world. In most cases, our online interactions are a highly personalized experience and require some form of identity verification, most commonly, logging into an account. Unfortunately, people frequently give away a lot of information while obtaining accounts, reuse usernames and passwords across different services, or link their accounts to take advantage of single sign-on to avoid retyping passwords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warding off Timing Channels in Deterland</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-wu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-wu/</guid>
      <description> Weiyi Wu Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
August 10, 2015 Abstract: XXX Ph.D. Thesis: PDF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Privacy-Preserving Cryptographic Credentials from Federated Online Identities</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-maheswaran/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2015-maheswaran/</guid>
      <description>John Maheswaran Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
June 24, 2015 Abstract: Third-party applications such as Quora or StackOverflow allow users to log in through a federated identity provider such as Facebook (Log in with Facebook), Google+ or Twitter. This process is called federated authentication. Examples of federated identity providers include social networks as well as other non-social network identity providers such as PayPal. Federated identity providers have gained widespread popularity among users as a way to manage their online identity across the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wire-Compatible TCP Implementation for Low-Latency Applications</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2014-nowlan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2014-nowlan/</guid>
      <description>Michael F. Nowlan Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
March 7, 2014 Abstract: Despite alternative transport protocols more suitable to latency-sensitive applications, TCP remains the de facto standard for Internet traffic, including many low-latency, interactive applications. As such, applications often tweak the TCP protocol to better suit their needs but run the risk that any change to TCP’s wire format can cause reachability issues or complete failure. This work presents a modified TCP implementation to reduce end-to-end latency without modifying TCP’s wire format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deterministic OpenMP</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2012-aviram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2012-aviram/</guid>
      <description>Amittai F. Aviram Ph.D. thesis advised by Bryan Ford
September 20, 2012 Abstract: Researchers widely agree that determinism in parallel programs is desirable. Although experimental parallel programming languages have long featured deterministic semantics, in mainstream parallel environments, developers still build on non-deterministic constructs such as mutexes, leading to time- or schedule-dependent heisenbugs. To make deterministic programming more accessible, we introduce DOMP, a deterministic extension to OpenMP, preserving the familiarity of traditional languages such as C and Fortran, and maintaining source-compatibility with much of the existing OpenMP standard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIA: A Global Connectivity Architecture for Mobile Personal Devices</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2008-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2008-phd/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packrat Parsing: a Practical Linear-Time Algorithm with Backtracking</title>
      <link>https://bford.info/thesis/2002-masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bford.info/thesis/2002-masters/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
